[
	{
		"answerText": "Breaking Bad[10]  Using his knowledge of chemistry, Walter is able to produce a 99.1% pure form of methamphetamine that is this color because of his usage of methylamine instead of pseudoephedrine.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: A spin-off of this AMC TV series, Better Call Saul, is set to be produced. For 10 points each: [10] Name this TV show that documents the escapades of terminal cancer patient Walter White as he struggles to provide for his family through the dealing of methamphetamine.",
		"answers": [
			"Breaking",
			"Bad",
			"10",
			"Using",
			"his",
			"knowledge",
			"chemistry",
			"Walter",
			"able",
			"to",
			"produce",
			"99",
			"1%",
			"pure",
			"form",
			"methamphetamine",
			"that",
			"this",
			"color",
			"because",
			"usage",
			"methylamine",
			"instead",
			"pseudoephedrine"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Wicked[10] This lead singer in the Broadway production of Wicked performed as the green-faced witch Elphaba in \"Defying Gravity.\" John Travolta infamously mispronounced her name at the 2014 Academy Awards.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this musical, Prince Fiyero advises his fellow students that they should stop studying and live the \"unexamined life\". For 10 points each: [10] Name this 2003 musical with the number \"Dancing Through Life\", in which Fiyero wins the admiration of many female students, including a girl whom Boq asks to a dance. She convinces Boq to ask Nessarose instead.",
		"answers": [
			"Wicked",
			"10",
			"This",
			"lead",
			"singer",
			"in",
			"Broadway",
			"production",
			"performed",
			"as",
			"green-faced",
			"witch",
			"Elphaba",
			"Defying",
			"Gravity",
			"John",
			"Travolta",
			"infamously",
			"mispronounced",
			"her",
			"name",
			"at",
			"2014",
			"Academy",
			"Awards"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yankee Stadium[10] This stadium located in the Bronx, New York was dubbed \"The House that Ruth Built\" due to Babe Ruth's many impressive games played in it. It takes its name from its home team.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 11 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these cathedrals of America's pastime: baseball stadiums. [10] This stadium located in the Bronx, New York was dubbed \"The House that Ruth Built\" due to Babe Ruth's many impressive games played in it. It takes its name from its home team.",
		"answers": [
			"Yankee",
			"Stadium",
			"10",
			"This",
			"stadium",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Bronx",
			"New",
			"York",
			"was",
			"dubbed",
			"The",
			"House",
			"that",
			"Ruth",
			"Built",
			"due",
			"to",
			"Babe",
			"Ruth's",
			"many",
			"impressive",
			"games",
			"played",
			"It",
			"takes",
			"its",
			"name",
			"from",
			"home",
			"team"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Rap God\"[10] Rap God was a song by this rapper, who occasionally performs under his alter-ego, Slim Shady. Singles from his 2010 album Recovery include \"Lose Yourself\" and \"Love the Way You Lie,\" which features Rihanna.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 4 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The artist of this song was going to go easy on us not to hurt our feelings, but changes his mind after he realizes that he's only going to get this one chance. For 10 points each: [10] Name this song in which the artist spews out a long string of unintelligible jibber-jabber before declaring that he's beginning to feel like the title figure.",
		"answers": [
			"Rap",
			"God",
			"10",
			"was",
			"song",
			"by",
			"this",
			"rapper",
			"who",
			"occasionally",
			"performs",
			"under",
			"his",
			"alter-ego",
			"Slim",
			"Shady",
			"Singles",
			"from",
			"2010",
			"album",
			"Recovery",
			"include",
			"Lose",
			"Yourself",
			"and",
			"Love",
			"Way",
			"You",
			"Lie",
			"which",
			"features",
			"Rihanna"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "zombies [accept equivalents like the undead][10] This video game follows Joel and Ellie, who fight Cordyceps-infected zombies as they traverse a post-apocalyptic landscape to find the Fireflies.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 1 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: John Marston fights these beings in a Red Dead Redemption downloadable pack. For 10 points each: [10] Name these beings who drop rotten flesh in Minecraft and name a special mode in the Call of Duty series. They are the principal enemies in Left 4 Dead, Resident Evil, and The Walking Dead. ",
		"answers": [
			"zombies",
			"equivalents",
			"undead",
			"10",
			"This",
			"video",
			"game",
			"follows",
			"Joel",
			"and",
			"Ellie",
			"who",
			"fight",
			"Cordyceps-infected",
			"as",
			"they",
			"traverse",
			"post-apocalyptic",
			"landscape",
			"to",
			"find",
			"Fireflies"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigur Rós (\"see-uhr rose\")[10] Sigur Rós collaborated with this English band on Merce Cunningham's Split Sides. Headed by Thom Yorke, they released the song \"Creep\" and the albums Kid A, OK Computer, and In Rainbows.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 6 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This band exhibited a more aggressive metal sound in their recent album Kveikur. For 10 points each: [10] Name this post-rock band led by Jonsi, who plays bowed guitar and sings ethereal vocals in Vonlenska. Their albums include Agaetis byrjun (\"OW-guy-tis bee-ARR-yun\"), Takk, and Valtari. ",
		"answers": [
			"Sigur",
			"Rós",
			"see-uhr",
			"rose",
			"10",
			"collaborated",
			"with",
			"this",
			"English",
			"band",
			"Merce",
			"Cunningham's",
			"Split",
			"Sides",
			"Headed",
			"by",
			"Thom",
			"Yorke",
			"they",
			"released",
			"song",
			"Creep",
			"and",
			"albums",
			"Kid",
			"A",
			"OK",
			"Computer",
			"In",
			"Rainbows"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Little Prince[10] This author of The Little Prince and Southern Mail expanded on his experience as a stranded aviator in the Sahara Desert in his memoir Wind, Sand, and Stars.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 21 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Its narrator begins by recalling his childhood sketch of a boa constrictor devouring an elephant. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this novel in which a wandering boy who leaves the asteroid B-612 because he does not know how to love his rose. He meets the narrator, now a full-fledged pilot whose plane has broken down in the Sahara.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Little",
			"Prince",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"and",
			"Southern",
			"Mail",
			"expanded",
			"his",
			"experience",
			"as",
			"stranded",
			"aviator",
			"in",
			"Sahara",
			"Desert",
			"memoir",
			"Wind",
			"Sand",
			"Stars"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lorde (accept Ella Yelich-O'Connor)[10] That single by Lorde is this song that advocates against lavish lifestyles in its chorus: \"that kind of luxe just ain't for us / we crave a different kind of buzz.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 3 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The chorus of one song by this artist begins \"Baby be the class clown/ I'll be the beauty queen in tears.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this sixteen-year-old artist from New Zealand, whose singles include \"Tennis Court\" and one that begins \"I've never seen a diamond in the flesh.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Lorde",
			"Ella",
			"Yelich-O'Connor",
			"10",
			"That",
			"single",
			"by",
			"this",
			"song",
			"that",
			"advocates",
			"against",
			"lavish",
			"lifestyles",
			"in",
			"its",
			"chorus:",
			"luxe",
			"just",
			"ain't",
			"for",
			"us",
			"/",
			"we",
			"crave",
			"different",
			"buzz"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Orleans Saints [accept either][10] This tight end for the Saints played basketball in college. In 2011, he broke the receiving yards record for a tight end, only to have his record broken later that day by Rob Gronkowski.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Sean Payton is the coach for this NFC South team led by quarterback Drew Brees. For 10 points each: [10] Name this team that plays in the Mercedes-Benz Superdome and is known for their fans' expression, \"Who Dat?\"",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Orleans",
			"Saints",
			"10",
			"This",
			"tight",
			"end",
			"for",
			"played",
			"basketball",
			"in",
			"college",
			"In",
			"2011",
			"he",
			"broke",
			"receiving",
			"yards",
			"record",
			"only",
			"to",
			"have",
			"his",
			"broken",
			"later",
			"that",
			"day",
			"by",
			"Rob",
			"Gronkowski"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hushpuppy[10] Hushpuppy is the main character of this Benh Zeitlin film set on a Louisiana island devastated by a hurricane. Zeitlin and Wallis received Academy Award nominations for their work in this film.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 10 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This character listens to her father's last heartbeat after negotiating a peace with the Aurochs. For 10 points each: [10] Name this protagonist of a 2012 indie film played by Quvenzhane Wallis who lives in \"The Bathtub\" with her father Wink.",
		"answers": [
			"Hushpuppy",
			"10",
			"main",
			"character",
			"this",
			"Benh",
			"Zeitlin",
			"film",
			"set",
			"Louisiana",
			"island",
			"devastated",
			"by",
			"hurricane",
			"and",
			"Wallis",
			"received",
			"Academy",
			"Award",
			"nominations",
			"for",
			"their",
			"work",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Duke Nukem Forever[10] After Episode 2 of the second installment in this series came out, the lack of any information about the next installment featuring Gordon Freeman helped lead to a joke that Valve can't count to three.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 16 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these video games we've been waiting a long time for: [10] This title became for a long time the most infamous example of vaporware, with its previous \"3D\" installation coming out in 1996. It was finally released in 2011, allowing its muscle-toting, bubblegum chewing action figure to see the light of day once again.",
		"answers": [
			"Duke",
			"Nukem",
			"Forever",
			"10",
			"After",
			"Episode",
			"2",
			"second",
			"installment",
			"in",
			"this",
			"series",
			"came",
			"out",
			"lack",
			"information",
			"about",
			"next",
			"featuring",
			"Gordon",
			"Freeman",
			"helped",
			"lead",
			"to",
			"joke",
			"that",
			"Valve",
			"can't",
			"count",
			"three"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "House of Cards[10] House of Cards airs exclusively on this online streaming site, that controversially split its rental and streaming services.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 7 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This show stars Kevin Spacey as House Majority Whip Frank Underwood. For 10 points each: [10] Name this online series focusing on the efforts of Underwood to undermine the government after getting denied for Secretary of State.",
		"answers": [
			"House",
			"Cards",
			"10",
			"airs",
			"exclusively",
			"this",
			"online",
			"streaming",
			"site",
			"that",
			"controversially",
			"split",
			"its",
			"rental",
			"and",
			"services"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "James Harden[10] Harden was traded to the Houston Rockets from this team, which reached the 2012 NBA Finals behind Kevin Durant and Russell Westbrook.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 18 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This NBA player's beard has inspired multiple Facebook and Twitter accounts, for 10 points each: [10] Name this shooting guard who was drafted out of Arizona State in 2009 by his former team, but now plays alongside Jeremy Lin in Houston.",
		"answers": [
			"James",
			"Harden",
			"10",
			"was",
			"traded",
			"to",
			"Houston",
			"Rockets",
			"from",
			"this",
			"team",
			"which",
			"reached",
			"2012",
			"NBA",
			"Finals",
			"behind",
			"Kevin",
			"Durant",
			"and",
			"Russell",
			"Westbrook"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Flash[10] This third incarnation of the Flash took over after Barry Allen was killed during the Crisis on Infinite Earths. He was the nephew of Barry's wife Iris.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 16 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Incarnations of this superhero have included Jay Garrick and Barry Allen. For 10 points each: [10] Name this \"Scarlet Speedster\" from the DC Comics universe who posses super-speed and has a lightning bolt insignia.",
		"answers": [
			"Flash",
			"10",
			"This",
			"third",
			"incarnation",
			"took",
			"over",
			"after",
			"Barry",
			"Allen",
			"was",
			"killed",
			"during",
			"Crisis",
			"Infinite",
			"Earths",
			"He",
			"nephew",
			"Barry's",
			"wife",
			"Iris"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Death Cab For Cutie[10] In The Motorcycle Diaries, this character swims across the Amazon River to be with some lepers on his birthday. His visage is commonly seen on T-shirts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 4 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about people who find themselves separated by bodies of water.  [10] This band's \"Transatlanticism\", about a relationship separated by the Atlantic, has a chorus of \"I need you so much closer.\" Other songs by them include \"I Will Possess Your Heart\" and \"I Will Follow You Into the Dark.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Death",
			"Cab",
			"For",
			"Cutie",
			"10",
			"In",
			"The",
			"Motorcycle",
			"Diaries",
			"this",
			"character",
			"swims",
			"across",
			"Amazon",
			"River",
			"to",
			"be",
			"with",
			"some",
			"lepers",
			"his",
			"birthday",
			"His",
			"visage",
			"commonly",
			"seen",
			"T-shirts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Firefly[10] Centering around the exploits of the dysfunctional Bluth family, new episodes of this comedy starring Jason Bateman will start airing on Netflix in the spring of 2013, seven years after it was originally cancelled by Fox.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 1 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Fox network has cancelled some of the best TV shows of all time. Name three of them, for 10 points each: [10] Starring Nathan Fillion and Morena Baccarin, this space western epic acquired so much post-cancellation support that its story was allowed to continue in the feature film Serenity.",
		"answers": [
			"Firefly",
			"10",
			"Centering",
			"around",
			"exploits",
			"dysfunctional",
			"Bluth",
			"family",
			"new",
			"episodes",
			"this",
			"comedy",
			"starring",
			"Jason",
			"Bateman",
			"will",
			"start",
			"airing",
			"Netflix",
			"in",
			"spring",
			"2013",
			"seven",
			"years",
			"after",
			"was",
			"originally",
			"cancelled",
			"by",
			"Fox"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Firefly[10] Centering around the exploits of the dysfunctional Bluth family, new episodes of this comedy starring Jason Bateman will start airing on Netflix in the spring of 2013, seven years after it was originally cancelled by Fox.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 1 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Fox network has cancelled some of the best TV shows of all time. Name three of them, for 10 points each: [10] Starring Nathan Fillion and Morena Baccarin, this space western epic acquired so much post-cancellation support that its story was allowed to continue in the feature film Serenity.",
		"answers": [
			"Firefly",
			"10",
			"Centering",
			"around",
			"exploits",
			"dysfunctional",
			"Bluth",
			"family",
			"new",
			"episodes",
			"this",
			"comedy",
			"starring",
			"Jason",
			"Bateman",
			"will",
			"start",
			"airing",
			"Netflix",
			"in",
			"spring",
			"2013",
			"seven",
			"years",
			"after",
			"was",
			"originally",
			"cancelled",
			"by",
			"Fox"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Back in Black[10] Back in Black is a song by this Australian band, famous for other songs such as Shoot to Thrill and Highway to Hell.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 2 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this song, famous for its intro guitar riff, whose singer has \"hit the sack\" and is \"glad\" since he's \"been too long\".",
		"answers": [
			"Back",
			"in",
			"Black",
			"10",
			"song",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Australian",
			"band",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"other",
			"songs",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Shoot",
			"to",
			"Thrill",
			"and",
			"Highway",
			"Hell"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kellogg's Frosted Flakes[10]  This fictional serial killer is depicted in The Silence of the Lambs. In the movie adaptation, he is played by Anthony Hopkins and claimed to have eaten a census taker's liver with \"some fava beans and a nice chianti\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 11 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Kellogg cereal known as Zucaritas in Latin America is a good source of Vitamin D. Its namesake flattened corn pieces are coated in sugar, and Tony the Tiger insists that they are delicious.",
		"answers": [
			"Kellogg's",
			"Frosted",
			"Flakes",
			"10",
			"This",
			"fictional",
			"serial",
			"killer",
			"depicted",
			"in",
			"The",
			"Silence",
			"Lambs",
			"In",
			"movie",
			"adaptation",
			"he",
			"played",
			"by",
			"Anthony",
			"Hopkins",
			"and",
			"claimed",
			"to",
			"have",
			"eaten",
			"census",
			"taker's",
			"liver",
			"with",
			"some",
			"fava",
			"beans",
			"nice",
			"chianti"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Song 2\"[10]  Blur clashed with this band whose members include the Gallagher brothers. Their songs include \"Rock 'N' Roll Star\" from Definitely Maybe and \"Wonderwall\" from [What's the Story] Morning Glory.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Britpop song from Blur's self-titled album includes the lines \"I got my head checked\" and \"Pleased to meet you\". Its raucous chorus sees Damon Albarn yell \"Woo-hoo!\".",
		"answers": [
			"Song",
			"2",
			"10",
			"Blur",
			"clashed",
			"with",
			"this",
			"band",
			"whose",
			"members",
			"include",
			"Gallagher",
			"brothers",
			"Their",
			"songs",
			"Rock",
			"'N'",
			"Roll",
			"Star",
			"from",
			"Definitely",
			"Maybe",
			"and",
			"Wonderwall",
			"What's",
			"Story",
			"Morning",
			"Glory"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mojo Jojo (\"mo-jo JO-JO!\")[10]  Mojo Jojo is the main antagonist of this animated TV show broadcast by Cartoon Network. It centers around the superhero trio of Blossom, Bubbles and Buttercup in the city of Townsville.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this purple-caped chimpanzee with green skin and a huge brain. He creates the Rowdyruff Boys to counter his archenemies.",
		"answers": [
			"Mojo",
			"Jojo",
			"mo-jo",
			"JO-JO!",
			"10",
			"main",
			"antagonist",
			"this",
			"animated",
			"TV",
			"show",
			"broadcast",
			"by",
			"Cartoon",
			"Network",
			"It",
			"centers",
			"around",
			"superhero",
			"trio",
			"Blossom",
			"Bubbles",
			"and",
			"Buttercup",
			"in",
			"city",
			"Townsville"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Inigo Montoya[10]  Inigo Montoya and Fezzik accompany Westley on his quest to save Buttercup in this film that notably cuts the ambiguous ending of the William Goldman novel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 15 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Spaniard who is finally able to kill Count Rugen. He does so while repeating a line in which he introduces himself and states \"You killed my father. Prepare to die.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Inigo",
			"Montoya",
			"10",
			"and",
			"Fezzik",
			"accompany",
			"Westley",
			"his",
			"quest",
			"to",
			"save",
			"Buttercup",
			"in",
			"this",
			"film",
			"that"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Marlon Brando Jr.[10]  This actor gained popularity after he appeared as the moody Cal Trask in Kazan's East of Eden. He died in a car crash a month after the release of Rebel Without a Cause, in which he played the angsty teenager Jim Stark.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 18 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Kazan launched the career of this actor who played Stanley Kowalski in A Streetcar Named Desire and Terry Malloy in On the Waterfront. His other roles include motorcycle gang leader Johnny Strabler and Vito Corleone.",
		"answers": [
			"Marlon",
			"Brando",
			"Jr",
			"10",
			"This",
			"actor",
			"gained",
			"popularity",
			"after",
			"he",
			"appeared",
			"as",
			"moody",
			"Cal",
			"Trask",
			"in",
			"Kazan's",
			"East",
			"Eden",
			"He",
			"died",
			"car",
			"crash",
			"month",
			"release",
			"Rebel",
			"Without",
			"Cause",
			"which",
			"played",
			"angsty",
			"teenager",
			"Jim",
			"Stark"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Solid Snake [accept David or Iroquois Pliskin][10]  This offensive class in Team Fortress 2 wields a Rocket Launcher as his primary weapon. He is fond of crazily waving around his melee weapon, a shovel, and lecturing on Sun Tzu, who he believes invented warfare.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This protagonist of the Metal Gear series uses a severely overpowered Grenade Launcher as his Final Smash in Super Smash Bros. Brawl. His job as a spy causes him to frequently hide within cardboard boxes.",
		"answers": [
			"Solid",
			"Snake",
			"David",
			"Iroquois",
			"Pliskin",
			"10",
			"This",
			"offensive",
			"class",
			"in",
			"Team",
			"Fortress",
			"2",
			"wields",
			"Rocket",
			"Launcher",
			"as",
			"his",
			"primary",
			"weapon",
			"He",
			"fond",
			"crazily",
			"waving",
			"around",
			"melee",
			"shovel",
			"and",
			"lecturing",
			"Sun",
			"Tzu",
			"who",
			"he",
			"believes",
			"invented",
			"warfare"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Taylor Swift[10]  The band Red fronted by Michael Barnes performs this genre of music. This subgenre of rock features groups like Relient K, Kutless and Skillet, whose 2000 album Ardent Worship contains the track \"Angels Fall Down\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This singer-songwriter released her album Red in 2012, which contains such tracks like \"We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together\". Her 2008 album, Fearless, contains \"Love Story\" and \"You Belong with Me\".",
		"answers": [
			"Taylor",
			"Swift",
			"10",
			"The",
			"band",
			"Red",
			"fronted",
			"by",
			"Michael",
			"Barnes",
			"performs",
			"this",
			"genre",
			"music",
			"This",
			"subgenre",
			"rock",
			"features",
			"groups",
			"Relient",
			"K",
			"Kutless",
			"and",
			"Skillet",
			"whose",
			"2000",
			"album",
			"Ardent",
			"Worship",
			"contains",
			"track",
			"Angels",
			"Fall",
			"Down"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "H.A.M.M.E.R.[10]  In this song, MC Hammer claims you must \"break it down\" since it is \"Hammer time\" and that he is \"dope on the floor and magic on the mic\". He proposes that this song will make listeners thinner since he is \"makin' 'em sweat\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 15 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  In the Marvel universe, Norman Osborn reforms S.H.I.E.L.D. into this organization after Tony Stark's security system is compromised by the secret Skrull invasion of Earth. This organization is ultimately dissolved following the failed siege of Asgard.",
		"answers": [
			"H",
			"A",
			"M",
			"E",
			"R",
			"10",
			"In",
			"this",
			"song",
			"MC",
			"Hammer",
			"claims",
			"you",
			"must",
			"break",
			"down",
			"since",
			"time",
			"and",
			"that",
			"he",
			"dope",
			"floor",
			"magic",
			"mic",
			"He",
			"proposes",
			"will",
			"make",
			"listeners",
			"thinner",
			"makin'",
			"'em",
			"sweat"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Dragon Ball Z [or Doragon Boru; accept Dragon Ball suffixed by anything][10]  Hirasawa Yui joins the Light Music club and befriends bassist Mio Akiyama and drummer Tainaka Ritsu in this anime. They later form the band Ho-Kago Tea Time which performs at Sakura High School.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 11 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Goku the Saiyan travels around the world learning martial arts, beating up enemies like Vegeta and Piccolo and searching for the title magical orbs in this 291-episode series.",
		"answers": [
			"Dragon",
			"Ball",
			"Z",
			"Doragon",
			"Boru",
			"suffixed",
			"by",
			"anything",
			"10",
			"Hirasawa",
			"Yui",
			"joins",
			"Light",
			"Music",
			"club",
			"and",
			"befriends",
			"bassist",
			"Mio",
			"Akiyama",
			"drummer",
			"Tainaka",
			"Ritsu",
			"in",
			"this",
			"anime",
			"They",
			"later",
			"form",
			"band",
			"Ho-Kago",
			"Tea",
			"Time",
			"which",
			"performs",
			"at",
			"Sakura",
			"High",
			"School"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cowboy Bebop [or Kauboi Bibappu][10]  This Joss Whedon-created series centers around the eccentric crew of Serenity, including the pilot Wash, the mercenary Jayne, and the somewhat unstable River, all led by Captain Malcolm Reynolds.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  An iconic scene from this animated series is the confrontation with Vicious in a church. It follows the bounty hunter Spike Spiegel, who is joined by Edward, Faye Valentine, Jet Black, and the data dog Ein.",
		"answers": [
			"Cowboy",
			"Bebop",
			"Kauboi",
			"Bibappu",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Joss",
			"Whedon-created",
			"series",
			"centers",
			"around",
			"eccentric",
			"crew",
			"Serenity",
			"including",
			"pilot",
			"Wash",
			"mercenary",
			"Jayne",
			"and",
			"somewhat",
			"unstable",
			"River",
			"all",
			"led",
			"by",
			"Captain",
			"Malcolm",
			"Reynolds"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "University of Kentucky Wildcats [or UK][10]  Calipari has been heavily criticized for his recruiting efforts at Kentucky, which focus on players that seek to take advantage of this rule.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 6 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this college basketball team coached by John Calipari.",
		"answers": [
			"University",
			"Kentucky",
			"Wildcats",
			"UK",
			"10",
			"Calipari",
			"has",
			"been",
			"heavily",
			"criticized",
			"for",
			"his",
			"recruiting",
			"efforts",
			"at",
			"which",
			"focus",
			"players",
			"that",
			"seek",
			"to",
			"take",
			"advantage",
			"this",
			"rule"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Michael Phelps[10]  This athlete, at seventeen, was the second-youngest member of the Olympic team. At the Olympics, she swept the backstroke events, and now holds the world record for the women's 100-meter backstroke.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 7 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man hails from Baltimore, Maryland, and his signature event is the 200 butterfly. He currently holds the world record for most gold medals won at the Olympics.",
		"answers": [
			"Michael",
			"Phelps",
			"10",
			"This",
			"athlete",
			"at",
			"seventeen",
			"was",
			"second-youngest",
			"member",
			"Olympic",
			"team",
			"At",
			"Olympics",
			"she",
			"swept",
			"backstroke",
			"events",
			"and",
			"now",
			"holds",
			"world",
			"record",
			"for",
			"women's",
			"100-meter"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The King's Speech[10]  This actor played the speech therapist Lionel Logue in The King's Speech. He is also known for playing the character of Barbosa in The Pirates of the Caribbean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 9 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This 2010 film starred Colin Firth as King George VI as he works to overcome his stutter with the help of a speech therapist. It won seven British Academy Film Awards, including Best Picture.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"King's",
			"Speech",
			"10",
			"This",
			"actor",
			"played",
			"speech",
			"therapist",
			"Lionel",
			"Logue",
			"in",
			"He",
			"also",
			"known",
			"for",
			"playing",
			"character",
			"Barbosa",
			"Pirates",
			"Caribbean"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Back in Black[10]  Back in Black is a song by this Australian band, famous for other songs such as Shoot to Thrill and Highway to Hell.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this song, famous for its intro guitar riff, whose singer has \"hit the sack\" and is \"glad\" since he's \"been too long\".",
		"answers": [
			"Back",
			"in",
			"Black",
			"10",
			"song",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Australian",
			"band",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"other",
			"songs",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Shoot",
			"to",
			"Thrill",
			"and",
			"Highway",
			"Hell"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "San Francisco[10]  McDonald's still hasn't re-opened a franchise in this country, due to the low purchasing power of the krona. This nation is governed by the Althing.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 21 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  In 2010, led by Eric Mar, this California city banned the giving of toys along with Happy Meals. It later unrelatedly tried to ban circumcision, but the measure never made it onto the ballot.\n",
		"answers": [
			"San",
			"Francisco",
			"10",
			"McDonald's",
			"still",
			"hasn't",
			"re-opened",
			"franchise",
			"in",
			"this",
			"country",
			"due",
			"to",
			"low",
			"purchasing",
			"power",
			"krona",
			"This",
			"nation",
			"governed",
			"by",
			"Althing"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Mean Girls[10]  Lindsay Lohan plays both of the twins Hallie and Annie who attempt to bring their divorced mother and father back together in this remake of a 1961 film.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 20 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This teen comedy explained the life of Cady Heron and her adventures with the Regina-led Plastics, who wear pink on Wednesdays.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Mean",
			"Girls",
			"10",
			"Lindsay",
			"Lohan",
			"plays",
			"both",
			"twins",
			"Hallie",
			"and",
			"Annie",
			"who",
			"attempt",
			"to",
			"bring",
			"their",
			"divorced",
			"mother",
			"father",
			"back",
			"together",
			"in",
			"this",
			"remake",
			"1961",
			"film"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "placekicker[10]  This kicker made the tying and winning field goals for the Patriots in the \"Tuck Rule Game,\" and later made the winning kicks in Super Bowls XXXVI (36) and XXXVIII (38). He now plays for the Colts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 16 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this position in American football, which is responsible for getting a ball through the uprights to make a field goal or get the extra point after a touchdown.",
		"answers": [
			"placekicker",
			"10",
			"This",
			"kicker",
			"made",
			"tying",
			"and",
			"winning",
			"field",
			"goals",
			"for",
			"Patriots",
			"in",
			"Tuck",
			"Rule",
			"Game",
			"later",
			"kicks",
			"Super",
			"Bowls",
			"XXXVI",
			"36",
			"XXXVIII",
			"38",
			"He",
			"now",
			"plays",
			"Colts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Key and Peele[10]  Key and Peele have also done multiple skits which mention the teeth of these animals, a talking one of which is voiced by Eddie Murphy in Shrek.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 13 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this show on Comedy Central in which two black comedians perform skits like Dueling Hats, Substitute Teacher, and Pizza Order.",
		"answers": [
			"Key",
			"and",
			"Peele",
			"10",
			"have",
			"also",
			"done",
			"multiple",
			"skits",
			"which",
			"teeth",
			"these",
			"animals",
			"talking",
			"one",
			"voiced",
			"by",
			"Eddie",
			"Murphy",
			"in",
			"Shrek"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Ferris Bueller (accept either)[10]  At the climax of the film, Cameron causes a red one of these objects owned by his father to go flying out the window and land broken on the ground.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 3 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this character who takes a 'day off' in a John Hughes film, skipping school with his friends Cameron and Sloane.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Ferris",
			"Bueller",
			"10",
			"At",
			"climax",
			"film",
			"Cameron",
			"causes",
			"red",
			"one",
			"these",
			"objects",
			"owned",
			"by",
			"his",
			"father",
			"to",
			"go",
			"flying",
			"out",
			"window",
			"and",
			"land",
			"broken",
			"ground"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Millenium Falcon[10]  This captain of the Falcon is inseparable from his Wookie friend Chewbacca, the ship's first mate. In the original Star Wars movie, this smuggler played by Harrison Ford shot Greedo first.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this spaceship, once owned by Lando Calrissian. It was able to make the Kessel run in less than twelve parsecs.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Millenium",
			"Falcon",
			"10",
			"This",
			"captain",
			"inseparable",
			"from",
			"his",
			"Wookie",
			"friend",
			"Chewbacca",
			"ship's",
			"first",
			"mate",
			"In",
			"original",
			"Star",
			"Wars",
			"movie",
			"this",
			"smuggler",
			"played",
			"by",
			"Harrison",
			"Ford",
			"shot",
			"Greedo"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "2 chainz (accept Tauheed Epps or Tity Boi)[10]  2 chainz raps alongside this performer in \"Birthday Song\".  He famously interrupted Taylor Swift at the Video Music Awards and to note that \"Beyonce had one of the best videos of all time\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this rapper, who appeared in \"No Lie\"  along with Drake where he says that he is \"smoking on that gas.\" His current stage name is derived from his trademark jewelry, and he formed Playaz Circle with his friend Dolla Boy.",
		"answers": [
			"2",
			"chainz",
			"Tauheed",
			"Epps",
			"Tity",
			"Boi",
			"10",
			"raps",
			"alongside",
			"this",
			"performer",
			"in",
			"Birthday",
			"Song",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"interrupted",
			"Taylor",
			"Swift",
			"at",
			"Video",
			"Music",
			"Awards",
			"and",
			"to"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Love the Way You Lie\"[10]  This rapper collaborated with Rihanna on \"Love the Way You Lie.\" His latest album, Recovery, features hit singles such as \"Not Afraid,\" and one of his most successful albums was 1999's The Slim Shady LP.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 21 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this song in which the main artist claims that their crazy relationship is \"what happens when a tornado meets a volcano,\" but never seems to tell the truth.",
		"answers": [
			"Love",
			"Way",
			"You",
			"Lie",
			"10",
			"This",
			"rapper",
			"collaborated",
			"with",
			"Rihanna",
			"His",
			"latest",
			"album",
			"Recovery",
			"features",
			"hit",
			"singles",
			"such",
			"as"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Minecraft[10]  This battle arena game, developed by Riot Games, features a spawn point called the \"spawning pool\" and includes such features as Nexuses and Turrets.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This indie game developed by Mojang Inc. was created by Markus Persson, also known as Notch. It features one by one meter blocks to form the gameplay world.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Minecraft",
			"10",
			"This",
			"battle",
			"arena",
			"game",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"Riot",
			"Games",
			"features",
			"spawn",
			"point",
			"called",
			"spawning",
			"pool",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Nexuses",
			"Turrets"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Citizen Kane (or Charles Foster Kane)[10]  Citizen Kane was directed by this man, who also played the title role. He also famously read The War of the Worlds on the radio, inciting a small panic.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 3 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this media magnate, the title character of the film in which he appears, who dies while dropping a snowglobe and saying the word \"Rosebud.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Citizen",
			"Kane",
			"Charles",
			"Foster",
			"10",
			"was",
			"directed",
			"by",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"also",
			"played",
			"title",
			"role",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"read",
			"The",
			"War",
			"Worlds",
			"radio",
			"inciting",
			"small",
			"panic"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Walking Dead[10]  This network broadcasts The Walking Dead, Mad Men, and Breaking Bad.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 19 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this show in which Rick Grimes leads a group on the run from zombies in northern Georgia.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Walking",
			"Dead",
			"10",
			"This",
			"network",
			"broadcasts",
			"Mad",
			"Men",
			"and",
			"Breaking",
			"Bad"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Downton Abbey[10]  This third cousin of the Earl becomes the heir presumptive to the estate after the deaths of the other heirs on the RMS Titanic. He later marries Mary.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This television series centers around the title fictional estate set in Yorkshire, England and focuses on the aristocratic Crawley family and their servants.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Downton",
			"Abbey",
			"10",
			"This",
			"third",
			"cousin",
			"Earl",
			"becomes",
			"heir",
			"presumptive",
			"to",
			"estate",
			"after",
			"deaths",
			"other",
			"heirs",
			"RMS",
			"Titanic",
			"He",
			"later",
			"marries",
			"Mary"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic[10]  This cyan-colored pegasus pony is known for her daring flight stunts and seeks to join an elite group of pony flyers called the \"Wonderbolts\". She is the only pony known to have successfully completed a \"sonic rainboom.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 5 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this television series, the first episode of which sees Twilight Sparkle and her friends unite the Elements of Harmony to save Equestria from Nightmare Moon.",
		"answers": [
			"My",
			"Little",
			"Pony:",
			"Friendship",
			"Magic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"cyan-colored",
			"pegasus",
			"pony",
			"known",
			"for",
			"her",
			"daring",
			"flight",
			"stunts",
			"and",
			"seeks",
			"to",
			"join",
			"an",
			"elite",
			"group",
			"flyers",
			"called",
			"Wonderbolts",
			"She",
			"only",
			"have",
			"successfully",
			"completed",
			"sonic",
			"rainboom"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stephen Colbert[10]  Colbert's best friend for six months was this man, who was part of the cast of SNL before getting his own late-night show on NBC. The house band for his show is The Roots.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 9 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man got his start on the Daily Show, and now hosts his own namesake Report [\"ruh-PORE\"]on Comedy Central, a parody of Fox News opinion shows.",
		"answers": [
			"Stephen",
			"Colbert",
			"10",
			"Colbert's",
			"best",
			"friend",
			"for",
			"six",
			"months",
			"was",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"part",
			"cast",
			"SNL",
			"getting",
			"his",
			"own",
			"late-night",
			"show",
			"NBC",
			"The",
			"house",
			"band",
			"Roots"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: The Princess Bride[10]  This Reiner film focuses on the murder of PFC William Santiago under a \"code red\" ordered by Colonel Jessep, who informs Kaffee that he \"can't handle the truth.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 2 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  \"Wuv, twoo wuv\" is the subject of this comedic film in which Wesley works with Inigo Montoya to rescue Buttercup from Prince Humperdink.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"The",
			"Princess",
			"Bride",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Reiner",
			"film",
			"focuses",
			"murder",
			"PFC",
			"William",
			"Santiago",
			"under",
			"code",
			"red",
			"ordered",
			"by",
			"Colonel",
			"Jessep",
			"who",
			"informs",
			"Kaffee",
			"that",
			"he",
			"can't",
			"handle",
			"truth"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: A Game of Thrones[10]  Lord Eddard Stark is stabbed non-fatally by this Lord Commander of the Kingsguard, the eldest son of Tywin and incestuous lover of Cersei.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 9 | Trash |  | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This first novel in \"A Song of Ice and Fire\" details the reign and death of King Robert I Baratheon.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"A",
			"Game",
			"Thrones",
			"10",
			"Lord",
			"Eddard",
			"Stark",
			"stabbed",
			"non-fatally",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Commander",
			"Kingsguard",
			"eldest",
			"son",
			"Tywin",
			"and",
			"incestuous",
			"lover",
			"Cersei"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Oliver Stanley \"Olly\" Murs[10] Murs came in second on 6th season of this show's British version. The boy band One Direction was formed on  this talent-search show, created by Simon Cowell years after American Idol.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 5 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In one song by this musician, he declares \"I swear you're giving me a heart attack\" right before singing the title  word. For 10 points each: [10] Name this singer whose song \"Troublemaker\" features Flo Rida. His singles \"Heart Skips a Beat\" and \"Dance  with Me Tonight\" also topped the British charts.",
		"answers": [
			"Oliver",
			"Stanley",
			"Olly",
			"Murs",
			"10",
			"came",
			"in",
			"second",
			"6th",
			"season",
			"this",
			"show's",
			"British",
			"version",
			"The",
			"boy",
			"band",
			"One",
			"Direction",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"talent-search",
			"show",
			"created",
			"by",
			"Simon",
			"Cowell",
			"years",
			"after",
			"American",
			"Idol"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Oliver Stanley \"Olly\" Murs[10] Murs came in second on 6th season of this show's British version. The boy band One Direction was formed on  this talent-search show, created by Simon Cowell years after American Idol.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 5 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In one song by this musician, he declares \"I swear you're giving me a heart attack\" right before singing the title  word. For 10 points each: [10] Name this singer whose song \"Troublemaker\" features Flo Rida. His singles \"Heart Skips a Beat\" and \"Dance  with Me Tonight\" also topped the British charts.",
		"answers": [
			"Oliver",
			"Stanley",
			"Olly",
			"Murs",
			"10",
			"came",
			"in",
			"second",
			"6th",
			"season",
			"this",
			"show's",
			"British",
			"version",
			"The",
			"boy",
			"band",
			"One",
			"Direction",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"talent-search",
			"show",
			"created",
			"by",
			"Simon",
			"Cowell",
			"years",
			"after",
			"American",
			"Idol"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Smashing Pumpkins[10] One former saxophone player for this band was Derek Kwan. This Californian alternative rock band is known  almost entirely for their 2004 single \"The Reason,\" which begins with the line \"I'm not a perfect person.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 10 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some related bands, for 10 points each: [10] This band fronted by Billy Corgan formerly had rhythm guitarist James Iha. Their albums include Siamese  Dream and Mellon Collie and the Infinite Sadness. After reforming in 2005, they released the album Zeitgeist.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Smashing",
			"Pumpkins",
			"10",
			"One",
			"former",
			"saxophone",
			"player",
			"for",
			"this",
			"band",
			"was",
			"Derek",
			"Kwan",
			"This",
			"Californian",
			"alternative",
			"rock",
			"known",
			"almost",
			"entirely",
			"their",
			"2004",
			"single",
			"Reason",
			"which",
			"begins",
			"with",
			"line",
			"I'm"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mewtwo[10] This Pokémon was originally going to be the mascot of the series, but that role was ultimately taken by  Pikachu. It evolves using a Moon Stone into Clefable.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: So you wanna be a master of Pokémon? Then name some. For 10 points each: [10] This Pokémon, number 150, comes earlier in the Pokédex than the Pokémon it was supposedly a clone of.",
		"answers": [
			"Mewtwo",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Pokémon",
			"was",
			"originally",
			"going",
			"to",
			"be",
			"mascot",
			"series",
			"but",
			"that",
			"role",
			"ultimately",
			"taken",
			"by",
			"Pikachu",
			"It",
			"evolves",
			"using",
			"Moon",
			"Stone",
			"into",
			"Clefable"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Seventh Seal [or Det Sjunde Inseglet][10] The Seventh Seal [or Det Sjunde Inseglet]",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 9 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: ends with a danse macabre witnessed by Jof, an actor. For 10 points each: [10] Name this film in which Antonius Block, a crusader who returned to a plague-ravaged Sweden, plays chess against Death.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Seventh",
			"Seal",
			"Det",
			"Sjunde",
			"Inseglet",
			"10"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Sopranos[10] This semi-fictional comedy show involves mostly improvised dialogue between characters, and stars Larry David as himself.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 10 | Trash | American | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some HBO shows, for 10 points each: [10] The pilot of this show involves the protagonist meeting with therapist Jennifer Melfi. This most-successful show ever focuses on Tony, a Mafia boss, and his relationship with his work and his family, which the show is named for. ",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Sopranos",
			"10",
			"This",
			"semi-fictional",
			"comedy",
			"show",
			"involves",
			"mostly",
			"improvised",
			"dialogue",
			"between",
			"characters",
			"and",
			"stars",
			"Larry",
			"David",
			"as",
			"himself"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Psych[10] In the series finale of season 3 of Psych, fake psychic Shawn Spencer is challenged by Mr. Yang, a serial killer based on this famous Bay Area serial killer who was active in 60's and 70's California.  A movie based on this killer was released in 2007.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer these seemingly unrelated questions: [10] Starring Dulé Hill and James Roday, the main protagonist of this television show is obsessed with pineapples. The actors playing a pair of detectives for the Santa Barbara police each starred in made-for-TV movies: Model Behavior and The Luck of the Irish.",
		"answers": [
			"Psych",
			"10",
			"In",
			"series",
			"finale",
			"season",
			"3",
			"fake",
			"psychic",
			"Shawn",
			"Spencer",
			"challenged",
			"by",
			"Mr",
			"Yang",
			"serial",
			"killer",
			"based",
			"this",
			"famous",
			"Bay",
			"Area",
			"who",
			"was",
			"active",
			"in",
			"60's",
			"and",
			"70's",
			"California",
			"A",
			"movie",
			"released",
			"2007"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Psych[10] In the series finale of season 3 of Psych, fake psychic Shawn Spencer is challenged by Mr. Yang, a serial killer based on this famous Bay Area serial killer who was active in 60's and 70's California.  A movie based on this killer was released in 2007.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer these seemingly unrelated questions: [10] Starring Dulé Hill and James Roday, the main protagonist of this television show is obsessed with pineapples. The actors playing a pair of detectives for the Santa Barbara police each starred in made-for-TV movies: Model Behavior and The Luck of the Irish.",
		"answers": [
			"Psych",
			"10",
			"In",
			"series",
			"finale",
			"season",
			"3",
			"fake",
			"psychic",
			"Shawn",
			"Spencer",
			"challenged",
			"by",
			"Mr",
			"Yang",
			"serial",
			"killer",
			"based",
			"this",
			"famous",
			"Bay",
			"Area",
			"who",
			"was",
			"active",
			"in",
			"60's",
			"and",
			"70's",
			"California",
			"A",
			"movie",
			"released",
			"2007"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Man Your Man Could Smell Like [prompt \"Isaiah Mustafa;\" prompt answers such as \"Old Spice guy,\" though don't let teams know you can prompt them unless you do prompt this][10]  The Man Your Man Could Smell Like is in ads for this deodorant brand which produces Red Zone body spray. Its other campaigns include \"Experience is Everything.\"",
		"prompts": [
			"Isaiah",
			"Mustafa"
		],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 12 | Trash | None | HS",
		"subject": "Trash",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In one parody of this figure, Grover of Sesame Street teaches children how to use the word \"on,\" and a seashell in his hand opens up to \"tickets to that thing you love,\" which melt into diamonds. For 10 points each: [10] Name this African-American figure first seen in a shower saying \"Look at your man, now back to me\" and later seen on a horse.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Man",
			"Your",
			"Could",
			"Smell",
			"Like"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Krishna[10] Arjuna was a member of this family, led by Yudhisthira during the Battle of Kurukshetra. This family fought against the Kauravas over the throne of Hastinapura.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 8 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This figure's birth occurred after his parents Vasudeva and Devaki were imprisoned. [10] Name this charioteer of Arjuna and blue-skinned avatar of Vishnu. He gave advice to Arjuna before the Battle of Kurukshetra in the Bhagavad Gita, and the Mahabharata culminates in his death.",
		"answers": [
			"Krishna",
			"10",
			"Arjuna",
			"was",
			"member",
			"this",
			"family",
			"led",
			"by",
			"Yudhisthira",
			"during",
			"Battle",
			"Kurukshetra",
			"This",
			"fought",
			"against",
			"Kauravas",
			"over",
			"throne",
			"Hastinapura"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Susano'o [or Takehaya Susanoo-no-Mikoto][10] Susanoo was born from the nose of this creator god during a purification ceremony, which occurred after this god returned from Yomi. He plunged a spear into the ocean with his wife, forming the islands of ancient Japan.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 3 | 18 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In Izumo Province, this figure turned Kushinada into a comb to hide in his hair. [10] Name this god of sea and storms who created five men from a necklace in a contest with his sister Amaterasu. This ruler of Yomi obtained the sword Kusanagi from the tail of the dragon Yamata no Orochi.",
		"answers": [
			"Susano'o",
			"Takehaya",
			"Susanoo-no-Mikoto",
			"10",
			"Susanoo",
			"was",
			"born",
			"from",
			"nose",
			"this",
			"creator",
			"god",
			"during",
			"purification",
			"ceremony",
			"which",
			"occurred",
			"after",
			"returned",
			"Yomi",
			"He",
			"plunged",
			"spear",
			"into",
			"ocean",
			"with",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"forming",
			"islands",
			"ancient",
			"Japan"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sekhmet [or Sachmis; or Sakhmet; or Sekhet; or Sakhet][10] Sekhmet's counterpart in Lower Egypt was this cat-headed goddess of warfare and protection, whose name translates to \"She of the Ointment Jar.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 8 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: During battle, this deity was said to drive a chariot in front of the pharaoh while firing flaming arrows. [10] Name this lion-headed Egyptian goddess who ravaged the earth, nearly destroying all of humanity. After drinking beer dyed with red ochre and pomegranate, she transformed into the cow-headed Hathor.",
		"answers": [
			"Sekhmet",
			"Sachmis",
			"Sakhmet",
			"Sekhet",
			"Sakhet",
			"10",
			"Sekhmet's",
			"counterpart",
			"in",
			"Lower",
			"Egypt",
			"was",
			"this",
			"cat-headed",
			"goddess",
			"warfare",
			"and",
			"protection",
			"whose",
			"name",
			"translates",
			"to",
			"She",
			"Ointment",
			"Jar"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Pegasus[10] Pegasus was famously ridden by this hero, who slew the Chimera before being stung by a gadfly and falling from the sky for his hubris.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2014 | 2 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Hippocrene spring on Mount Helicon was created by this figure. For 10 points each: [10] Name this winged-figure whose hooves created springs wherever they struck the ground.",
		"answers": [
			"Pegasus",
			"10",
			"was",
			"famously",
			"ridden",
			"by",
			"this",
			"hero",
			"who",
			"slew",
			"Chimera",
			"being",
			"stung",
			"gadfly",
			"and",
			"falling",
			"from",
			"sky",
			"for",
			"his",
			"hubris"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Odin (accept Woden, Wotan, or Wodan)[10] To gain the power of the runes, Odin used a spear to hang himself from this ash tree for nine days.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 3 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this chief deity of Norse myth, who gave up an eye to drink from the well of Mimir [MIH-mir].",
		"answers": [
			"Odin",
			"Woden",
			"Wotan",
			"Wodan",
			"10",
			"To",
			"gain",
			"power",
			"runes",
			"used",
			"spear",
			"to",
			"hang",
			"himself",
			"from",
			"this",
			"ash",
			"tree",
			"for",
			"nine",
			"days"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Telemachus[10] The ambush that awaited Telemachus [teh-leh-MAH-kus] was planned by suitors pursuing this queen, whose husband was absent for twenty years.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 3 | 10 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this youth, who was advised by Athena to take a different route home after visiting Nestor and Menelaus [meh-neh-LAY-us].",
		"answers": [
			"Telemachus",
			"10",
			"The",
			"ambush",
			"that",
			"awaited",
			"teh-leh-MAH-kus",
			"was",
			"planned",
			"by",
			"suitors",
			"pursuing",
			"this",
			"queen",
			"whose",
			"husband",
			"absent",
			"for",
			"twenty",
			"years"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Heracles (accept Hercules)[10] Zeus fathered Heracles by disguising himself as this king and sleeping with Alcmene [alk-MEE-nee] for three days and nights.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 4 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this hero who was undone by the poison of the Lernaean [LER-nay-un] hydra, which he killed as one of twelve labors ordered by his cousin Eurystheus [yoo-RIS-thee-us].",
		"answers": [
			"Heracles",
			"Hercules",
			"10",
			"Zeus",
			"fathered",
			"by",
			"disguising",
			"himself",
			"as",
			"this",
			"king",
			"and",
			"sleeping",
			"with",
			"Alcmene",
			"alk-MEE-nee",
			"for",
			"three",
			"days",
			"nights"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Theseus[10] After arriving in Athens to claim his rightful place, this wife of Aegeas and ex-wife of Jason convinced the king to try to poison Theseus. She also killed her sons Alcimenes [al-ki-MEE-nees] and Tisander.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 4 | 2 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this Athenian king and husband of Hippolyta [hih-poe-LIE-tah]. After this person forgot to change the flags following his conquering of the Labyrinth, his father Aegeas [ay-JEE-us] jumped into the sea.",
		"answers": [
			"Theseus",
			"10",
			"After",
			"arriving",
			"in",
			"Athens",
			"to",
			"claim",
			"his",
			"rightful",
			"place",
			"this",
			"wife",
			"Aegeas",
			"and",
			"ex-wife",
			"Jason",
			"convinced",
			"king",
			"try",
			"poison",
			"She",
			"also",
			"killed",
			"her",
			"sons",
			"Alcimenes",
			"al-ki-MEE-nees",
			"Tisander"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nuwa [or Nu Gua] [10] Nuwa is a deity from the mythology of this nation. In this mythology, the chief deity is the Jade Emperor.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In the Investiture of the Gods, this goddess' subordinates included the Nine-headed Pheasant. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this creator goddess who cut off the legs of a tortoise to repair the pillar of heaven. ",
		"answers": [
			"Nuwa",
			"Nu",
			"Gua",
			"10",
			"deity",
			"from",
			"mythology",
			"this",
			"nation",
			"In",
			"chief",
			"Jade",
			"Emperor"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "immortality[10] This centaur surrendered his immortality to free Prometheus. He mentored a number of heroes including Heracles and Achilles.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 17 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This quality was possessed by Pollux, but not Castor. For 10 points each: [10] Name this quality conferred by nectar and ambrosia. Possessed by the gods of Olympus, it makes the gods unchanging in their imperfections.",
		"answers": [
			"immortality",
			"10",
			"This",
			"centaur",
			"surrendered",
			"his",
			"to",
			"free",
			"Prometheus",
			"He",
			"mentored",
			"number",
			"heroes",
			"including",
			"Heracles",
			"and",
			"Achilles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Thor[10] Cursed with impotence during the Pandavas' exile, this Hindu hero from the Mahabharata crossdressed as Brihannala to teach music and dance. When the curse was lifted, he took up his bow to fight the Kauravas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 15 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Cross-dressing in mythology is quite popular! For 10 points each, name some figures who did so.  [10] This Norse god of thunder reluctantly dressed up as Freyja to marry the giant Thrym, who stole this god's hammer Mjolnir. ",
		"answers": [
			"Thor",
			"10",
			"Cursed",
			"with",
			"impotence",
			"during",
			"Pandavas'",
			"exile",
			"this",
			"Hindu",
			"hero",
			"from",
			"Mahabharata",
			"crossdressed",
			"as",
			"Brihannala",
			"to",
			"teach",
			"music",
			"and",
			"dance",
			"When",
			"curse",
			"was",
			"lifted",
			"he",
			"took",
			"up",
			"his",
			"bow",
			"fight",
			"Kauravas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cúchulainn (\"coo-HEL-en\") [or Cuhillin; or Setanta][10] Cúchulainn earned his name by killing one of these animals belonging to a blacksmith, though he later died after eating the meat of one of these. Cerberus is a three-headed one of these animals.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He is the son of Lugh and Deichtine. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Irish hero of the Ulster Cycle known for his berserker frenzy in battle. He was the sole defender in the Cattle Raid of Cooley.",
		"answers": [
			"Cúchulainn",
			"coo-HEL-en",
			"Cuhillin",
			"Setanta",
			"10",
			"earned",
			"his",
			"name",
			"by",
			"killing",
			"one",
			"these",
			"animals",
			"belonging",
			"to",
			"blacksmith",
			"though",
			"he",
			"later",
			"died",
			"after",
			"eating",
			"meat",
			"Cerberus",
			"three-headed"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "King Arthur Pendragon [prompt on Pendragon][10] Geoffrey of Monmouth wrote that this nephew of Arthur seduced Arthur's wife Guinevere, forcing Arthur to return from his wars against Rome. He was later portrayed as Arthur's son by his half-sister Morgause.",
		"prompts": [
			"Pendragon",
			"10",
			"Geoffrey",
			"Monmouth",
			"wrote",
			"that",
			"this",
			"nephew",
			"Arthur",
			"seduced",
			"Arthur's",
			"wife",
			"Guinevere",
			"forcing",
			"Arthur",
			"to",
			"return",
			"from",
			"his",
			"wars",
			"against",
			"Rome",
			"He",
			"was",
			"later",
			"portrayed",
			"as",
			"Arthur's",
			"son",
			"by",
			"his",
			"half-sister",
			"Morgause"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about a myth system written about by Geoffrey of Monmouth. For 10 points each: [10] Geoffrey of Monmouth's self-proclaimed \"histories\" mostly deal with this legendary king of England, who wielded Excalibur.",
		"answers": [
			"King",
			"Arthur",
			"Pendragon"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Psyche[10] Psyche's sisters convinced her to sneak a peek at her husband as he slept. Cupid didn't turn out to be hideous at all, but Psyche made this mistake, causing Cupid to wake up and flee.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 3 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: She was told that if she kept silent about her pregnancy, her child would be immortal. For 10 points each: [10] Name this woman prophesied to marry a hideous monster. She was assisted by ants, a talking reed, and an eagle in her quest to be reunited with her lover Cupid. ",
		"answers": [
			"Psyche",
			"10",
			"Psyche's",
			"sisters",
			"convinced",
			"her",
			"to",
			"sneak",
			"peek",
			"at",
			"husband",
			"as",
			"he",
			"slept",
			"Cupid",
			"didn't",
			"turn",
			"out",
			"be",
			"hideous",
			"all",
			"but",
			"made",
			"this",
			"mistake",
			"causing",
			"wake",
			"up",
			"and",
			"flee"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "beheading [or decapitation][10] Lancelot's encounter with the red-girdled knight is probably derived from an earlier depiction of this Arthurian knight's beheading game with the Green Knight.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 5 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In two instances, a game centered on this action included three faked strikes to test the recipient's resolve. For 10 points each: [10] Give this method of death, committed by Judith against Holofernes, and by Lancelot against a red-girdled knight in The High History of the Holy Grail.",
		"answers": [
			"beheading",
			"decapitation",
			"10",
			"Lancelot's",
			"encounter",
			"with",
			"red-girdled",
			"knight",
			"probably",
			"derived",
			"from",
			"an",
			"earlier",
			"depiction",
			"this",
			"Arthurian",
			"knight's",
			"game",
			"Green",
			"Knight"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "floods[10] In the Sumerian creation myth, this patron god of Eridu warns one human to build an ark to escape the oncoming flood. He is also the god of seawater, crafts, and mischief.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In Chinese mythology, Gun is first appointed to try to staunch the Great one of these with magically absorptive soil. For 10 points each: [10] Name these disasters common in mythology and religion, usually as divine retribution intended to start human civilization anew. In the book of Genesis, Noah saves his family and pairs of animals from one of these events.",
		"answers": [
			"floods",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Sumerian",
			"creation",
			"myth",
			"this",
			"patron",
			"god",
			"Eridu",
			"warns",
			"one",
			"human",
			"to",
			"build",
			"an",
			"ark",
			"escape",
			"oncoming",
			"flood",
			"He",
			"also",
			"seawater",
			"crafts",
			"and",
			"mischief"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Agamemnon[10] Calchas recommended interrogating Helenus, who revealed that the Achaeans would need the bones of this figure to take Troy. He was given an ivory shoulder blade after his father Tantalus cut him up for the gods.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about the prophecies of Calchas (\"KAHL-kahs\"), for 10 points each: [10] Calchas told this commander of Greek forces to sacrifice his daughter Iphigenia before setting sail for Troy. After the war, he was murdered by his wife Clytemnestra.",
		"answers": [
			"Agamemnon",
			"10",
			"Calchas",
			"recommended",
			"interrogating",
			"Helenus",
			"who",
			"revealed",
			"that",
			"Achaeans",
			"would",
			"need",
			"bones",
			"this",
			"figure",
			"to",
			"take",
			"Troy",
			"He",
			"was",
			"given",
			"an",
			"ivory",
			"shoulder",
			"blade",
			"after",
			"his",
			"father",
			"Tantalus",
			"cut",
			"him",
			"up",
			"for",
			"gods"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "breathing fire [or equivalents][10] Examples of these fire-breathing creatures in Greek myth include Ladon and Python. They're commonly depicted in Chinese myth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 2 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Konabos, some horses owned by Ares, possessed this ability. For 10 points each: [10] Name this ability. Bellerophon slew the Chimera because the beast attempted to use this ability while a lead spear was stuck down its throat.",
		"answers": [
			"breathing",
			"fire",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"Examples",
			"these",
			"fire-breathing",
			"creatures",
			"in",
			"Greek",
			"myth",
			"include",
			"Ladon",
			"and",
			"Python",
			"They're",
			"commonly",
			"depicted",
			"Chinese"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Jörmungandr [accept Midgard Serpent or World Serpent][10] That last battle will occur during this event, in which Fenrir will break free and eat the moon and the sun. It will also feature the destruction of the world by the armies of the fire-giant Surtr.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 10 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He surrounds the world and eats his own tail. For 10 points each: [10] Name this enormous monster who will kill and be killed by Thor in an epic battle.",
		"answers": [
			"Jörmungandr",
			"Midgard",
			"Serpent",
			"World",
			"10",
			"That",
			"last",
			"battle",
			"will",
			"occur",
			"during",
			"this",
			"event",
			"in",
			"which",
			"Fenrir",
			"break",
			"free",
			"and",
			"eat",
			"moon",
			"sun",
			"It",
			"also",
			"feature",
			"destruction",
			"world",
			"by",
			"armies",
			"fire-giant",
			"Surtr"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ares[10] This son of Myrrha and Cinyras was raised by Aphrodite, who fell in love with him. He died when a boar gored him, and Aphrodite patronized a yearly festival in his honor.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 21 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some lovers of Aphrodite, for 10 points each: [10] This god was trapped under a net with Aphrodite by her jealous husband Hephaestus. With her, he sired Phobos and Deimos, who accompanied him to war.",
		"answers": [
			"Ares",
			"10",
			"This",
			"son",
			"Myrrha",
			"and",
			"Cinyras",
			"was",
			"raised",
			"by",
			"Aphrodite",
			"who",
			"fell",
			"in",
			"love",
			"with",
			"him",
			"He",
			"died",
			"when",
			"boar",
			"gored",
			"patronized",
			"yearly",
			"festival",
			"his",
			"honor"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ra[10] Ra sent this terrible lioness to destroy humankind when they conspired against him. Before she could slaughter everyone, he stopped her by tricking her into drinking too much beer.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 10 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Mnevis bull symbolized this god in Heliopolis. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Egyptian Sun deity who slays Apophis in the form of a cat. He is often depicted with a falcon head.",
		"answers": [
			"Ra",
			"10",
			"sent",
			"this",
			"terrible",
			"lioness",
			"to",
			"destroy",
			"humankind",
			"when",
			"they",
			"conspired",
			"against",
			"him",
			"Before",
			"she",
			"could",
			"slaughter",
			"everyone",
			"he",
			"stopped",
			"her",
			"by",
			"tricking",
			"into",
			"drinking",
			"too",
			"much",
			"beer"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Argonauts[10] This former king of Thrace helped the Argonauts by revealing the secret to pass through the Sympleglades. His abuse of his foresight led to his blindness.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Members of this group included Hercules, the twins Castor and Pollux, and the only female, Atalanta. For 10 points each: [10] Name this group of adventurers that Jason took on his quest for the Golden Fleece.",
		"answers": [
			"Argonauts",
			"10",
			"This",
			"former",
			"king",
			"Thrace",
			"helped",
			"by",
			"revealing",
			"secret",
			"to",
			"pass",
			"through",
			"Sympleglades",
			"His",
			"abuse",
			"his",
			"foresight",
			"led",
			"blindness"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Furies [accept Erinyes, Eumenides, or Dirae][10] These Greek spirits of charm and beauty often appear nude in many sculptures. One of them, Thalia, shares her name with the Muse of comedy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer the following about mythological groups of three. [10] These flying hags persecute oath-breakers and murderers. They pursued Orestes until Athena personally stopped them.",
		"answers": [
			"Furies",
			"Erinyes",
			"Eumenides",
			"Dirae",
			"10",
			"These",
			"Greek",
			"spirits",
			"charm",
			"and",
			"beauty",
			"often",
			"appear",
			"nude",
			"in",
			"many",
			"sculptures",
			"One",
			"them",
			"Thalia",
			"shares",
			"her",
			"name",
			"with",
			"Muse",
			"comedy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hephaestus (do not accept or prompt on \"Vulcan\")[10] With Athena as his charioteer, this Greek soldier inflicted a wound upon Ares who was fighting alongside the Trojans. This man had ventured with Odysseus into Troy to retrieve the Palladium.",
		"prompts": [
			"Vulcan",
			"10",
			"With",
			"Athena",
			"as",
			"his",
			"charioteer",
			"this",
			"Greek",
			"soldier",
			"inflicted",
			"wound",
			"upon",
			"Ares",
			"who",
			"was",
			"fighting",
			"alongside",
			"Trojans",
			"This",
			"man",
			"had",
			"ventured",
			"with",
			"Odysseus",
			"into",
			"Troy",
			"to",
			"retrieve",
			"Palladium"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Though the god of war, it became a running joke in Greek mythology that Ares was actually a wimp. For 10 points each; [10] After learning that Ares was having an affair with his wife Aphrodite, this god of the smithy constructed a golden net and caught them in the act to the humor of the rest of the gods.",
		"answers": [
			"Hephaestus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "flood or Great Deluge[10] In Hindusim, this god's son Manu was the progenitor of mankind and had also survived a flood after being forewarned by the fish Shaphari. This god was the creator member of the Trimurti.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 15 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Noah survived one of these events using an ark. For 10 points each: [10] Name these events, one of which Deucalion and Pyrrha survived. Those two later recreated mankind using rocks.",
		"answers": [
			"flood",
			"Great",
			"Deluge",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Hindusim",
			"this",
			"god's",
			"son",
			"Manu",
			"was",
			"progenitor",
			"mankind",
			"and",
			"had",
			"also",
			"survived",
			"after",
			"being",
			"forewarned",
			"by",
			"fish",
			"Shaphari",
			"This",
			"god",
			"creator",
			"member",
			"Trimurti"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Jason[10] These hero twins were children of Leda. They were called the Dioscuri in Greek and the Gemini in Latin.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 20 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these members of the Argonauts: [10] This leader of the Argonauts began the expedition after being made to find the Golden Fleece by the usurping king Pelias.",
		"answers": [
			"Jason",
			"10",
			"These",
			"hero",
			"twins",
			"were",
			"children",
			"Leda",
			"They",
			"called",
			"Dioscuri",
			"in",
			"Greek",
			"and",
			"Gemini",
			"Latin"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Greek underworld (or Hades) [10] This ferryman escorted souls across the Styx into the underworld. A coin was usually buried with the dead to pay this son of Nyx and Erebus.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 6 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Its entrance is guarded by the three-headed dog Cerberus. For 10 points each:  [10] The Styx and Acheron rivers are located in what place in Greek mythology, where Persephone reigns as queen for nine months of the year? ",
		"answers": [
			"Greek",
			"underworld",
			"Hades",
			"10",
			"This",
			"ferryman",
			"escorted",
			"souls",
			"across",
			"Styx",
			"into",
			"A",
			"coin",
			"was",
			"usually",
			"buried",
			"with",
			"dead",
			"to",
			"pay",
			"this",
			"son",
			"Nyx",
			"and",
			"Erebus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cú Chulainn (prompt on \"Sétanta\")[10] Cú Chulainn was the son of this deity known as \"the long-handed\". After the Cattle Raid of Cooley this god healed Cú Culainn over a period of three days.",
		"prompts": [
			"Sétanta",
			"10",
			"Cú",
			"Chulainn",
			"was",
			"son",
			"this",
			"deity",
			"known",
			"as",
			"long-handed",
			"After",
			"Cattle",
			"Raid",
			"Cooley",
			"this",
			"god",
			"healed",
			"Cú",
			"Culainn",
			"over",
			"period",
			"three",
			"days"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 20 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This hero ensures that he would die standing upright by tying his intestines to a rock. For 10 points each: [10] Name this mythical warrior who was taught by Scathach and fights in the Cattle Raid of Cooley against Queen Medb. ",
		"answers": [
			"Cú",
			"Chulainn"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yggdrasil[10] This god hung himself upside-down from Yggdrasil for nine days and nine nights to be allowed to understand the language of runes. He also sacrificed an eye to drink from the Well of Mimir.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Well of Mimir is located under one of this entity's roots. For 10 points each: [10] Name this \"World Tree\" in Norse mythology. Its roots span Asgard and Hel.",
		"answers": [
			"Yggdrasil",
			"10",
			"This",
			"god",
			"hung",
			"himself",
			"upside-down",
			"from",
			"for",
			"nine",
			"days",
			"and",
			"nights",
			"to",
			"be",
			"allowed",
			"understand",
			"language",
			"runes",
			"He",
			"also",
			"sacrificed",
			"an",
			"eye",
			"drink",
			"Well",
			"Mimir"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ajax[10] Ajax the Greater is also sometimes named after this father of his who helped his friend Heracles in an earlier siege of Troy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 3 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One man with this name slaughtered a flock of sheep in a fit of madness for not winning Achilles's armor. For 10 points each: [10] Give this name of two men who fought in the Trojan War, one known as \"the Greater\" and the other as \"the Lesser.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Ajax",
			"10",
			"Greater",
			"also",
			"sometimes",
			"named",
			"after",
			"this",
			"father",
			"his",
			"who",
			"helped",
			"friend",
			"Heracles",
			"in",
			"an",
			"earlier",
			"siege",
			"Troy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cupid [10] Associated with love, music, dance, and motherhood this cow-headed Egyptian goddess is said to hold up the sky.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 20 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name these gods and goddesses of love: [10] This Roman God of desire and affection is the son of Venus. He is often contrasted with the Greek Eros and usually is depicted as an archer with arrows of gold which cause people to fall in love. ",
		"answers": [
			"Cupid",
			"10",
			"Associated",
			"with",
			"love",
			"music",
			"dance",
			"and",
			"motherhood",
			"this",
			"cow-headed",
			"Egyptian",
			"goddess",
			"said",
			"to",
			"hold",
			"up",
			"sky"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Xibalba [shee-BAHL-bah][10] This pair of mythological siblings descended into Xibalba to play a ball game and defeat the Death Gods. They consist of Hunahpu [WAH-nuh-pwuh] and Xbalanque [shi-BAY-lan-kay].",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 5 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The name of this location is roughly translated as \"place of fear.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this underworld overseen by the Death Gods which included trials like the Bat House and the Razor House.",
		"answers": [
			"Xibalba",
			"shee-BAHL-bah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"pair",
			"mythological",
			"siblings",
			"descended",
			"into",
			"to",
			"play",
			"ball",
			"game",
			"and",
			"defeat",
			"Death",
			"Gods",
			"They",
			"consist",
			"Hunahpu",
			"WAH-nuh-pwuh",
			"Xbalanque",
			"shi-BAY-lan-kay"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vishnu[10] This god obtained a blue throat when he swallowed the poison produced during the churning. He is the father of Ganesh.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 12 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer the following about the churning of the ocean in Hindu mythology: [10] This Preserver member of the Trimurti took on the form of a turtle to act as a pivot for the mountain used in the churning. He is known for his many avatars. ",
		"answers": [
			"Vishnu",
			"10",
			"This",
			"god",
			"obtained",
			"blue",
			"throat",
			"when",
			"he",
			"swallowed",
			"poison",
			"produced",
			"during",
			"churning",
			"He",
			"father",
			"Ganesh"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Pegasus[10] This man tamed the winged-horse Pegasus using a golden bridle on the advice of Athena.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 4 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This creature helped fight against the Solymi and Amazons. For 10 points each: [10] Name this sibling of Chrysaor which was captured while it drank from the Pirene.",
		"answers": [
			"Pegasus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"tamed",
			"winged-horse",
			"using",
			"golden",
			"bridle",
			"advice",
			"Athena"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "giant (prompt on \"jotnar\")[10] Ymir was killed by Odin, Vili, and Ve, who were the first generation of this pantheon of gods. They wage a war with, and then combine with, the Vanir.",
		"prompts": [
			"jotnar",
			"10",
			"Ymir",
			"was",
			"killed",
			"by",
			"Odin",
			"Vili",
			"and",
			"Ve",
			"who",
			"were",
			"first",
			"generation",
			"this",
			"pantheon",
			"gods",
			"They",
			"wage",
			"war",
			"with",
			"and",
			"then",
			"combine",
			"with",
			"Vanir"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about the death of Ymir, which led to the creation of the world: [10] Ymir was the primordial first example of this type of creature in Norse mythology. The jotunn were the \"frost\" type of these large creatures.",
		"answers": [
			"giant"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "giant (prompt on \"jotnar\")[10] Ymir was killed by Odin, Vili, and Ve, who were the first generation of this pantheon of gods. They wage a war with, and then combine with, the Vanir.",
		"prompts": [
			"jotnar",
			"10",
			"Ymir",
			"was",
			"killed",
			"by",
			"Odin",
			"Vili",
			"and",
			"Ve",
			"who",
			"were",
			"first",
			"generation",
			"this",
			"pantheon",
			"gods",
			"They",
			"wage",
			"war",
			"with",
			"and",
			"then",
			"combine",
			"with",
			"Vanir"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about the death of Ymir, which led to the creation of the world: [10] Ymir was the primordial first example of this type of creature in Norse mythology. The jotunn were the \"frost\" type of these large creatures.",
		"answers": [
			"giant"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "centaurs[10] The immortal son of Cronus, this centaur served as the teacher of many heroes including Theseus.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 9 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: These creatures were born out of the union between Ixion and a thundercloud he believed to be Hera. For 10 points each: [10] Nessus was a famous one of what half-man, half-horse combinations?",
		"answers": [
			"centaurs",
			"10",
			"The",
			"immortal",
			"son",
			"Cronus",
			"this",
			"centaur",
			"served",
			"as",
			"teacher",
			"many",
			"heroes",
			"including",
			"Theseus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Krishna[10] Krishna is an avatar of this \"Preserver\" of the Hindu Trimurti. His other avatars include Rama and the fish Matsya, while his final avatar Kalki is yet to come.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 1 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this blue-skinned figure, a son of Devaki who served as the charioteer of Prince Arjuna. The dialogue between him and Arjuna makes up most of the Bhagavad Gita.",
		"answers": [
			"Krishna",
			"10",
			"an",
			"avatar",
			"this",
			"Preserver",
			"Hindu",
			"Trimurti",
			"His",
			"other",
			"avatars",
			"include",
			"Rama",
			"and",
			"fish",
			"Matsya",
			"while",
			"his",
			"final",
			"Kalki",
			"yet",
			"to",
			"come"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Thoth [or Djehuty; be lenient with vowels] [10] Thoth was sometimes described as the son of this bird-headed god, who drove the sun barge across the sky each day. He was sometimes merged with Amun or Atum.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 2 | 2 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  This god wrote a namesake book supposedly buried near Memphis that would give the reader the spells needed to control the gods. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Egyptian god with the long beak of an ibis. He took up residence on the moon and served as a divine scribe. ",
		"answers": [
			"Thoth",
			"Djehuty",
			"be",
			"lenient",
			"with",
			"vowels",
			"10",
			"was",
			"sometimes",
			"described",
			"as",
			"son",
			"this",
			"bird-headed",
			"god",
			"who",
			"drove",
			"sun",
			"barge",
			"across",
			"sky",
			"each",
			"day",
			"He",
			"merged",
			"Amun",
			"Atum"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "a boulder [or rock or stone] [10]  Sisyphus's crime was stopping this phenomenon from happening by tying up the god of it in his own chains. In the Iliad, the god of this phenomenon carries Sarpedon's corpse away along with his brother Sleep.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 11 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer these questions about the myth of Sisyphus, as in the actual Greek myth, for 10 points each. [10] Sisyphus's punishment is to push one of these objects uphill in Tartarus forever. ",
		"answers": [
			"a",
			"boulder",
			"rock",
			"stone",
			"10",
			"Sisyphus's",
			"crime",
			"was",
			"stopping",
			"this",
			"phenomenon",
			"from",
			"happening",
			"by",
			"tying",
			"up",
			"god",
			"in",
			"his",
			"own",
			"chains",
			"In",
			"Iliad",
			"carries",
			"Sarpedon's",
			"corpse",
			"away",
			"along",
			"with",
			"brother",
			"Sleep"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cadmus[10]  This man survived the great flood by hiding with his wife Pyrrha in a large chest. He and Pyrrha threw the \"bones of their mother,\" or stones, behind them to form the new human race.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 14 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Phoenician prince and brother of Europa was given dragon's teeth by Athena to plant in the ground. The oracle at Delphi told him to follow a cow, leading him to found Thebes.",
		"answers": [
			"Cadmus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"survived",
			"great",
			"flood",
			"by",
			"hiding",
			"with",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"Pyrrha",
			"in",
			"large",
			"chest",
			"He",
			"and",
			"threw",
			"bones",
			"their",
			"mother",
			"stones",
			"behind",
			"them",
			"to",
			"form",
			"new",
			"human",
			"race"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Thor[10]  This goddess and wife of Thor had golden hair, an allusion to wheat. Loki once cut her hair off, after which Thor threatened to break all of Loki's bones.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 8 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This son of Odin was served by Djalfi and wielded the hammer Mjolnir.",
		"answers": [
			"Thor",
			"10",
			"This",
			"goddess",
			"and",
			"wife",
			"had",
			"golden",
			"hair",
			"an",
			"allusion",
			"to",
			"wheat",
			"Loki",
			"once",
			"cut",
			"her",
			"off",
			"after",
			"which",
			"threatened",
			"break",
			"all",
			"Loki's",
			"bones"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sekhmet [accept Sakhmet, Sachmis, Sekhet, or Sakhet][10]  Sekhmet is the wife and sister of this green-skinned god, the patron of craftsmen. He is depicted in the linens of a mummy and carries a was sceptre with a djed and an ankh. In some myths, he thought the universe into existence.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This goddess has a lion's head and a woman's body. Ra created her to destroy mankind, but when she got out of hand, he tricked her into drinking seven thousand jars of beer, transforming her into her counterpart Hathor.",
		"answers": [
			"Sekhmet",
			"Sakhmet",
			"Sachmis",
			"Sekhet",
			"Sakhet",
			"10",
			"wife",
			"and",
			"sister",
			"this",
			"green-skinned",
			"god",
			"patron",
			"craftsmen",
			"He",
			"depicted",
			"in",
			"linens",
			"mummy",
			"carries",
			"was",
			"sceptre",
			"with",
			"djed",
			"an",
			"ankh",
			"In",
			"some",
			"myths",
			"he",
			"thought",
			"universe",
			"into",
			"existence"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Coyote[10]  This spider from African folklore tried to hoard all the world's knowledge in a pot, but dropped it out of annoyance at being bested by his son.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 8 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Native American trickster god stole fire from the gods by dancing around it with reeds on his head, and running away before the gods stopped laughing.",
		"answers": [
			"Coyote",
			"10",
			"This",
			"spider",
			"from",
			"African",
			"folklore",
			"tried",
			"to",
			"hoard",
			"all",
			"world's",
			"knowledge",
			"in",
			"pot",
			"but",
			"dropped",
			"out",
			"annoyance",
			"at",
			"being",
			"bested",
			"by",
			"his",
			"son"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hades or Plouton [do not accept \"Pluto\"][10]  This Norse goddess is the daughter of Loki, and the world she rules bears her name. She is often described as half-flesh and half-black or rot, and with a generally melancholy air.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 14 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Greek god of the dead is also known as \"The Rich One,\" and famously captured Demeter's daughter, Persephone, to be his wife. Hercules asked this god for his dog, Cerberus.",
		"answers": [
			"Hades",
			"Plouton"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Andromache[10]  This husband of Andromache led the Trojans against the Greeks. He dueled Ajax and killed Patroclus before he was chased around the walls of Troy, killed, and had his body mistreated.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this mother of Astyanax and wife of the greatest Trojan hero. She was taken as Neoptolemus's concubine during the Trojan War but later married Helenus.",
		"answers": [
			"Andromache",
			"10",
			"This",
			"husband",
			"led",
			"Trojans",
			"against",
			"Greeks",
			"He",
			"dueled",
			"Ajax",
			"and",
			"killed",
			"Patroclus",
			"he",
			"was",
			"chased",
			"around",
			"walls",
			"Troy",
			"had",
			"his",
			"body",
			"mistreated"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bellerophon[10]  Bellerophon used a golden bridle to tame this magical winged horse with whom he killed the Chimera. he and his brother Chrysaor sprung from the decapitated corpse of Medusa.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 11 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this mythological hero who slew his most famous enemy with a lump of lead attached to a spear. This man lived on the Plains of Aleion after being blinded and crippled by a gadfly sent by Zeus.",
		"answers": [
			"Bellerophon",
			"10",
			"used",
			"golden",
			"bridle",
			"to",
			"tame",
			"this",
			"magical",
			"winged",
			"horse",
			"with",
			"whom",
			"he",
			"killed",
			"Chimera",
			"and",
			"his",
			"brother",
			"Chrysaor",
			"sprung",
			"from",
			"decapitated",
			"corpse",
			"Medusa"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ymir [accept Aurgelmir, Brimir, or Blainn][10]  When Ymir got too huge and powerful, Vili, Ve, and this god killed him. He is the husband of Frigg and ruler of the Aesir.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 19 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This giant was the first being, created when the fire of Muspelheim and the ice of Niflheim formed a water droplet. A race of frost giants descended from him.",
		"answers": [
			"Ymir",
			"Aurgelmir",
			"Brimir",
			"Blainn",
			"10",
			"When",
			"got",
			"too",
			"huge",
			"and",
			"powerful",
			"Vili",
			"Ve",
			"this",
			"god",
			"killed",
			"him",
			"He",
			"husband",
			"Frigg",
			"ruler",
			"Aesir"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tiamat[10]  This god used a whole slew of weapons, including a giant net, a flood-storm, and a whole bunch of winds, to kill Tiamat. After he succeeded, he was made the chief Babylonian god and was given 50 names.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round09.docx | 10 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this massive dragon in Babylonian myth, the primordial personification of chaos and the ocean. After her defeat, her body was split in two and used to form the world.",
		"answers": [
			"Tiamat",
			"10",
			"This",
			"god",
			"used",
			"whole",
			"slew",
			"weapons",
			"including",
			"giant",
			"net",
			"flood-storm",
			"and",
			"bunch",
			"winds",
			"to",
			"kill",
			"After",
			"he",
			"succeeded",
			"was",
			"made",
			"chief",
			"Babylonian",
			"given",
			"50",
			"names"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Priam[10]  This princess was the daughter of Priam and Hecuba. She had the gift of foresight but was cursed by Apollo so that nobody would listen to her predictions.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man was the king of Troy at the time of the Iliad. This father of Hector was killed by Achilles's son.",
		"answers": [
			"Priam",
			"10",
			"This",
			"princess",
			"was",
			"daughter",
			"and",
			"Hecuba",
			"She",
			"had",
			"gift",
			"foresight",
			"but",
			"cursed",
			"by",
			"Apollo",
			"so",
			"that",
			"nobody",
			"would",
			"listen",
			"to",
			"her",
			"predictions"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Galatea[10]  This extremely ugly satyr was the god of nature. His flute was made from reeds, which the nymph Syrinx changed into after he chased her.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 13 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Pygmalion fell in love with this creation of his, a sculpture of a woman. He prayed to Venus, who turned this woman from ivory to flesh.",
		"answers": [
			"Galatea",
			"10",
			"This",
			"extremely",
			"ugly",
			"satyr",
			"was",
			"god",
			"nature",
			"His",
			"flute",
			"made",
			"from",
			"reeds",
			"which",
			"nymph",
			"Syrinx",
			"changed",
			"into",
			"after",
			"he",
			"chased",
			"her"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rama[10]  Rama's main enemy was this demon king of Lanka who had ten heads and performed immense penances to Brahma and Shiva to gain power. He stored the nectar of immortality in his navel, making him effectively invincible.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 5 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this self-exiled king of Kosala, a man with blue skin who wielded the bow. He is featured in a namesake epic.",
		"answers": [
			"Rama",
			"10",
			"Rama's",
			"main",
			"enemy",
			"was",
			"this",
			"demon",
			"king",
			"Lanka",
			"who",
			"had",
			"ten",
			"heads",
			"and",
			"performed",
			"immense",
			"penances",
			"to",
			"Brahma",
			"Shiva",
			"gain",
			"power",
			"He",
			"stored",
			"nectar",
			"immortality",
			"in",
			"his",
			"navel",
			"making",
			"him",
			"effectively",
			"invincible"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mayans[10]  Translated by Francisco Ximenez, the title of this four-part work means \"Book of the People.\" It recounts three attempts at creating humans, and the tale of the first four men, their wives, and the First Dawn.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 11 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  These Mesomaerican people believed the god Itzamna brought them writing and the calendar system, which includes the 260-day Tzolkin count and the Long Count, which ended in December 2012.",
		"answers": [
			"Mayans",
			"10",
			"Translated",
			"by",
			"Francisco",
			"Ximenez",
			"title",
			"this",
			"four-part",
			"work",
			"means",
			"Book",
			"People",
			"It",
			"recounts",
			"three",
			"attempts",
			"at",
			"creating",
			"humans",
			"and",
			"tale",
			"first",
			"four",
			"men",
			"their",
			"wives",
			"First",
			"Dawn"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Krishna[10]  Krishna is an avatar of this \"Preserver\" of the Hindu Trimurti. His other avatars include Rama and the fish Matsya, while his final avatar Kalki is yet to come.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this blue-skinned figure, a son of Devaki who served as the charioteer of Prince Arjuna. The dialogue between him and Arjuna makes up most of the Bhagavad Gita.",
		"answers": [
			"Krishna",
			"10",
			"an",
			"avatar",
			"this",
			"Preserver",
			"Hindu",
			"Trimurti",
			"His",
			"other",
			"avatars",
			"include",
			"Rama",
			"and",
			"fish",
			"Matsya",
			"while",
			"his",
			"final",
			"Kalki",
			"yet",
			"to",
			"come"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gigantomachy (accept equivalents like Giant War)[10]  The Giants were sons of this personification of the Earth. With Ouranos, she was the mother of the Titans, Hekatonkheires, and Cyclopes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this rebellion against the Olympian gods, which was quelled with the help of Heracles. Some participants in it could not be killed unless they were taken out of their homeland of Pallene.",
		"answers": [
			"Gigantomachy",
			"equivalents",
			"Giant",
			"War",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Giants",
			"were",
			"sons",
			"this",
			"personification",
			"Earth",
			"With",
			"Ouranos",
			"she",
			"was",
			"mother",
			"Titans",
			"Hekatonkheires",
			"and",
			"Cyclopes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Odin (accept Wotan or Woden)[10]  With his brothers Vili and Ve, Odin killed this primordial giant to build the world. He was formed in Ginnungagap by the union of fire and ice.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 13 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this owner of the ravens Hugin and Munin who was the chief Norse deity and father of the Aesir.",
		"answers": [
			"Odin",
			"Wotan",
			"Woden",
			"10",
			"With",
			"his",
			"brothers",
			"Vili",
			"and",
			"Ve",
			"killed",
			"this",
			"primordial",
			"giant",
			"to",
			"build",
			"world",
			"He",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"in",
			"Ginnungagap",
			"by",
			"union",
			"fire",
			"ice"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ahuramazda (or Ohrmazd)[10]  Ahuramazda and Angra Mainyu are the two central gods of this Persian religion, the chief text of which is the Avesta.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 5 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this \"good god\" who is rivals with Angra Mainyu in a dualistic Persian religion.",
		"answers": [
			"Ahuramazda",
			"Ohrmazd",
			"10",
			"and",
			"Angra",
			"Mainyu",
			"are",
			"two",
			"central",
			"gods",
			"this",
			"Persian",
			"religion",
			"chief",
			"text",
			"which",
			"Avesta"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ixion[10]  Nephele married King Athamas, but he later got rid of her in favor of Ino, a daughter of this man. This figure was the husband  of Harmonia and founder of Thebes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 18 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this king of the Lapiths and father of Pirithous, who was later chained to a fiery wheel in Hades because he could not contain his lust for Hera. With the cloud nymph Nephele, he was the father of the Centaurs.",
		"answers": [
			"Ixion",
			"10",
			"Nephele",
			"married",
			"King",
			"Athamas",
			"but",
			"he",
			"later",
			"got",
			"rid",
			"her",
			"in",
			"favor",
			"Ino",
			"daughter",
			"this",
			"man",
			"This",
			"figure",
			"was",
			"husband",
			"Harmonia",
			"and",
			"founder",
			"Thebes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Beowulf[10]  This kami of storms and the sea slew the dragon Orochi and pulled the sword Kusanagi from its tail. He was born with his siblings, the goddess of the Sun and the god of the Moon,  from Izanagi's face.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This owner of the sword Hrunting and hero of a namesake Anglo-Saxon epic discovered that the weapon failed to work against Grendel's Mother, forcing him to discard it.",
		"answers": [
			"Beowulf",
			"10",
			"This",
			"kami",
			"storms",
			"and",
			"sea",
			"slew",
			"dragon",
			"Orochi",
			"pulled",
			"sword",
			"Kusanagi",
			"from",
			"its",
			"tail",
			"He",
			"was",
			"born",
			"with",
			"his",
			"siblings",
			"goddess",
			"Sun",
			"god",
			"Moon",
			"Izanagi's",
			"face"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Romulus[10]  Romulus ordered a kidnapping of this tribe's women to provide wives for the inhabitants of Rome. In retaliation, their king Titus Tatius attacked Rome, only to be stopped when the women threw themselves before the troops.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 4 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This man founded Rome with his brother Remus, but later killed him for criticizing the height of the city's walls.",
		"answers": [
			"Romulus",
			"10",
			"ordered",
			"kidnapping",
			"this",
			"tribe's",
			"women",
			"to",
			"provide",
			"wives",
			"for",
			"inhabitants",
			"Rome",
			"In",
			"retaliation",
			"their",
			"king",
			"Titus",
			"Tatius",
			"attacked",
			"only",
			"be",
			"stopped",
			"when",
			"threw",
			"themselves",
			"troops"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cattle Raid of Cooley (or Tain Bo Cuailnge; accept any answer indicating a theft of cattle from Cooley)[10]  The Cattle Raid of Cooley is recorded in the Ulster Cycle of this country's mythology. Famous figures in this country's mythology include Deirdre of the Sorrows and Finn MacCool.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 3 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this event in which the armies of Queen Medb attacked Ulster in an attempt to steal a valuable bull.",
		"answers": [
			"Cattle",
			"Raid",
			"Cooley",
			"Tain",
			"Bo",
			"Cuailnge",
			"answer",
			"indicating",
			"theft",
			"cattle",
			"from",
			"10",
			"The",
			"recorded",
			"in",
			"Ulster",
			"Cycle",
			"this",
			"country's",
			"mythology",
			"Famous",
			"figures",
			"include",
			"Deirdre",
			"Sorrows",
			"and",
			"Finn",
			"MacCool"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "oracles (do not accept or prompt on \"prophets\")[10]  Apollo established the Oracle of Delphi after killing this serpent, which had been pursuing his mother Leto. The predecessor to the Olympic Games were held to commemorate the killing of this creature.",
		"prompts": [
			"prophets",
			"10",
			"Apollo",
			"established",
			"Oracle",
			"Delphi",
			"after",
			"killing",
			"this",
			"serpent",
			"which",
			"had",
			"been",
			"pursuing",
			"his",
			"mother",
			"Leto",
			"The",
			"predecessor",
			"to",
			"Olympic",
			"Games",
			"were",
			"held",
			"to",
			"commemorate",
			"killing",
			"this",
			"creature"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 1 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name these places or people through which the gods communicated when consulted. The most famous example of these was the one at Delphi dedicated to Apollo.",
		"answers": [
			"oracles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Huitzilopochtli [accept Uitzilopochtli, prompt on some combination of \"Hummingbird\" and \"left\"][10]  Huitzilopochtli, whose Nahuatl name meant \"hummingbird on the left\", was the war god of these Mesoamerican people. Ometeotl was their creator god, and Tezcatlipoca served as their sorcerer.",
		"prompts": [
			"some",
			"combination",
			"Hummingbird",
			"and",
			"left",
			"10",
			"Huitzilopochtli",
			"whose",
			"Nahuatl",
			"name",
			"meant",
			"hummingbird",
			"left",
			"was",
			"war",
			"god",
			"these",
			"Mesoamerican",
			"people",
			"Ometeotl",
			"was",
			"their",
			"creator",
			"god",
			"and",
			"Tezcatlipoca",
			"served",
			"as",
			"their",
			"sorcerer"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this hummingbird god of war who required human sacrifices every 52 years. His mother was impregnated by a ball of feathers, leading to his birth.",
		"answers": [
			"Huitzilopochtli",
			"Uitzilopochtli"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Troy (or Ilium, or Ilion, or Ilios)[10]  This king ruled Troy at the time of the Trojan War and was the father of Hector. He was killed by Neoptolemus during the sack of Troy, after which his wife Hecuba was sold as a slave to Odysseus.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 5 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this city in Asia Minor that was conquered and destroyed by the Greeks in a war chronicled by a Homeric epic. The army of this city was led by Hector.",
		"answers": [
			"Troy",
			"Ilium",
			"Ilion",
			"Ilios",
			"10",
			"This",
			"king",
			"ruled",
			"at",
			"time",
			"Trojan",
			"War",
			"and",
			"was",
			"father",
			"Hector",
			"He",
			"killed",
			"by",
			"Neoptolemus",
			"during",
			"sack",
			"after",
			"which",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"Hecuba",
			"sold",
			"as",
			"slave",
			"to",
			"Odysseus"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Coltrane[10]  Coltrane played the tenor variety of this instrument, the alto and soprano types of which were played by Charlie Parker and Kenny G.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this jazz musician, who also recorded Giant Steps and My Favorite Things. Ira Gitler famously described his music as \"sheets of sound.\"",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Coltrane",
			"10",
			"played",
			"tenor",
			"variety",
			"this",
			"instrument",
			"alto",
			"and",
			"soprano",
			"types",
			"which",
			"were",
			"by",
			"Charlie",
			"Parker",
			"Kenny",
			"G"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Geb (accept Gebeb, Keb, or Kebeb)[10]  Due to a restriction put in place by Ra, Geb's wife Nut could not give birth on all 360 days of the year, so this divine scribe and god of wisdom gambled with Khonsu for 5 extra days in the year during which Nut could give birth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 16 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this god of the earth and father of Osiris, Set, Isis, and Nepthys. This son of Shu and Tefnut married his sky-goddess sister.",
		"answers": [
			"Geb",
			"Gebeb",
			"Keb",
			"Kebeb",
			"10",
			"Due",
			"to",
			"restriction",
			"put",
			"in",
			"place",
			"by",
			"Ra",
			"Geb's",
			"wife",
			"Nut",
			"could"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Aethiopia[10]  This man's son was the Aethiopian prince Memnon. Priam bribed this lover of Eos with a golden grapevine, and he turned into a cicada after receiving immortality without eternal youth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 3 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this nebulously defined African region where the Olympians would often go and feast. It shares its name with a country whose former ruler, Haile Selassie, is venerated by Rastafarians.",
		"answers": [
			"Aethiopia",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man's",
			"son",
			"was",
			"Aethiopian",
			"prince",
			"Memnon",
			"Priam",
			"bribed",
			"this",
			"lover",
			"Eos",
			"with",
			"golden",
			"grapevine",
			"and",
			"he",
			"turned",
			"into",
			"cicada",
			"after",
			"receiving",
			"immortality",
			"without",
			"eternal",
			"youth"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "spiders[10]  This Native American trickster god is the brother of Wolf and created humanity by kicking a ball of dirt.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 15 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  One of these animals, the African trickster god Anansi, managed to get ahold of all the stories in the world. In Greek mythology, Arachne was turned into one of these after losing a weaving contest.",
		"answers": [
			"spiders",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Native",
			"American",
			"trickster",
			"god",
			"brother",
			"Wolf",
			"and",
			"created",
			"humanity",
			"by",
			"kicking",
			"ball",
			"dirt"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Theseus[10]  Theseus killed the Minotaur with the help of this daughter of Minos, who gave him some thread so that he could find a way out of the Labyrinth. However, Theseus abandoned her on Naxos while on the way back to Athens.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 17 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this son of Aegeus, a Greek hero who slew the Minotaur.",
		"answers": [
			"Theseus",
			"10",
			"killed"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "valkyries[10]  Actually, valkyries only carry half the valiant dead to Valhalla. The other half are selected by this Norse goddess of beauty and sent to a hall named Folkvangr.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 22 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Norse shieldmaidens who carried the valiant dead away to Valhalla.",
		"answers": [
			"valkyries",
			"10",
			"Actually",
			"only",
			"carry",
			"half",
			"valiant",
			"dead",
			"to",
			"Valhalla",
			"The",
			"other",
			"are",
			"selected",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Norse",
			"goddess",
			"beauty",
			"and",
			"sent",
			"hall",
			"named",
			"Folkvangr"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ra (or Atum-Ra, or Amun-Ra, or Ra-Horakhty; accept Re in place of \"Ra\"; prompt on Atum, Amun, or Horakhty)[10]  Amenhotep IV changed his name to honor this deity, the worship of whom replaced that of Ra and other traditional Egyptian gods. This god represented the solar disk.",
		"prompts": [
			"Atum",
			"Amun",
			"Horakhty",
			"10",
			"Amenhotep",
			"IV",
			"changed",
			"his",
			"name",
			"to",
			"honor",
			"this",
			"deity",
			"worship",
			"whom",
			"replaced",
			"that",
			"Ra",
			"and",
			"other",
			"traditional",
			"Egyptian",
			"gods",
			"This",
			"god",
			"represented",
			"solar",
			"disk"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 17 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Egyptian god of the sun was the grandfather of Osiris and Isis.",
		"answers": [
			"Ra",
			"Atum-Ra",
			"Amun-Ra",
			"Ra-Horakhty",
			"Re",
			"in",
			"place"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Epimetheus[10]  Unfortunately, Epimetheus didn't listen and accepted this woman as a bride. As a wedding present, she received a box that later released various evils and illnesses to humanity when she opened it.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 10 | Mythology |  | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this son of Iapetus whose name means \"afterthought\". He was warned by his wiser brother to never accept any gift from Zeus.",
		"answers": [
			"Epimetheus",
			"10",
			"Unfortunately",
			"didn't",
			"listen",
			"and",
			"accepted",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"as",
			"bride",
			"As",
			"wedding",
			"present",
			"she",
			"received",
			"box",
			"that",
			"later",
			"released",
			"various",
			"evils",
			"illnesses",
			"to",
			"humanity",
			"when",
			"opened"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigurd [or Siegfried; or Sifrid][10] Fafnir the dragon sat on a hoard of this substance, which King Midas turned things into with his accursed touch.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: After tasting the heart of the dragon Fafnir, this man learned to understand the language of birds. For 10 points  each: [10] Name this Germanic hero, a son of Sigmund who wrote through a circle of flames to rescue the maiden  Brynhild.",
		"answers": [
			"Sigurd",
			"Siegfried",
			"Sifrid",
			"10",
			"Fafnir",
			"dragon",
			"sat",
			"hoard",
			"this",
			"substance",
			"which",
			"King",
			"Midas",
			"turned",
			"things",
			"into",
			"with",
			"his",
			"accursed",
			"touch"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigurd [or Siegfried; or Sifrid][10] Fafnir the dragon sat on a hoard of this substance, which King Midas turned things into with his accursed touch.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: After tasting the heart of the dragon Fafnir, this man learned to understand the language of birds. For 10 points  each: [10] Name this Germanic hero, a son of Sigmund who wrote through a circle of flames to rescue the maiden  Brynhild.",
		"answers": [
			"Sigurd",
			"Siegfried",
			"Sifrid",
			"10",
			"Fafnir",
			"dragon",
			"sat",
			"hoard",
			"this",
			"substance",
			"which",
			"King",
			"Midas",
			"turned",
			"things",
			"into",
			"with",
			"his",
			"accursed",
			"touch"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lancelot[10] Lancelot was raised by this woman after the death of his father. In some stories, she trapped the smitten Merlin  in a tree after learning magic from him.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 6 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about King Arthur's Court, for 10 points each: [10] This Knight conducted an affair with Guinevere, but was banished after he sired Galahad with Elaine.",
		"answers": [
			"Lancelot",
			"10",
			"was",
			"raised",
			"by",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"after",
			"death",
			"his",
			"father",
			"In",
			"some",
			"stories",
			"she",
			"trapped",
			"smitten",
			"Merlin",
			"in",
			"tree",
			"learning",
			"magic",
			"from",
			"him"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Hesperides[10] This Titan was condemned to hold up the sky after the Titanomachy. Heracles had him collect golden apples  from the Hesperides, then tricked him into taking back his burden.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 19 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 19. [10] These nymphs of the evening tended their namesake garden and guarded the immortality-giving apples of a tree  belonging to Hera.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Hesperides",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Titan",
			"was",
			"condemned",
			"to",
			"hold",
			"up",
			"sky",
			"after",
			"Titanomachy",
			"Heracles",
			"had",
			"him",
			"collect",
			"golden",
			"apples",
			"from",
			"then",
			"tricked",
			"into",
			"taking",
			"back",
			"his",
			"burden"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vainamoinen[10] Vainamoinen sails away after Marjotta's son chides him for his sins at the end of this epic poem. Other  episodes involve Ilmarinen's Bride of Gold and Kullervo's misfortune.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 14 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Aino drowned herself rather than marry this bard. For 10 points each: [10] Name this rival of Joukahanien who tortured the Luotes out of Antero Vipunen. He also tried to woo the  Maiden of the North and tricked Ilmarinen into crafting the Sampo.",
		"answers": [
			"Vainamoinen",
			"10",
			"sails",
			"away",
			"after",
			"Marjotta's",
			"son",
			"chides",
			"him",
			"for",
			"his",
			"sins",
			"at",
			"end",
			"this",
			"epic",
			"poem",
			"Other",
			"episodes",
			"involve",
			"Ilmarinen's",
			"Bride",
			"Gold",
			"and",
			"Kullervo's",
			"misfortune"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ireland [accept Eire][10] This Irish hero fought the Fomorians in his travels, but is best known for going berserk and crushing the armies of Connacht under Queen Maeve during the Cattle Raid of Cooley.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 13 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This place was once invaded by the Fomorians, led by giants like Balor of the Evil Eye, as recorded in the Book of Invasions. For 10 points each: [10] Name this place where races like the Fir Bolg were displaced by the Tuatha de Danann. In real life this island was invaded by Oliver Cromwell, leading to the Siege of Drogheda.",
		"answers": [
			"Ireland",
			"Eire",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Irish",
			"hero",
			"fought",
			"Fomorians",
			"in",
			"his",
			"travels",
			"but",
			"best",
			"known",
			"for",
			"going",
			"berserk",
			"and",
			"crushing",
			"armies",
			"Connacht",
			"under",
			"Queen",
			"Maeve",
			"during",
			"Cattle",
			"Raid",
			"Cooley"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Arjuna[10] The Pandavas fought against their cousins, members of this lineage, led by patriarch Dhritarashtra and his son Duryodhana.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 5 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Agni gave a gift to this warrior, which he then used to slay his foe and half-brother, Karna. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this third of the Pandavas, sired by Indra, whose chariot was driven by Krishna at the Battle of Kurukshetra.",
		"answers": [
			"Arjuna",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Pandavas",
			"fought",
			"against",
			"their",
			"cousins",
			"members",
			"this",
			"lineage",
			"led",
			"by",
			"patriarch",
			"Dhritarashtra",
			"and",
			"his",
			"son",
			"Duryodhana"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Huitzilopochtli[10] Huitzilopochtli was the patron deity of this place, the capital city of the Nahua people, perhaps better known as the Aztecs.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 14 | Mythology | None | HS",
		"subject": "Mythology",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This deity, son of Coatlicue, led the Nahua people out of Aztlan and commanded them never to return. For 10 points each: [10]  Identify this deity of war and the sun, whose name translates as \"blue hummingbird of the left.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Huitzilopochtli",
			"10",
			"was",
			"patron",
			"deity",
			"this",
			"place",
			"capital",
			"city",
			"Nahua",
			"people",
			"perhaps",
			"better",
			"known",
			"as",
			"Aztecs"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "On Liberty[10] On Liberty was written by this British philosopher who also wrote Utilitarianism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 3 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this work, the author justifies despotism over barbarians to prepare them for democratic rule. [10] Name this 1859 essay in which the author argues for freedom of speech and other forms of the title concept and argues that the only reason the title concept should be limited is to prevent harm to others.",
		"answers": [
			"On",
			"Liberty",
			"10",
			"was",
			"written",
			"by",
			"this",
			"British",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"also",
			"wrote",
			"Utilitarianism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "games[10] In game theory, a dominant strategy for a player is one which is this type of response to all of his opponent's strategies.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 17 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: A zero-sum one of these occurs when the gains of one competitor are negated by the losses of others. [10] Name these hypothetical situations created by a namesake study of decision making. In these constructs, exemplified by the prisoner's dilemma, rational beings cooperate and compete with each other.",
		"answers": [
			"games",
			"10",
			"In",
			"game",
			"theory",
			"dominant",
			"strategy",
			"for",
			"player",
			"one",
			"which",
			"this",
			"type",
			"response",
			"to",
			"all",
			"his",
			"opponent's",
			"strategies"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "cruel and unusual punishment [accept equivalents like \"cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment\"; do not accept specific instances like \"torture\" or \"enhanced interrogation\"][10] In Furman v. Georgia, the Supreme Court declared that inconsistencies in this form of punishment make this cruel and unusual. In the United States, it is primarily conducted through lethal injection.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 3 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In Trop v. Dulles, Chief Justice Earl Warren wrote that this concept \"must draw its meaning from the evolving standards of decency that mark the progress of a maturing society.\" [10] Name this concept prohibited in the Eighth Amendment of the United States Constitution. This phrase may have first been used to describe the sentence of Titus Oates after the uncovering of the Popish Plot.",
		"answers": [
			"cruel",
			"and",
			"unusual",
			"punishment",
			"equivalents",
			"inhuman",
			"degrading",
			"treatment"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "suicide[10] Suicide was analyzed in a case study by this French sociologist, who helped develop sociology as a field with his The Rules of Sociological Method.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 9 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Albert Camus described it as the only philosophical question. [10] Name this act of killing oneself. One man studying it noted its increased prevalence among Protestant communities, as well as its decreased prevalence during times of war.",
		"answers": [
			"suicide",
			"10",
			"Suicide",
			"was",
			"analyzed",
			"in",
			"case",
			"study",
			"by",
			"this",
			"French",
			"sociologist",
			"who",
			"helped",
			"develop",
			"sociology",
			"as",
			"field",
			"with",
			"his",
			"The",
			"Rules",
			"Sociological",
			"Method"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Invisible Hand\"[10] This economist posited the idea of the \"invisible hand\" in his works The Theory of Moral Sentiments and The Wealth of Nations.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2014 | 2 | 1 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This concept argues that individual self-interest in the economy benefits society overall. For 10 points each: [10] Name this metaphor used by a Scottish economist to describe the self-regulation of a free market.",
		"answers": [
			"Invisible",
			"Hand",
			"10",
			"This",
			"economist",
			"posited",
			"idea",
			"invisible",
			"hand",
			"in",
			"his",
			"works",
			"The",
			"Theory",
			"Moral",
			"Sentiments",
			"and",
			"Wealth",
			"Nations"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "emotions[10] This first theory proposed to explain emotions describes how the mind receives the bodily response first and experiences emotion afterwards.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 8 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: According to one theory, the mind uses both the situation and the physical response to a stimulus to interpret these phenomena. For 10 points each:  [10] Identify these phenomena explained by the Schachter-Singer and Cannon-Bard theories, which include happiness, sadness, and fear. ",
		"answers": [
			"emotions",
			"10",
			"This",
			"first",
			"theory",
			"proposed",
			"to",
			"explain",
			"describes",
			"how",
			"mind",
			"receives",
			"bodily",
			"response",
			"and",
			"experiences",
			"emotion",
			"afterwards"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Art of War[10] The uncertainty of war is also described as part of a \"fascinating trinity\" in On War, a text on early 19th-century European warfare by this Prussian officer who served during the Napoleonic Wars.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer these questions about learning proper fighting strategy. [10] Name this book by Sun Tzu on tactics, strategy, and military organization. It contains sections on martial arts and terrain, and characterizes war as an information game involving deception and uncertainty. ",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Art",
			"War",
			"10",
			"uncertainty",
			"war",
			"also",
			"described",
			"as",
			"part",
			"fascinating",
			"trinity",
			"in",
			"On",
			"text",
			"early",
			"19th-century",
			"European",
			"warfare",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Prussian",
			"officer",
			"who",
			"served",
			"during",
			"Napoleonic",
			"Wars"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Emile Durkheim[10] This anxiety disorder is often comorbid with suicidality. Its symptoms include flashbacks, irritability, and hypervigilance. It occurs frequently among military personnel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 18 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name the following about the study of suicide.  [10] The first sociological study of suicide was conducted by this French author of Rules of the Sociological Method. He studied differences in suicide rates between Catholic and Protestant communities.",
		"answers": [
			"Emile",
			"Durkheim",
			"10",
			"This",
			"anxiety",
			"disorder",
			"often",
			"comorbid",
			"with",
			"suicidality",
			"Its",
			"symptoms",
			"include",
			"flashbacks",
			"irritability",
			"and",
			"hypervigilance",
			"It",
			"occurs",
			"frequently",
			"among",
			"military",
			"personnel"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gross domestic product or GDP [do not accept \"GNP\" or \"GDP per capita\"][10] This theory holds that currency exchange rates will approach the ratio of prices of identical goods and services in two countries. It can convert GDP between currencies to avoid discrepancies from fluctuating exchange rates.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 18 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about measures used to compare the economies of different countries. For 10 points each: [10] This term denotes the total market value of goods and services produced within a country.",
		"answers": [
			"gross",
			"domestic",
			"product",
			"GDP"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "object permanence[10] This psychologist first studied object permanence in infants, and believed it originated in the sensorimotor stage of his theory of cognitive development.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 10 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The incompleteness of this understanding can result in an a-not-b error. For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept, the continued existence of items that can no longer be seen or otherwise observed. The lack of it may be why some babies are startled by the game of peek-a-boo.",
		"answers": [
			"object",
			"permanence",
			"10",
			"This",
			"psychologist",
			"first",
			"studied",
			"in",
			"infants",
			"and",
			"believed",
			"originated",
			"sensorimotor",
			"stage",
			"his",
			"theory",
			"cognitive",
			"development"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Swahili language[10] In written characters, many African languages such as Xhosa use a character symbolized by an exclamation point. Those sounds are pronounced by making this noise.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 20 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about African languages, for 10 points each: [10] This language mostly prominent today in East Africa developed as a result of mixing Bantu, Arabic, and some European languages. In this language, \"hakuna matata\" means no worries, and is generally a wonderful phrase.",
		"answers": [
			"Swahili",
			"language",
			"10",
			"In",
			"written",
			"characters",
			"many",
			"African",
			"languages",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Xhosa",
			"use",
			"character",
			"symbolized",
			"by",
			"an",
			"exclamation",
			"point",
			"Those",
			"sounds",
			"are",
			"pronounced",
			"making",
			"this",
			"noise"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bystander Effect[10] The murder of this New York resident first brought the bystander effect to the attention of researchers, although many details of her death were inaccurately reported.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One experiment investigating this effect involved subjects conversing with a stranger over an intercom, who then proceeded to fake an epileptic seizure. For 10 points each: [10] Name this social phenomenon, in which the presence of greater numbers of people decreases the probability of individuals giving aid to a potential victim.",
		"answers": [
			"Bystander",
			"Effect",
			"10",
			"The",
			"murder",
			"this",
			"New",
			"York",
			"resident",
			"first",
			"brought",
			"bystander",
			"effect",
			"to",
			"attention",
			"researchers",
			"although",
			"many",
			"details",
			"her",
			"death",
			"were",
			"inaccurately",
			"reported"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rats[10] B. F. Skinner trained these animals to play ping pong, and in Skinner's Box, they pecked at a device to release food. Skinner also devised a plan using these birds to guide missiles.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 12 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some animals used in psychological studies and experiments, for 10 points each: [10] John Watson conditioned Little Albert to fear a white one of these rodents. Laboratory types of these rodents generally traverse mazes, and they are slightly larger than mice.",
		"answers": [
			"Rats",
			"10",
			"B",
			"F",
			"Skinner",
			"trained",
			"these",
			"animals",
			"to",
			"play",
			"ping",
			"pong",
			"and",
			"in",
			"Skinner's",
			"Box",
			"they",
			"pecked",
			"at",
			"device",
			"release",
			"food",
			"also",
			"devised",
			"plan",
			"using",
			"birds",
			"guide",
			"missiles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Prisoner's Dilemma[10] Both players choosing to defect is an example of this concept, in which players know the strategies of others and make the best decision for themselves with that knowledge.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 17 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this scenario, two players are given a choice between cooperating and defecting. For 10 points each: [10] Name this situation in game theory in which defecting is the best decision, even though mutual cooperation would lead to the optimal outcome.",
		"answers": [
			"Prisoner's",
			"Dilemma",
			"10",
			"Both",
			"players",
			"choosing",
			"to",
			"defect",
			"an",
			"example",
			"this",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"which",
			"know",
			"strategies",
			"others",
			"and",
			"make",
			"best",
			"decision",
			"for",
			"themselves",
			"with",
			"that",
			"knowledge"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Taxation [accept word forms such as \"taxes\"][10] This curve plots taxation against government revenue, and can be used to find the optimal rate to maximize revenue.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 4 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Supply-side economics argues for a lower rate for this economic institution. For 10 points each: [10] Name this method used by the government to raise revenue from sales, property, income, wealth, and payrolls, among others.",
		"answers": [
			"Taxation",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"such",
			"as",
			"taxes",
			"10",
			"This",
			"curve",
			"plots",
			"taxation",
			"against",
			"government",
			"revenue",
			"and",
			"can",
			"be",
			"used",
			"to",
			"find",
			"optimal",
			"rate",
			"maximize"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stanford Prison Experiment[10] Following the Stanford Prison Experiment, Zimbardo published this book, which examines how good people can turn evil.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 16 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One subject in this experiment became known as \"John Wayne\" for his cruelty. For 10 points each: [10] Name this psychological experiment conducted by Philip Zimbardo, in which students were chosen to be either inmates or guards.",
		"answers": [
			"Stanford",
			"Prison",
			"Experiment",
			"10",
			"Following",
			"Zimbardo",
			"published",
			"this",
			"book",
			"which",
			"examines",
			"how",
			"good",
			"people",
			"can",
			"turn",
			"evil"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Maynard Keynes[10] This major work by Keynes was published during the Great Depression, and lays out the framework of his major economic ideas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 1 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He advocated raising taxes to pay for World War II, rather than increased deficit spending, and notably opposed the gold standard. For 10 points each: [10] Name this British economist, whose namesake school of thought holds that aggregate demand influences economic output.",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Maynard",
			"Keynes",
			"10",
			"This",
			"major",
			"work",
			"by",
			"was",
			"published",
			"during",
			"Great",
			"Depression",
			"and",
			"lays",
			"out",
			"framework",
			"his",
			"economic",
			"ideas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "doll[10] This psychologist conducted the Bobo doll experiment, and repeated it with variations in which the children watch films and cartoons of violence.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This type of object was used in an experiment in which an adult yelled phrases like \"Sock him\" and \"Kick him.\" For 10 points each: [10] A Bobo type of what toy was repeatedly hit by an adult as a child watched in an experiment studying observational learning?",
		"answers": [
			"doll",
			"10",
			"This",
			"psychologist",
			"conducted",
			"Bobo",
			"experiment",
			"and",
			"repeated",
			"with",
			"variations",
			"in",
			"which",
			"children",
			"watch",
			"films",
			"cartoons",
			"violence"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Franz Boas[10] Boas founded the anthropology program at this Ivy League university. Located in New York City, this university subsequently held the country's leading anthropology program.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man taught people like Margaret Mead and Zora Neale Hurston. For 10 points each: [10] Name this German-American \"Father of Anthropology\" who argued against racist beliefs in his The Mind of Primitive Man.",
		"answers": [
			"Franz",
			"Boas",
			"10",
			"founded",
			"anthropology",
			"program",
			"at",
			"this",
			"Ivy",
			"League",
			"university",
			"Located",
			"in",
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"subsequently",
			"held",
			"country's",
			"leading"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "bystander effect[10] The bystander effect is sometimes also named for this woman who was murdered while returning to her Queens home. The media account of 38 witnesses who failed to help may have been exaggerated.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 1 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This effect was demonstrated in China in 2011 after the two year old Wang Yue was hit by a van and truck in the street yet ignored by 18 people. For 10 points: [10] Name this effect in which the title people fail to give help in an emergency. As the number of people present increases its strength also increases.",
		"answers": [
			"bystander",
			"effect",
			"10",
			"The",
			"sometimes",
			"also",
			"named",
			"for",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"who",
			"was",
			"murdered",
			"while",
			"returning",
			"to",
			"her",
			"Queens",
			"home",
			"media",
			"account",
			"38",
			"witnesses",
			"failed",
			"help",
			"may",
			"have",
			"been",
			"exaggerated"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "capital [10] The Cobb-Douglas function estimates the output of these entities as a function of capital and labor using two exponents. Modeled as profit maximizers, these producers' optimization concerns determine the supply curve.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 18 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Union leaders and socialists often described this term as being at odds with labor, although they were generally referring to its owners. For 10 points each:  [10] Give this term from economics, which describes the machinery and tools used to produce goods more efficiently. Its 'human' variety is acquired through education and training. ",
		"answers": [
			"capital",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Cobb-Douglas",
			"function",
			"estimates",
			"output",
			"these",
			"entities",
			"as",
			"and",
			"labor",
			"using",
			"two",
			"exponents",
			"Modeled",
			"profit",
			"maximizers",
			"producers'",
			"optimization",
			"concerns",
			"determine",
			"supply",
			"curve"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "coinage or coins[10] Along with banknotes, coins are labeled under this term, which should not be confused with another term that also includes the balances in bank checking and saving accounts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 10 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Creating a special platinum one of these objects was suggested to avoid hitting the debt ceiling. For 10 points each: [10] Name these objects of value which in America usually have denominations under a dollar. Quarters and dimes are examples.",
		"answers": [
			"coinage",
			"coins",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Social Darwinism (accept word forms)[10] Darwin was influenced by the 1798 An Essay on the Principle of Population by this man, which contrasted the geometric growth of population and the arithmetic growth of food supply. The epithet 'dismal science' for economics was coined based on a work by this man.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This idea, loosely based on evolutionary principles, was first applied to the economic world by Joseph Fisher, and was popularized by Richard Hofstadter. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this concept, defined by the phrase \"survival of the fittest\". ",
		"answers": [
			"Social",
			"Darwinism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"Darwin",
			"was",
			"influenced",
			"by",
			"1798",
			"An",
			"Essay",
			"Principle",
			"Population",
			"this",
			"man",
			"which",
			"contrasted",
			"geometric",
			"growth",
			"population",
			"and",
			"arithmetic",
			"food",
			"supply",
			"The",
			"epithet",
			"'dismal",
			"science'",
			"for",
			"economics",
			"coined",
			"based",
			"work"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "monopoly (accept word forms)[10] The reverse of the monopoly is this structure characterized by a single buyer and many sellers. Government contracts are an example.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 2 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some different economic markets, for 10 points each: [10] Competition is diminished in this type of market in which a single seller dominates the market.",
		"answers": [
			"monopoly",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"The",
			"reverse",
			"this",
			"structure",
			"characterized",
			"by",
			"single",
			"buyer",
			"and",
			"many",
			"sellers",
			"Government",
			"contracts",
			"are",
			"an",
			"example"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "monopoly (accept word forms)[10] The reverse of the monopoly is this structure characterized by a single buyer and many sellers. Government contracts are an example.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 2 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some different economic markets, for 10 points each: [10] Competition is diminished in this type of market in which a single seller dominates the market.",
		"answers": [
			"monopoly",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"The",
			"reverse",
			"this",
			"structure",
			"characterized",
			"by",
			"single",
			"buyer",
			"and",
			"many",
			"sellers",
			"Government",
			"contracts",
			"are",
			"an",
			"example"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "memory[10] Many psychoanalysts have proposed that humans perform this action, in which painful memories are submerged in the subconscious.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Elizabeth Loftus showed that this process can be tricked and manipulated. For 10 points each: [10] Name this human ability in which information is stored, retrieved, and recalled. The short term form is often called its \"working\" form.",
		"answers": [
			"memory",
			"10",
			"Many",
			"psychoanalysts",
			"have",
			"proposed",
			"that",
			"humans",
			"perform",
			"this",
			"action",
			"in",
			"which",
			"painful",
			"memories",
			"are",
			"submerged",
			"subconscious"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Milton Friedman [10] This man drew up a plan for Bolivia fiscal reform in 1985. He has argued global poverty can be eliminated through foreign aid in works such as The End of Poverty and Common Wealth.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 2 | 10 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  Name this economists and economic policies who influenced Latin America, for 10 points each:  [10] This man taught the \"Money and Banking Workshop\" to Chilean economists that became influential in Augusto Pinochet's government. This Chicago economist promoted the free market in books like Capitalism and Freedom and the TV program Free to Choose. ",
		"answers": [
			"Milton",
			"Friedman",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"drew",
			"up",
			"plan",
			"for",
			"Bolivia",
			"fiscal",
			"reform",
			"in",
			"1985",
			"He",
			"has",
			"argued",
			"global",
			"poverty",
			"can",
			"be",
			"eliminated",
			"through",
			"foreign",
			"aid",
			"works",
			"such",
			"as",
			"The",
			"End",
			"Poverty",
			"and",
			"Common",
			"Wealth"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "economic rent[10]  This author of An Inquiry Into the Nature and Progress of Rent pointed out the difference between arithmetically growing resources and exponentially increasing population.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 3 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This concept describes the cost of buying into producing a certain good. Examples include the cost of joining a medieval guild, government royalties, or patent and license costs.",
		"answers": [
			"economic",
			"rent",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"An",
			"Inquiry",
			"Into",
			"Nature",
			"and",
			"Progress",
			"Rent",
			"pointed",
			"out",
			"difference",
			"between",
			"arithmetically",
			"growing",
			"resources",
			"exponentially",
			"increasing",
			"population"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sigmund Freud [or Sigismund Schlomo Freud][10]  Freud proposed that fixations with this second stage in psychosexual development would cause either a destructive and messy personality or a rigid and compulsive personality.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 6 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This psychologist postulated the existence of the mind as an id, ego, and superego in his Beyond the Pleasure Principle.",
		"answers": [
			"Sigmund",
			"Freud",
			"Sigismund",
			"Schlomo",
			"10",
			"proposed",
			"that",
			"fixations",
			"with",
			"this",
			"second",
			"stage",
			"in",
			"psychosexual",
			"development",
			"would",
			"cause",
			"destructive",
			"and",
			"messy",
			"personality",
			"rigid",
			"compulsive"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "artificial intelligence [accept AI or machine intelligence][10]  One method of assessing AI is this test, which an AI can pass if their behavior is indistinguishable from that of a human.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 10 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this concept that refers to a machine's ability to reason, plan, learn, and emulate other aspects of human cognition.",
		"answers": [
			"artificial",
			"intelligence",
			"AI",
			"machine",
			"10",
			"One",
			"method",
			"assessing",
			"this",
			"test",
			"which",
			"an",
			"can",
			"pass",
			"if",
			"their",
			"behavior",
			"indistinguishable",
			"from",
			"that",
			"human"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "magic[10]  This anthropologist suggested that societies first believed in magic, before progressing to religion and science, in his tome of comparative mythology, The Golden Bough.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 20 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this concept which, along with \"Coral Gardens,\" titles a Malinowski book which analyzes agricultural practices of Trobriand Islanders. In \"A General Theory of\" this concept, Mauss contrasts it with religion.",
		"answers": [
			"magic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"anthropologist",
			"suggested",
			"that",
			"societies",
			"first",
			"believed",
			"in",
			"progressing",
			"to",
			"religion",
			"and",
			"science",
			"his",
			"tome",
			"comparative",
			"mythology",
			"The",
			"Golden",
			"Bough"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Souls of Black Folk[10]  The Souls of Black Folk is a seminal work in sociology by this editor of The Crisis. A rival of Booker T. Washington, he introduced the idea of the \"talented tenth,\" and founded the Niagara movement.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 11 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this sociological work, a collection of essays on African-American identity. It argues that the happy black slave is a flawed image created by whites, and describes a \"veil\" between black and white perspectives.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Souls",
			"Black",
			"Folk",
			"10",
			"seminal",
			"work",
			"in",
			"sociology",
			"by",
			"this",
			"editor",
			"Crisis",
			"A",
			"rival",
			"Booker",
			"T",
			"Washington",
			"he",
			"introduced",
			"idea",
			"talented",
			"tenth",
			"and",
			"founded",
			"Niagara",
			"movement"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "psychoanalysis[10]  Unconditional positive regard is a trait of a therapist who uses person-centered therapy, a technique developed by this humanistic psychologist. He is the author of On Becoming a Person.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 17 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This approach emphasizes the effect of unconscious factors and childhood experiences on current behaviors. Developers of this approach include Sigmund Freud and Jacques Lacan.",
		"answers": [
			"psychoanalysis",
			"10",
			"Unconditional",
			"positive",
			"regard",
			"trait",
			"therapist",
			"who",
			"uses",
			"person-centered",
			"therapy",
			"technique",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"this",
			"humanistic",
			"psychologist",
			"He",
			"author",
			"On",
			"Becoming",
			"Person"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "depression [or major depressive disorder][10]  Zoloft treats depression by selectively inhibiting the reuptake of this neurotransmitter. Derived from tryptophan, it has also been linked to schizophrenia and OCD.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 16 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This disorder alternates with mania in bipolar disorder. Its symptoms include social withdrawal, appetite and sleep changes, fatigue, and persistent disinterest or general sadness.",
		"answers": [
			"depression",
			"major",
			"depressive",
			"disorder",
			"10",
			"Zoloft",
			"treats",
			"by",
			"selectively",
			"inhibiting",
			"reuptake",
			"this",
			"neurotransmitter",
			"Derived",
			"from",
			"tryptophan",
			"has",
			"also",
			"been",
			"linked",
			"to",
			"schizophrenia",
			"and",
			"OCD"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stanford prison experiment[10]  This psychology professor conducted the Stanford prison experiment and wrote The Time Paradox.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round09.docx | 15 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this experiment was intended to show the effects of authority, but was aborted six days after its inception after guards began to physically and psychologically abuse other participants.",
		"answers": [
			"Stanford",
			"prison",
			"experiment",
			"10",
			"This",
			"psychology",
			"professor",
			"conducted",
			"and",
			"wrote",
			"The",
			"Time",
			"Paradox"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "trolley problem[10]  As a form of consequentialism, this ethical theory would have the agent flip the switch to maximize the net happiness for the greatest number.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 3 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this thought experiment proposed by Philippa Foot which asks whether it is ethical to flip a track switch to kill one man instead of five.",
		"answers": [
			"trolley",
			"problem",
			"10",
			"As",
			"form",
			"consequentialism",
			"this",
			"ethical",
			"theory",
			"would",
			"have",
			"agent",
			"flip",
			"switch",
			"to",
			"maximize",
			"net",
			"happiness",
			"for",
			"greatest",
			"number"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gestaltism [or Gestalt theory][10]  This theory that emerged from Gestalt theory holds that there exist two of its namesake entities in memory, verbatim and gist. It also attempts to explain risky decision making.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 9 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This theory claims that the whole is greater than its parts. Central to this theory is the law of pragnanz which claims that we try to find order and regularity in our sensations.",
		"answers": [
			"Gestaltism",
			"Gestalt",
			"theory",
			"10",
			"This",
			"that",
			"emerged",
			"from",
			"holds",
			"there",
			"exist",
			"two",
			"its",
			"namesake",
			"entities",
			"in",
			"memory",
			"verbatim",
			"and",
			"gist",
			"It",
			"also",
			"attempts",
			"to",
			"explain",
			"risky",
			"decision",
			"making"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gender[10]  This writer tackled \"the problem that has no name\" and, in The Feminine Mystique, described the title concept as the illusion that women were fulfilled through marriage and housework.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 15 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this psychological concept that refers to characteristics and roles associated with sex. Unlike sex, which is usually considered biologically determined, this concept can be self-determined.",
		"answers": [
			"gender",
			"10",
			"This",
			"writer",
			"tackled",
			"problem",
			"that",
			"has",
			"no",
			"name",
			"and",
			"in",
			"The",
			"Feminine",
			"Mystique",
			"described",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"as",
			"illusion",
			"women",
			"were",
			"fulfilled",
			"through",
			"marriage",
			"housework"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sapir-Whorf hypothesis[10]  This MIT professor of linguistics and author of Syntactic Structures argued for a universal grammar, meaning that surface differences in languages do not affect cognition, contrary to the Sapir-Whorf hypothesis.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 12 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This principle of linguistic relativity has a strong form, which holds that thought is determined by language, and a weak form, stating that thought is only influenced, not limited, by language.",
		"answers": [
			"Sapir-Whorf",
			"hypothesis",
			"10",
			"This",
			"MIT",
			"professor",
			"linguistics",
			"and",
			"author",
			"Syntactic",
			"Structures",
			"argued",
			"for",
			"universal",
			"grammar",
			"meaning",
			"that",
			"surface",
			"differences",
			"in",
			"languages"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "taxes[10]  At tax rates of 0 and 100 percent, this curve assumes that government revenue is zero. Its maxima represents the optimal tax rate.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 20 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  These entities can be progressive or regressive. Before becoming savings, income is partitioned such that these are taken out and used to fund public-sector expenditures.",
		"answers": [
			"taxes",
			"10",
			"At",
			"tax",
			"rates",
			"0",
			"and",
			"100",
			"percent",
			"this",
			"curve",
			"assumes",
			"that",
			"government",
			"revenue",
			"zero",
			"Its",
			"maxima",
			"represents",
			"optimal",
			"rate"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ruth Benedict[10]  This father of modern anthropology taught Ruth Benedict and Margaret Mead. His own studies of the Kwakiutl led him to develop his ideas of cultural relativism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 16 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this anthropologist whose Patterns of Culture expressed her views of cultural relativism. She wrote about the Japanese guilt and shame cultures in The Chrysanthemum and the Sword.",
		"answers": [
			"Ruth",
			"Benedict",
			"10",
			"This",
			"father",
			"modern",
			"anthropology",
			"taught",
			"and",
			"Margaret",
			"Mead",
			"His",
			"own",
			"studies",
			"Kwakiutl",
			"led",
			"him",
			"to",
			"develop",
			"his",
			"ideas",
			"cultural",
			"relativism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "bald eagle (accept Haliaeetus leucocephalus)[10]  This woman's book Silent Spring raised awareness for the plight of the bald eagle population and the impact of DDT on other birds. She was a marine biologist, and also wrote The Sea Around Us.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 14 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This national bird of the United States is named for its white plumage on the top of its head and not for its lack of hair. It faced near-extinction in the middle of the 20th century.",
		"answers": [
			"bald",
			"eagle",
			"Haliaeetus",
			"leucocephalus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"woman's",
			"book",
			"Silent",
			"Spring",
			"raised",
			"awareness",
			"for",
			"plight",
			"population",
			"and",
			"impact",
			"DDT",
			"other",
			"birds",
			"She",
			"was",
			"marine",
			"biologist",
			"also",
			"wrote",
			"The",
			"Sea",
			"Around",
			"Us"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Benghazi[10]  This UN Ambassador was considered for appointment to Secretary of State in President Obama's second term, but withdrew her name due to the expected controversy over the Benghazi attacks.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 4 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this city, in which a September 11, 2012 attack on the US Embassy led to the death of Ambassador Chris Stevens.",
		"answers": [
			"Benghazi",
			"10",
			"This",
			"UN",
			"Ambassador",
			"was",
			"considered",
			"for",
			"appointment",
			"to",
			"Secretary",
			"State",
			"in",
			"President",
			"Obama's",
			"second",
			"term",
			"but",
			"withdrew",
			"her",
			"name",
			"due",
			"expected",
			"controversy",
			"over",
			"attacks"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "production possibility frontier (or production possibility curve)[10]  The slope at a given point on the PPF is the amount of one good to produce more of the other, the marginal opportunity type of this entity. The next-best alternative given up in a decision is referred to as the opportunity-this.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 7 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this curve from economics which plots the maximum quantity of one good that can be produced against another, such as the trade-off between guns and butter.",
		"answers": [
			"production",
			"possibility",
			"frontier",
			"curve",
			"10",
			"The",
			"slope",
			"at",
			"given",
			"point",
			"PPF",
			"amount",
			"one",
			"good",
			"to",
			"produce",
			"more",
			"other",
			"marginal",
			"opportunity",
			"type",
			"this",
			"entity",
			"next-best",
			"alternative",
			"up",
			"in",
			"decision",
			"referred",
			"as",
			"opportunity-this"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "polygraph machines[10]  Polygraph tests are typically not permitted as evidence in court due to the prevalence of these cases, where people who tell the truth are marked as liars. This term also describes people mistakenly diagnosed with a disease.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 9 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name these machines which can be used to detect lies.",
		"answers": [
			"polygraph",
			"machines",
			"10",
			"Polygraph",
			"tests",
			"are",
			"typically"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "personality[10]  Carl Jung's Psychological Types provided the basis for this personality test. It uses a combination of four dichotomies, such as sensing versus intuition and thinking versus feeling.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 21 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this term which describes the pattern of thoughts, emotions, and behaviors in people. Temperament is considered the innate component of it.",
		"answers": [
			"personality",
			"10",
			"Carl",
			"Jung's",
			"Psychological",
			"Types",
			"provided",
			"basis",
			"for",
			"this",
			"test",
			"It",
			"uses",
			"combination",
			"four",
			"dichotomies",
			"such",
			"as",
			"sensing",
			"versus",
			"intuition",
			"and",
			"thinking",
			"feeling"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "bystander effect (accept Kitty Genovese effect, but do not reveal if not given)[10]  This phenomenon is thought to magnify the bystander effect in large groups. It maintains that people are discouraged from action by the inaction of others around them.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 12 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this effect in which the presence of others makes people less likely to react in emergency situations.",
		"answers": [
			"bystander",
			"effect",
			"Kitty",
			"Genovese",
			"but"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Capitalism and Freedom[10]  This economist wrote Capitalism and Freedom and co-authored Free to Choose with his wife. He advocated for monetarism and criticized the Phillips curve with the natural rate of unemployment.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 5 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this work which sought to define the liberal in European Enlightenment terms. It advocates replacing the Bretton Woods system with a floating exchange rate system.",
		"answers": [
			"Capitalism",
			"and",
			"Freedom",
			"10",
			"This",
			"economist",
			"wrote",
			"co-authored",
			"Free",
			"to",
			"Choose",
			"with",
			"his",
			"wife",
			"He",
			"advocated",
			"for",
			"monetarism",
			"criticized",
			"Phillips",
			"curve",
			"natural",
			"rate",
			"unemployment"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ivan Pavlov[10]  Pavlov championed this branch of behaviorism in which subjects learn to anticipate events by pairing two or more stimuli that are presented in close succession.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 10 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Russian psychologist who more famously monitored salivation to show that dogs can learn to associate the ringing of a bell, with the arrival of food.",
		"answers": [
			"Ivan",
			"Pavlov",
			"10",
			"championed",
			"this",
			"branch",
			"behaviorism",
			"in",
			"which",
			"subjects",
			"learn",
			"to",
			"anticipate",
			"events",
			"by",
			"pairing",
			"two",
			"more",
			"stimuli",
			"that",
			"are",
			"presented",
			"close",
			"succession"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Carl Jung[10]  Jung believed that these universal symbols were used to channel human experience and resulted in typical patterns of behavior.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 20 | Social Science |  | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This psychoanalyst broke with Freud over his assertion that humanity has a collective unconscious. He described the anima and animus as representing the feminine and masculine parts of personality.",
		"answers": [
			"Carl",
			"Jung",
			"10",
			"believed",
			"that",
			"these",
			"universal",
			"symbols",
			"were",
			"used",
			"to",
			"channel",
			"human",
			"experience",
			"and",
			"resulted",
			"in",
			"typical",
			"patterns",
			"behavior"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "availability heuristic[10] This other cognitive bias is the tendency for people to pay attention to information which supports their  preconcieved notions and screen out contradictory information.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many people answer wrongly when asked whether there are more English words that start with K or more words  with K as their third letter. For 10 points each: [10] This heuristic is exemplified by picking the first answer even though more English words have K as their third  letter. This bias makes people think an event is more probable based on how readily an example comes to mind.",
		"answers": [
			"availability",
			"heuristic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"cognitive",
			"bias",
			"tendency",
			"for",
			"people",
			"to",
			"pay",
			"attention",
			"information",
			"which",
			"supports",
			"their",
			"preconcieved"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "availability heuristic[10] This other cognitive bias is the tendency for people to pay attention to information which supports their  preconcieved notions and screen out contradictory information.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 11 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many people answer wrongly when asked whether there are more English words that start with K or more words  with K as their third letter. For 10 points each: [10] This heuristic is exemplified by picking the first answer even though more English words have K as their third  letter. This bias makes people think an event is more probable based on how readily an example comes to mind.",
		"answers": [
			"availability",
			"heuristic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"cognitive",
			"bias",
			"tendency",
			"for",
			"people",
			"to",
			"pay",
			"attention",
			"information",
			"which",
			"supports",
			"their",
			"preconcieved"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "demand curve[10] The slope of the demand curve is related to this measure, defined as the ratio of percentage change in demand  to percentage change in price. It is 0 for a vertical demand curve and infinite for a horizontal demand curve.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 16 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: As income rises, it shifts outward for normal goods and inward for inferior goods. For 10 points each: [10] Name this usually downward-sloping curve that plots the amount of a good that consumers will buy at a given  price.",
		"answers": [
			"demand",
			"curve",
			"10",
			"The",
			"slope",
			"related",
			"to",
			"this",
			"measure",
			"defined",
			"as",
			"ratio",
			"percentage",
			"change",
			"in",
			"price",
			"It",
			"0",
			"for",
			"vertical",
			"and",
			"infinite",
			"horizontal"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "learned helplessness[10] In this questionably ethical experiment, Watson and Rayner aversively conditioned a baby to fear rats and other  furry things.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name some things about conditioning: [10] The inability to avoid adverse events can result in this feeling of futility. Even if the opportunity to escape is  reintroduced, the learner will often still resign themselves.",
		"answers": [
			"learned",
			"helplessness",
			"10",
			"In",
			"this",
			"questionably",
			"ethical",
			"experiment",
			"Watson",
			"and",
			"Rayner",
			"aversively",
			"conditioned",
			"baby",
			"to",
			"fear",
			"rats",
			"other",
			"furry",
			"things"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "William James[10] William James and C. S. Peirce founded this philosophical school whose core maxim emphasizes the  importance of clear concepts and practical consequences.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 8 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He critiqued Spinoza and Hume in \"The Sentiment of Rationality.\" For 10 points each: [10] Identify this philosopher who described the \"stream of thought\" in Principles of Psychology and discussed  mysticism in The Varieties of Religious Experience.",
		"answers": [
			"William",
			"James",
			"10",
			"and",
			"C",
			"S",
			"Peirce",
			"founded",
			"this",
			"philosophical",
			"school",
			"whose",
			"core",
			"maxim",
			"emphasizes",
			"importance",
			"clear",
			"concepts",
			"practical",
			"consequences"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "money [do not accept \"currency\"][10] The Federal Reserve sets this minimum amount of money that a bank must retain at the end of each day. It is  currently 10% of the bank's net transactions. The money multiplier is the reciprocal of this quantity.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 12 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The fiat type of this entity derives its value from its declaration as \"legal tender\" by the government. For 10  points each: [10] Give this general term for an object that can be accepted as payment for a good or service. Most of its M1 (\"M  one\") supply is held in banks.",
		"answers": [
			"money"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Edward Sapir[10] In an influential study in linguistic relativity, Berlin and Kay studied different languages' words for these concepts, classifying English as \"Stage VII\" since it has separate words for purple, pink, orange, and gray.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 12 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man helped record the Yahi language from its last living member, a man called Ishi. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Yale linguist who created a comprehensive classification of Native American languages for the Encyclopedia Britannica. He inspired his student Benjamin Whorf to develop the theory of linguistic relativity.",
		"answers": [
			"Edward",
			"Sapir",
			"10",
			"In",
			"an",
			"influential",
			"study",
			"in",
			"linguistic",
			"relativity",
			"Berlin",
			"and",
			"Kay",
			"studied",
			"different",
			"languages'",
			"words",
			"for",
			"these",
			"concepts",
			"classifying",
			"English",
			"as",
			"Stage",
			"VII",
			"since",
			"has",
			"separate",
			"purple",
			"pink",
			"orange",
			"gray"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "mythology [or mythologies][10] This French anthropologist developed his structuralist approach to myth in Mythologiques, which includes The Raw and the Cooked. He also wrote the memoir Tristes Tropiques and The Elementary Structures of Kinship.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 15 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Robert Graves subtitled his The White Goddess \"a Historical Grammar of Poetic\" this, and Roland Barthes examined \"The World of Wrestling\" and \"Toys\" in a book named for a set of these. For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept whose Zuni variety titles an anthropological survey by Ruth Benedict.",
		"answers": [
			"mythology",
			"mythologies",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"anthropologist",
			"developed",
			"his",
			"structuralist",
			"approach",
			"to",
			"myth",
			"in",
			"Mythologiques",
			"which",
			"includes",
			"The",
			"Raw",
			"and",
			"Cooked",
			"He",
			"also",
			"wrote",
			"memoir",
			"Tristes",
			"Tropiques",
			"Elementary",
			"Structures",
			"Kinship"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Max Weber[10] Weber proposed that the Protestant ethic was closely related to \"the spirit of\" this economic system based on free markets, which communists oppose.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 6 | Social Science | None | HS",
		"subject": "Social Science",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This German author of The Religion of China, The Religion of India, and Economy and Society delineated rational-legal, traditional, and charismatic types of authority. For 10 points each: [10] Name this sociologist who suggested that Calvinism was responsible for the appearance of a novel economic system in Northern Europe.",
		"answers": [
			"Max",
			"Weber",
			"10",
			"proposed",
			"that",
			"Protestant",
			"ethic",
			"was",
			"closely",
			"related",
			"to",
			"spirit",
			"this",
			"economic",
			"system",
			"based",
			"free",
			"markets",
			"which",
			"communists",
			"oppose"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "cogito ergo sum [or I am thinking, therefore I am; prompt on the cogito][10] This French dualist philosopher who wrote Discourse on Method declared cogito ergo sum. He questioned the veracity of our senses with scenarios involving melting wax and an evil demon.",
		"prompts": [
			"cogito",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"dualist",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"wrote",
			"Discourse",
			"Method",
			"declared",
			"cogito",
			"ergo",
			"sum",
			"He",
			"questioned",
			"veracity",
			"our",
			"senses",
			"with",
			"scenarios",
			"involving",
			"melting",
			"wax",
			"and",
			"an",
			"evil",
			"demon"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 1 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Nietzsche and Kierkegaard criticized this proposition because its first statement presupposes self-existence. For 10 points each:  [10] Identify this proposition concluding self-existence that for one philosopher, serves as the basis for all further knowledge. It was reached by indirect proof after a process of hyperbolic doubt in Discourse on Method. ",
		"answers": [
			"cogito",
			"ergo",
			"sum",
			"I",
			"am",
			"thinking",
			"therefore"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Leviathan[10] The Leviathan is a political structure imagined by this English philosopher, who warned that the alternative is a state of nature where life is \"solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 16 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This entity is depicted wielding both a sword and a papal staff with a body made of people. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this symbol of the Commonwealth, headed by a Sovereign with civil and ecclesiastical power. It represents a covenant where people cede their natural rights for a state of peace. ",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Leviathan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"political",
			"structure",
			"imagined",
			"by",
			"this",
			"English",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"warned",
			"that",
			"alternative",
			"state",
			"nature",
			"where",
			"life",
			"solitary",
			"poor",
			"nasty",
			"brutish",
			"and",
			"short"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "anarchy[10] Thucydides fictionalized a dialogue between realist Athens and this idealist island during the Peloponnesian War. This island refuses to surrender to the Athenians, who justify its destruction wih \"might makes right\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 12 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, identify the following about realism in international relations. [10] Realists believe that the international system is characterized by this property, since it lacks a universal central authority. Because of this, uncertainty and self-help pervade the system.",
		"answers": [
			"anarchy",
			"10",
			"Thucydides",
			"fictionalized",
			"dialogue",
			"between",
			"realist",
			"Athens",
			"and",
			"this",
			"idealist",
			"island",
			"during",
			"Peloponnesian",
			"War",
			"This",
			"refuses",
			"to",
			"surrender",
			"Athenians",
			"who",
			"justify",
			"its",
			"destruction",
			"wih",
			"might",
			"makes",
			"right"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "being [or Sein][10] Martin Heidegger, the author of Being and Time, was a forerunner of this movement most notably espoused by Jacques Derrida in Of Grammatology. This form of criticism believes that there is \"nothing outside the text.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BISB |2013 | 2 | 10 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This phenomenon occurs \"toward-death\" and \"in-the-world\", and one form of it is defined as \"this entity which each of us is himself.\" For 10 points each [10] Name this central concept of dasein (pr. DIE-ZIN). This word is paired with \"time\" in the title of a 1927 work of philosophy.",
		"answers": [
			"being",
			"Sein",
			"10",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"author",
			"Being",
			"and",
			"Time",
			"was",
			"forerunner",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"most"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "syllogism[10] In order to get the upper hand, your partner remarks, \"Well, you've got a terrible sense of taste, and you have big feet.\" Such irrelevant, personal attacks, are often described by this two-word Latin phrase.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 8 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: You are arguing that all M&Ms don't have the same flavor with a terrible arguer who thinks they do. For 10 points each: [10] Your adversary claims, \"All M&Ms are made of chocolate, and all chocolate has the same flavor, therefore all M&Ms have the same flavor\"--an example of these three-part statements first described by Aristotle.",
		"answers": [
			"syllogism",
			"10",
			"In",
			"order",
			"to",
			"get",
			"upper",
			"hand",
			"your",
			"partner",
			"remarks",
			"Well",
			"you've",
			"got",
			"terrible",
			"sense",
			"taste",
			"and",
			"you",
			"have",
			"big",
			"feet",
			"Such",
			"irrelevant",
			"personal",
			"attacks",
			"are",
			"often",
			"described",
			"by",
			"this",
			"two-word",
			"Latin",
			"phrase"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Birth of Tragedy from the Spirit of Music [accept Die Geburt der Tragödie aus dem Geiste der Musik][10] This work by the same author of The Birth of Tragedy first introduced the concept of the Übermensch, which is described as the ultimate goal for humanity.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 18 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This work was later reissued by its author with an additional preface, An Attempt at Self-Criticism. For 10 points each: [10] Name this work which contrasts the Apollonian and Dionysian interpretations of a certain art form.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Birth",
			"Tragedy",
			"from",
			"Spirit",
			"Music",
			"Die",
			"Geburt",
			"der",
			"Tragödie",
			"aus",
			"dem",
			"Geiste",
			"Musik",
			"10",
			"This",
			"work",
			"by",
			"same",
			"author",
			"first",
			"introduced",
			"concept",
			"Übermensch",
			"which",
			"described",
			"as",
			"ultimate",
			"goal",
			"for",
			"humanity"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Immanuel Kant[10] This philosopher gave a critique of Kant in the work Kant and the Problem of Metaphysics. This Nazi supporter proposed the concept of Dasein, or \"existence,\" in Being and Time.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 18 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This philosopher encouraged others to \"dare to know\" in his work \"What is Enlightenment?\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this German philosopher who examined a priori knowledge in his Critique of Pure Reason.",
		"answers": [
			"Immanuel",
			"Kant",
			"10",
			"This",
			"philosopher",
			"gave",
			"critique",
			"in",
			"work",
			"and",
			"Problem",
			"Metaphysics",
			"Nazi",
			"supporter",
			"proposed",
			"concept",
			"Dasein",
			"existence",
			"Being",
			"Time"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Karl Heinrich Marx[10] Marx is known for this multi-volume treatise, which posits that the tendency of the rate of profit to fall leads to the exploitation of labor by employers to produce the title asset.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 5 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man claimed that \"[s]ociety does not consist of individuals, but expresses the sum of interrelations, the relations within which these individuals stand.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this man, whose writings inspired the theory of historical materialism.",
		"answers": [
			"Karl",
			"Heinrich",
			"Marx",
			"10",
			"known",
			"for",
			"this",
			"multi-volume",
			"treatise",
			"which",
			"posits",
			"that",
			"tendency",
			"rate",
			"profit",
			"to",
			"fall",
			"leads",
			"exploitation",
			"labor",
			"by",
			"employers",
			"produce",
			"title",
			"asset"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Principia Mathematica[10] This British thinker wrote Principia Mathematica along with Alfred Whitehead; other works by him include \"A History of Western Philosophy\" and \"Why I am not a Christian.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 12 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This work attempted to derive a set of axioms that could be used to prove mathematical truths. For 10 points each: [10] Name this work of set theory and mathematical logic that was shown to have failed to fulfill its goal by Gödel's Incompleteness Theorems. ",
		"answers": [
			"Principia",
			"Mathematica",
			"10",
			"This",
			"British",
			"thinker",
			"wrote",
			"along",
			"with",
			"Alfred",
			"Whitehead",
			"other",
			"works",
			"by",
			"him",
			"include",
			"A",
			"History",
			"Western",
			"Philosophy",
			"and",
			"Why",
			"I",
			"am"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Friedrich Nietzsche[10] In The Birth of Tragedy Nietzsche compares the more chaotic art of Dionysus to the art of this god, which is guided more by reason.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 20 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: His book Ecce Homo contains chapters titled \"Why I Am So Wise\" and \"Why I Am a Destiny.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this German philosopher who said \"God is dead\" and related concepts like the ubermensch in his book Thus Spake Zarathustra.",
		"answers": [
			"Friedrich",
			"Nietzsche",
			"10",
			"In",
			"The",
			"Birth",
			"Tragedy",
			"compares",
			"more",
			"chaotic",
			"art",
			"Dionysus",
			"to",
			"this",
			"god",
			"which",
			"guided",
			"by",
			"reason"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Confucianism (accept word forms including Confucius)[10] This collection of Confucius's sayings was compiled by his followers, and includes his descriptions of concepts such as the Golden Rule.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 9 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Mencius was one member of this school of thought. For 10 points each: [10] Name this philosophy formulated by a namesake Chinese philosopher which advocates filial piety. It was the state philosophy of the Han dynasty.",
		"answers": [
			"Confucianism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"including",
			"Confucius",
			"10",
			"This",
			"collection",
			"Confucius's",
			"sayings",
			"was",
			"compiled",
			"by",
			"his",
			"followers",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"descriptions",
			"concepts",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Golden",
			"Rule"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mohism [or Mojia][10] The Mohist theory of \"impartial care\" is often translated as the \"Universal\" type of this emotion, which is discussed drunkenly in Plato's Symposium.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 5 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  This school sought objective moral standards called fa, and followed ten doctrines such as \"Thrift in Funerals\" which were laid out in ten triads of essays. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this Chinese school of thought which was opposed to Confucianism for its lack of concern with filial piety. It was wiped out by Legalism. ",
		"answers": [
			"Mohism",
			"Mojia",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Mohist",
			"theory",
			"impartial",
			"care",
			"often",
			"translated",
			"as",
			"Universal",
			"type",
			"this",
			"emotion",
			"which",
			"discussed",
			"drunkenly",
			"in",
			"Plato's",
			"Symposium"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Baruch Spinoza[10]  Spinoza's monism contrasts with this theory that asserts that the mind is an independently existing but non-physical substance. It was developed by Rene Descartes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This philosopher approached the mind-body problem with the assertion that everything that exists, including human beings, is a \"mode\" of God, a theory that he espoused in his work Ethics.",
		"answers": [
			"Baruch",
			"Spinoza",
			"10",
			"Spinoza's",
			"monism",
			"contrasts",
			"with",
			"this",
			"theory",
			"that",
			"asserts",
			"mind",
			"an",
			"independently",
			"existing",
			"but",
			"non-physical",
			"substance",
			"It",
			"was",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"Rene",
			"Descartes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pragmatism[10]  This author of The Principles of Psychology and \"The Will to Believe\" sought a middle ground between \"tough-minded\" and \"tender-minded\" philosophers in his work Pragmatism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 1 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this school of philosophy that emphasizes practical utility and uses actual value to define truth. It was espoused by John Dewey and the author of \"How to Make Our Ideas Clear\", C.S. Peirce (\"purse\").",
		"answers": [
			"pragmatism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"The",
			"Principles",
			"Psychology",
			"and",
			"Will",
			"to",
			"Believe",
			"sought",
			"middle",
			"ground",
			"between",
			"tough-minded",
			"tender-minded",
			"philosophers",
			"in",
			"his",
			"work",
			"Pragmatism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "relativism[10]  This Greek sophist was an early relativist. His teachings are described in Theaetetus and his namesake Platonic dialogue, where he discussed if virtue can be taught. He famously stated \"man is the measure of all things\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 1 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This concept states that there is no absolute truth or validity, but that truth should be viewed within the reference frame of a language or culture. The \"moral\" type of this concept is particularly contentious.",
		"answers": [
			"relativism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Greek",
			"sophist",
			"was",
			"an",
			"early",
			"relativist",
			"His",
			"teachings",
			"are",
			"described",
			"in",
			"Theaetetus",
			"and",
			"his",
			"namesake",
			"Platonic",
			"dialogue",
			"where",
			"he",
			"discussed",
			"if",
			"virtue",
			"can",
			"be",
			"taught",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"stated",
			"man",
			"measure",
			"all",
			"things"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "separation of powers [prompt on \"tripartite system\"][10]  This French Enlightenment political philosopher articulated a theory of the separation of powers. He argued that monarchies relied on the principle of virtue, and despotisms relied on fear.",
		"prompts": [
			"tripartite",
			"system",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"Enlightenment",
			"political",
			"philosopher",
			"articulated",
			"theory",
			"separation",
			"powers",
			"He",
			"argued",
			"that",
			"monarchies",
			"relied",
			"principle",
			"virtue",
			"and",
			"despotisms",
			"relied",
			"fear"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 12 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This model proposes the division of the state into independent branches, each no more powerful than the others. This system often yields legislative, judicial, and executive branches.",
		"answers": [
			"separation",
			"powers"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Epicureanism[10]  This Roman Epicurean stated that the \"nature of mind and soul\" is \"corporeal\" in his De rerum natura, or \"On the Nature of Things\", which also asserts that nothing exists except bodies and the void.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 11 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical school, named after its Athenian founder, which believed pleasure to be the ultimate good, advocating moderate asceticism in order to be free from pain.",
		"answers": [
			"Epicureanism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Roman",
			"Epicurean",
			"stated",
			"that",
			"nature",
			"mind",
			"and",
			"soul",
			"corporeal",
			"in",
			"his",
			"De",
			"rerum",
			"natura",
			"On",
			"Nature",
			"Things",
			"which",
			"also",
			"asserts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"On Denoting\"[10]  This writer of \"Why I am Not a Christian\" and \"On Denoting\" is also known for his namesake paradox, which pertains to a set of all sets that does not include itself.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 18 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this essay that attempts to tackle the problems of substitutivity, the excluded middle, and negative existentials by introducing a theory of definite descriptions.",
		"answers": [
			"On"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Summa Theologica [or Summation of Theology; prompt on \"Summa\"][10]  This Scholastic philosopher defended Christianity and put forth a four-part definition of faith in Summa con Gentiles, which he expanded on in Summa Theologica.",
		"prompts": [
			"Summa",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Scholastic",
			"philosopher",
			"defended",
			"Christianity",
			"and",
			"put",
			"forth",
			"four-part",
			"definition",
			"faith",
			"in",
			"Summa",
			"con",
			"Gentiles",
			"which",
			"he",
			"expanded",
			"in",
			"Summa",
			"Theologica"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 5 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this incomplete work structured as a series of objections and responses. It contains five arguments for the existence of God.",
		"answers": [
			"Summa",
			"Theologica",
			"Summation",
			"Theology"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "principle of sufficient reason[10]  This philosopher used the principle of sufficient reason to argue that the reason for this world is that it is the best of all possible worlds in Monadology.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 20 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this principle which states that all truths must have a cause.",
		"answers": [
			"principle",
			"sufficient",
			"reason",
			"10",
			"This",
			"philosopher",
			"used",
			"to",
			"argue",
			"that",
			"for",
			"this",
			"world",
			"best",
			"all",
			"possible",
			"worlds",
			"in",
			"Monadology"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Martin Heidegger[10]  This Heidegger work discusses viewing objects as a means to an end as being \"ready-to-hand\", as opposed to \"present-at-hand\". Heidegger never finished this work, so the part on the second title concept is incomplete.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 21 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this post-Kantian German philosopher, who argued that experience was grounded in intentionality and care. He coined the term Dasein to refer to a state of being that understands itself through its own existence.",
		"answers": [
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"10",
			"This",
			"work",
			"discusses",
			"viewing",
			"objects",
			"as",
			"means",
			"to",
			"an",
			"end",
			"being",
			"ready-to-hand",
			"opposed",
			"present-at-hand",
			"never",
			"finished",
			"this",
			"so",
			"part",
			"second",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"incomplete"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "arithmetic (or Arithmetik)[10]  This man had earlier analyzed the statement 7+5=12 in his Critique of Pure Reason. The most well-known formulation of his categorical imperative states that one should only do something if it should be done universally.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 18 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this discipline, the foundations of which were written about by Gottlob Frege. That work attacks the notion that 7+5=12 is a synthetic statement.",
		"answers": [
			"arithmetic",
			"Arithmetik",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"had",
			"earlier",
			"analyzed",
			"statement",
			"7+5=12",
			"in",
			"his",
			"Critique",
			"Pure",
			"Reason",
			"The",
			"most",
			"well-known",
			"formulation",
			"categorical",
			"imperative",
			"states",
			"that",
			"one",
			"should",
			"only",
			"something",
			"if",
			"be",
			"done",
			"universally"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Soren Kierkegaard (accept Anti-Climacus, John the Silent, or Johannes de Silentio)[10]  Some consider Kierkegaard to be the first philosopher from this movement, which claimed that the individual must be the starting point of philosophy. Other members of it included Simone de Beauvoir and Martin Heidegger.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 9 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Danish philosopher, author of The Sickness Unto Death and Fear and Trembling.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Soren",
			"Kierkegaard",
			"Anti-Climacus",
			"John",
			"Silent",
			"Johannes",
			"de",
			"Silentio",
			"10",
			"Some",
			"consider",
			"to",
			"be",
			"first",
			"philosopher",
			"from",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"which",
			"claimed",
			"that",
			"individual",
			"must",
			"starting",
			"point",
			"philosophy",
			"Other",
			"members",
			"included",
			"Simone",
			"Beauvoir",
			"and",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Rawls[10]  Rawls described this concept as a combination of liberty and equality in a work titled [this] as Fairness. His A Theory of [this] was refuted by Robert Nozick in Anarchy, State, and Utopia, and it's sometimes also defined as \"giving each his due\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 6 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this American philosopher whose \"original position\" parallels the \"state of nature\". He argued that inequalities in society should benefit the least advantaged, his \"difference principle\".",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Rawls",
			"10",
			"described",
			"this",
			"concept",
			"as",
			"combination",
			"liberty",
			"and",
			"equality",
			"in",
			"work",
			"titled",
			"Fairness",
			"His",
			"A",
			"Theory",
			"was",
			"refuted",
			"by",
			"Robert",
			"Nozick",
			"Anarchy",
			"State",
			"Utopia",
			"it's",
			"sometimes",
			"also",
			"defined",
			"giving",
			"each",
			"his",
			"due"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Being and Time (or Sein und Zeit)[10]  This German philosopher  joined the Nazi party soon after writing Being and Time. His other works include Kant and the Problem of Metaphysics and On the Way to Language.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical work, which uses phenomenological ontology to analyze the concept of Dasein, which describes the awareness of human consciousness.",
		"answers": [
			"Being",
			"and",
			"Time",
			"Sein",
			"und",
			"Zeit",
			"10",
			"This",
			"German",
			"philosopher",
			"joined",
			"Nazi",
			"party",
			"soon",
			"after",
			"writing",
			"His",
			"other",
			"works",
			"include",
			"Kant",
			"Problem",
			"Metaphysics",
			"On",
			"Way",
			"to",
			"Language"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus[10]  This Austrian philosopher wrote Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus and described the \"beetle in a box\" thought experiment in his posthumously published Philosophical Investigations.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 21 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical work comprised of seven propositions, such as \"the world is everything that is the case\" and \"whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Tractatus",
			"Logico-Philosophicus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Austrian",
			"philosopher",
			"wrote",
			"and",
			"described",
			"beetle",
			"in",
			"box",
			"thought",
			"experiment",
			"his",
			"posthumously",
			"published",
			"Philosophical",
			"Investigations"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stoicism (accept word forms)[10]  This founder of Stoicism rejected the cynicism of his teacher, Crates of Thebes. He declined Athenian citizenship in order to remain faithful to his native Citium.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 19 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Hellenistic school of philosophy which advocated for self-control to think clearly. Its members included Marcus Aurelius, Cicero, and Seneca the Younger.",
		"answers": [
			"Stoicism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"This",
			"founder",
			"rejected",
			"cynicism",
			"his",
			"teacher",
			"Crates",
			"Thebes",
			"He",
			"declined",
			"Athenian",
			"citizenship",
			"in",
			"order",
			"to",
			"remain",
			"faithful",
			"native",
			"Citium"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Stuart Mill[10]  Along with Jeremy Bentham, Mill is known as a proponent of this ethical theory, which maintains that the moral course of action is the one which results in the greatest good for the greatest number.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 5 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this English philosopher whose feminist ideas were published in \"The Subjection of Women\". He described his \"harm principle\" in On Liberty.",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Stuart",
			"Mill",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"Jeremy",
			"Bentham",
			"known",
			"as",
			"proponent",
			"this",
			"ethical",
			"theory",
			"which",
			"maintains",
			"that",
			"moral",
			"course",
			"action",
			"one",
			"results",
			"in",
			"greatest",
			"good",
			"for",
			"number"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "skepticism[10]  This Spanish-American philosopher discussed the title concept \"in religion\" and \"in common sense\" in The Sense of Beauty and wrote Scepticism and Animal Faith as well as The Life of Reason.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical school of thought which sought ataraxia, or \"freedom from worry\", and argued against absolute certainty in belief. One philosopher refuted it in a work titled [this] and Animal Faith.",
		"answers": [
			"skepticism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Spanish-American",
			"philosopher",
			"discussed",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"religion",
			"and",
			"common",
			"sense",
			"The",
			"Sense",
			"Beauty",
			"wrote",
			"Scepticism",
			"Animal",
			"Faith",
			"as",
			"well",
			"Life",
			"Reason"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Leviathan[10]  This English philosopher and social contract theorist wrote that life in the state of nature was \"nasty, brutish, and short\" in  Leviathan. He also argued that an effective government must have absolute authority.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 22 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this work which describes life without a central government as a \"war of all against all\". Its \"Of Man\" section describes the fear of violent death as the greatest evil.",
		"answers": [
			"Leviathan",
			"10",
			"This",
			"English",
			"philosopher",
			"and",
			"social",
			"contract",
			"theorist",
			"wrote",
			"that",
			"life",
			"in",
			"state",
			"nature",
			"was",
			"nasty",
			"brutish",
			"short",
			"He",
			"also",
			"argued",
			"an",
			"effective",
			"government",
			"must",
			"have",
			"absolute",
			"authority"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Immanuel Kant[10] Kant introduced this term that refers to the subjective experience of noumena. Kant claimed that knowledge was limited to these appearances of things, which are the only directly observable objects.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 6 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He cited Horace's \"Sapere Aude\" as part of the transition out of immaturity in What is Enlightenment? For 10 points each:  [10] Name this philosopher who concluded that metaphysics is inherently dialectical in his Critique of Pure Reason. He also wrote the Critique of Judgment and the Metaphysics of Morals.",
		"answers": [
			"Immanuel",
			"Kant",
			"10",
			"introduced",
			"this",
			"term",
			"that",
			"refers",
			"to",
			"subjective",
			"experience",
			"noumena",
			"claimed",
			"knowledge",
			"was",
			"limited",
			"these",
			"appearances",
			"things",
			"which",
			"are",
			"only",
			"directly",
			"observable",
			"objects"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zeno[10] Another philosopher, Zeno of Citium, founded this school of philosophy, whose adherents included Epictetus and the Roman Emperor Marcus Aurelius. It proposed that virtue was the only good.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 19 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following questions about Classical philosophers, for 10 points each. [10] One philosopher of this name from Elea was a student of Parmenides, and according to a Platonic dialogue, debated a young Socrates. His paradoxes of motion feature the motionless arrow and Achilles racing a tortoise.",
		"answers": [
			"Zeno",
			"10"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "time[10] Martin Heidegger later joined the Nazis, whose central philosophy came from this anti-Semitic autobiography presaging Germany's invasion of Russia, written by an imprisoned Adolf Hitler.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 2 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Immanuel Kant's transcendental aesthetic defines this as the a priori ability to perceive oneself, and Bergson contrasted this concept with \"free will.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept central to  a Martin Heidegger work that developed the concept of Dasein, in which it is contrasted with \"Being\".",
		"answers": [
			"time",
			"10",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"later",
			"joined",
			"Nazis",
			"whose",
			"central",
			"philosophy",
			"came",
			"from",
			"this",
			"anti-Semitic",
			"autobiography",
			"presaging",
			"Germany's",
			"invasion",
			"Russia",
			"written",
			"by",
			"an",
			"imprisoned",
			"Adolf",
			"Hitler"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Judges [or Sefer Shoftim][10] In the Book of Judges, this homicidal son of Gideon kills seventy of his brothers and meets his ignominious end when a lady fatally wounds him by tossing a mill-stone, prompting this man to instruct his armor-bearer to kill him so he wouldn't die at the hands of a woman.",
		"prompts": [
			"this",
			"man",
			"to",
			"instruct",
			"his",
			"armor-bearer",
			"to",
			"kill",
			"him",
			"so",
			"he",
			"wouldn't",
			"die",
			"at",
			"hands",
			"woman"
		],
		"heading": "PACE NSC |2015 | 4 | 18 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this book, Ehud tells the king Eglon \"I have a message from God for you,\" then stabs the overweight king in the abdomen so hard that his bowels leak out. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Biblical book in which Jephthah promises to sacrifice the first person he sees after a battle, who ends up being his own daughter, and Deborah teams up with Barak to defeat Sisera.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Judges",
			"Sefer",
			"Shoftim",
			"10",
			"In",
			"this",
			"homicidal",
			"son",
			"Gideon",
			"kills",
			"seventy",
			"his",
			"brothers",
			"and",
			"meets",
			"ignominious",
			"end",
			"when",
			"lady",
			"fatally",
			"wounds",
			"him",
			"by",
			"tossing",
			"mill-stone"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Simon Peter [prompt on \"Kephas\"][10] This Apostle is the only one not to have been martyred, but was exiled to the island of Patmos, where he had mystic visions and recorded them in the Book of Revelation.",
		"prompts": [
			"Kephas",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Apostle",
			"only",
			"one",
			"not",
			"to",
			"have",
			"been",
			"martyred",
			"but",
			"was",
			"exiled",
			"to",
			"island",
			"Patmos",
			"where",
			"he",
			"had",
			"mystic",
			"visions",
			"and",
			"recorded",
			"them",
			"in",
			"Book",
			"Revelation"
		],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 1 | 4 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name these Apostles of Jesus [10] This Apostle was crucified upside-down in Nero's Circus after seeing a vision of Jesus telling him to return to Rome. He is considered by Catholics to be the first Pope, and is buried underneath the altar of his namesake Basilica.",
		"answers": [
			"Simon",
			"Peter"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hanukkah [or Chanukah; or Festival of Lights; or Feast of Dedication][10] This holiday is celebrated on the fourteenth day of Adar and commemorates an event in which Esther and Mordecai foiled Haman's plot to kill the Jews.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 15 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name the following Jewish holidays. [10] This eight-day holiday begins on the twenty-fifth day of Kislev and includes the lighting of the shamash on the nine-branched Menorah. It commemorates the reclaiming of the Temple in Jerusalem during the Maccabean Revolt.",
		"answers": [
			"Hanukkah",
			"Chanukah",
			"Festival",
			"Lights",
			"Feast",
			"Dedication",
			"10",
			"This",
			"holiday",
			"celebrated",
			"fourteenth",
			"day",
			"Adar",
			"and",
			"commemorates",
			"an",
			"event",
			"in",
			"which",
			"Esther",
			"Mordecai",
			"foiled",
			"Haman's",
			"plot",
			"to",
			"kill",
			"Jews"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Qur'an [or Koran][10] One source for interpretation of the Qur'an are these sayings and deeds of Muhammad. They are classified into the categories of authentic, good, and weak.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 3 | 20 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: With the exception of At-Tawba, each sura of this work begins with the basmala. [10] Name this holy text, said to have been dictated to Muhammad by the angel Jibril. It is the most important Islamic scripture.",
		"answers": [
			"Qur'an",
			"Koran",
			"10",
			"One",
			"source",
			"for",
			"interpretation",
			"are",
			"these",
			"sayings",
			"and",
			"deeds",
			"Muhammad",
			"They",
			"classified",
			"into",
			"categories",
			"authentic",
			"good",
			"weak"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Theravāda Buddhism [prompt on \"Hinayana Buddhism\"][10] Through the Sutta Pitaka, Theravada Buddhism teaches that there are four steps in achieving this state. One attempts to achieve this state to become an arahant, and the first stage in that process is being a \"stream-enterer.\"",
		"prompts": [
			"Hinayana",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"Through",
			"Sutta",
			"Pitaka",
			"Theravada",
			"Buddhism",
			"teaches",
			"that",
			"there",
			"are",
			"four",
			"steps",
			"in",
			"achieving",
			"this",
			"state",
			"One",
			"attempts",
			"to",
			"achieve",
			"this",
			"state",
			"to",
			"become",
			"an",
			"arahant",
			"and",
			"first",
			"stage",
			"in",
			"that",
			"process",
			"being",
			"stream-enterer"
		],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 5 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This sect's standard collection of scriptures is the Pāli Canon. [10] Name this sect of Buddhism, which acknowledges only Gautama Buddha and teaches the incorruptibility of arahants. It is often contrasted with Mahayana Buddhism.",
		"answers": [
			"Theravāda",
			"Buddhism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Saint Stephen[10] This saint was beheaded under Diocletian for opposing his ban on Christian soldiers. He is the patron saint of England, and he is known for slaying a dragon in Cappadocia.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2014 | 2 | 12 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One witness to this man's stoning was Saul of Tarsus, who held the coats of those who killed this man. For 10 points each: [10] Name this first martyr of Christianity, whose death is recorded in the Acts of the Apostles.",
		"answers": [
			"Saint",
			"Stephen",
			"10",
			"This",
			"saint",
			"was",
			"beheaded",
			"under",
			"Diocletian",
			"for",
			"opposing",
			"his",
			"ban",
			"Christian",
			"soldiers",
			"He",
			"patron",
			"England",
			"and",
			"he",
			"known",
			"slaying",
			"dragon",
			"in",
			"Cappadocia"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Beatitudes[10] The Sermon on the Mount is contained within Chapter 5 of this first book of the New Testament.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 2 | 5 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this collection of statements which claims that the kingdom of heaven awaits those poor in spirit and those who are persecuted for the sake of righteousness.",
		"answers": [
			"Beatitudes",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Sermon",
			"Mount",
			"contained",
			"within",
			"Chapter",
			"5",
			"this",
			"first",
			"book",
			"New",
			"Testament"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sabbath (accept Shabbath, Sabbatum, or Sabbaton)[10] Keeping the Sabbath day holy is required by the fourth of these laws. These also forbid killing and taking the Lord's name in vain.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 2 | 6 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this day on which work was forbidden. In some traditions, travel outside the city walls was restricted to 2000 cubits, which is about half a mile.",
		"answers": [
			"Sabbath",
			"Shabbath",
			"Sabbatum",
			"Sabbaton",
			"10",
			"Keeping",
			"day",
			"holy",
			"required",
			"by",
			"fourth",
			"these",
			"laws",
			"These",
			"also",
			"forbid",
			"killing",
			"and",
			"taking",
			"Lord's",
			"name",
			"in",
			"vain"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zen Buddhism [10] Zen Buddhism supposedly had its legend in this story in which Buddha handed the namesake object to his follower Mahakashyapa while sitting at a pond.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 4 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Sanskrit word \"Dhyana\" is the origin for the name of this religion. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this branch of Mahayana Buddhism that asks unanswerable questions called koans and is practiced in Eastern Asia. ",
		"answers": [
			"Zen",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"supposedly",
			"had",
			"its",
			"legend",
			"in",
			"this",
			"story",
			"which",
			"Buddha",
			"handed",
			"namesake",
			"object",
			"to",
			"his",
			"follower",
			"Mahakashyapa",
			"while",
			"sitting",
			"at",
			"pond"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "hajj[10] This other pillar of Islam involves giving alms to the poor and needy. Its non-Muslim equivalent is the Jizyah tax.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 8 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name some things associated with pillars of Islam. [10] This pillar of Islam, which takes place during the last month of the Islamic calendar, is a ritual pilgrimage to Mecca.",
		"answers": [
			"hajj",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"pillar",
			"Islam",
			"involves",
			"giving",
			"alms",
			"to",
			"poor",
			"and",
			"needy",
			"Its",
			"non-Muslim",
			"equivalent",
			"Jizyah",
			"tax"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gematriya[10] This is the number of days of Creation in Genesis including resting, the number of holy virtues and deadly sins in Christianity, and the number of skies or heavens in a variety of religions including Islam.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 6 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about significant numbers in religion, for 10 points each. [10] This Jewish numerological tradition assigns numbers to letters, words, and phrases. In this system, the letters of chai, meaning life, add to 18, which is therefore considered a lucky number.",
		"answers": [
			"gematriya",
			"10",
			"This",
			"number",
			"days",
			"Creation",
			"in",
			"Genesis",
			"including",
			"resting",
			"holy",
			"virtues",
			"and",
			"deadly",
			"sins",
			"Christianity",
			"skies",
			"heavens",
			"variety",
			"religions",
			"Islam"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kaddish[10] This prayer, traditionally said twice a day, is a restatement of three passages from the Bible, starting with \"Hear O Israel, the LORD is God, the LORD is one.\" Along with the Amidah, it is one of the central prayers in Judaism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 18 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about bits of the Jewish prayer service for 10 points each. [10] This prayer, one kind of which is said by mourners, is used to split up sections of a prayer service. It needs 10 Jewish adults present to be said.",
		"answers": [
			"Kaddish",
			"10",
			"This",
			"prayer",
			"traditionally",
			"said",
			"twice",
			"day",
			"restatement",
			"three",
			"passages",
			"from",
			"Bible",
			"starting",
			"with",
			"Hear",
			"O",
			"Israel",
			"LORD",
			"God",
			"one",
			"Along",
			"Amidah",
			"central",
			"prayers",
			"in",
			"Judaism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Quakers [accept Religious Society of Friends][10] This man founded the Quakers. He was arrested for blasphemy twice, once while preaching under a tree at Balby.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Followers of this religion were known for their opposition to slavery. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Christian sect known for its pacifism. Its colloquial name comes from the command to \"tremble at the word of the Lord.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Quakers",
			"Religious",
			"Society",
			"Friends",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"founded",
			"He",
			"was",
			"arrested",
			"for",
			"blasphemy",
			"twice",
			"once",
			"while",
			"preaching",
			"under",
			"tree",
			"at",
			"Balby"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Esther [or Hadassah][10] This woman set the precedent for conversion and familial piety in her namesake book by telling her mother-in-law that \"your people shall be my people, and your God shall be my God\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 5 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about women who have their own Old Testament books, for 10 points each. [10] This woman married the Persian king in order to stop a plot to kill the Jews. Her namesake book forms the basis for the holiday Purim.",
		"answers": [
			"Esther",
			"Hadassah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"woman",
			"set",
			"precedent",
			"for",
			"conversion",
			"and",
			"familial",
			"piety",
			"in",
			"her",
			"namesake",
			"book",
			"by",
			"telling",
			"mother-in-law",
			"that",
			"your",
			"people",
			"shall",
			"be",
			"my",
			"God"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Australia[10] The Tjurunga cannot be approached by people who have not undergone this rite. Women, foreigners, and children who have not come of age cannot undergo this.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 17 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer these questions about totems called Tjurungu (\"chuh-ROON-guh\"), for 10 points each: [10] Tjurunga are spiritual totems of indigenous people from this country. Those people are collectively known as \"Aborigines.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Australia",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Tjurunga"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Haile Selassie I [accept Tafari Makonnen Woldimikael][10] Adherents of this movement believe Haile Selassie to be the messiah. Practices in this faith include the dietary law of ital and the religious use of cannabis.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 16 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man's arrival in Jamaica is celebrated as Grounation Day. For 10 points each: [10] Name this final Ethiopian emperor, whom a certain faith believes to be the incarnate of the Jah and will lead the righteous to create Zion.",
		"answers": [
			"Haile",
			"Selassie",
			"I",
			"Tafari",
			"Makonnen",
			"Woldimikael",
			"10",
			"Adherents",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"believe",
			"to",
			"be",
			"messiah",
			"Practices",
			"in",
			"faith",
			"include",
			"dietary",
			"law",
			"ital",
			"and",
			"religious",
			"use",
			"cannabis"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Bahá'í Faith [accept Bahá'íyyah][10] The Bahá'í Faith was founded by Bahá'u'lláh, who had been a follower of this mystic who claimed to be the Mahdi of Islam. He was executed by firing squad for apostasy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 20 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This religion's founder described his journey to enlightenment in The Seven Valleys. For 10 points each: [10] Name this monotheistic religion which claims that most major religions have been inspired by the same God.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Bahá'í",
			"Faith",
			"Bahá'íyyah",
			"10",
			"The",
			"was",
			"founded",
			"by",
			"Bahá'u'lláh",
			"who",
			"had",
			"been",
			"follower",
			"this",
			"mystic",
			"claimed",
			"to",
			"be",
			"Mahdi",
			"Islam",
			"He",
			"executed",
			"firing",
			"squad",
			"for",
			"apostasy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Samsara[10] This concept refers to liberation from the cycle of Samsara; in Hinduism, this concept allows one to leave behind mundane things and rejoin with Brahman.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Buddhism, Hinduism, and Jainism share similar concepts of enlightenment. For 10 points each: [10] Name this endless cycle of birth, death, and rebirth that translates from Sanskrit as \"Journeying.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Samsara",
			"10",
			"This",
			"concept",
			"refers",
			"to",
			"liberation",
			"from",
			"cycle",
			"in",
			"Hinduism",
			"this",
			"allows",
			"one",
			"leave",
			"behind",
			"mundane",
			"things",
			"and",
			"rejoin",
			"with",
			"Brahman"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shabbat [or Shabbos][10] Shabbat is commenced using two of these objects, over which the head female of the household typically says a blessing.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 17 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: It is said that manna did not fall on this day, and people who observe this day are prohibited from building, writing, or transporting property across boundaries. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Jewish day of rest, which falls on the seventh of every week.",
		"answers": [
			"Shabbat",
			"Shabbos",
			"10",
			"commenced",
			"using",
			"two",
			"these",
			"objects",
			"over",
			"which",
			"head",
			"female",
			"household",
			"typically",
			"says",
			"blessing"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Voodoo [accept Vodun][10] These spirits in Voodoo have no creative power like Bondye, but their nanchons rule every physical and social realm. They include figures like Marinette, Agwé, and Baron Samedi.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 6 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Religious figures in this religion are called houngan and mambo, if male or female respectively. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Haitian religion that syncretized West African and Catholic beliefs, famous for its namesake \"dolls.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Voodoo",
			"Vodun",
			"10",
			"These",
			"spirits",
			"in",
			"have",
			"no",
			"creative",
			"power",
			"Bondye",
			"but",
			"their",
			"nanchons",
			"rule",
			"every",
			"physical",
			"and",
			"social",
			"realm",
			"They",
			"include",
			"figures",
			"Marinette",
			"Agwé",
			"Baron",
			"Samedi"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zen or Ch'an Buddhism[10] Koans in this 13th century collection published by the monk Wumen include the stories of Gutei's finger and the lack of Bodhidharma's beard. It is often cited with the Blue Cliff Record as a major source of koans.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 20 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Koans from the Rinzai sect of this religion include \"does a dog have the Buddha's nature\", and \"what was your face before your parents were born?\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this primarily Japanese sect of Buddhism which emphasizes the use of koans to achieve enlightenment. Enlightenment may also be achieved through strict meditation.",
		"answers": [
			"Zen",
			"Ch'an",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"Koans",
			"in",
			"this",
			"13th",
			"century",
			"collection",
			"published",
			"by",
			"monk",
			"Wumen",
			"include",
			"stories",
			"Gutei's",
			"finger",
			"and",
			"lack",
			"Bodhidharma's",
			"beard",
			"It",
			"often",
			"cited",
			"with",
			"Blue",
			"Cliff",
			"Record",
			"as",
			"major",
			"source",
			"koans"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vodou (pronounced \"Voodoo\"; accept Vodun) [10] These spirits are venerated in Vodou. They are represented by vÃ©vÃ© symbols, which act as beacons to them.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 2 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Priestesses in this religion are called mambo and priests are called houngan. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this religion based in Haiti with African and Catholic elements. It is associated by many people with the sticking of pins into dolls to curse people.",
		"answers": [
			"Vodou",
			"pronounced",
			"Voodoo",
			"Vodun",
			"10",
			"These",
			"spirits",
			"are",
			"venerated",
			"in",
			"They",
			"represented",
			"by",
			"vÃ©vÃ©",
			"symbols",
			"which",
			"act",
			"as",
			"beacons",
			"to",
			"them"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Abraham or Abram[10] Sarah asked Abraham to cast out this handmaid following the birth of Isaac. She was the mother of Abraham's firstborn son, Ishmael.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 8 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man was told that his descendants would be \"as numerous as the stars in the sky.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this patriarch of some namesake monotheistic religions who once claimed that his wife, Sarah, was actually his sister. He also nearly sacrificed their only son, Isaac, to God.",
		"answers": [
			"Abraham",
			"Abram",
			"10",
			"Sarah",
			"asked",
			"to",
			"cast",
			"out",
			"this",
			"handmaid",
			"following",
			"birth",
			"Isaac",
			"She",
			"was",
			"mother",
			"Abraham's",
			"firstborn",
			"son",
			"Ishmael"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Dead Sea Scrolls[10] This manuscript was the first comprehensive translation of the Bible into Latin from Hebrew, and was made by St. Jerome. It replaced the Vetus Latina.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 11 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: There are many manuscripts associated with parts of the Bible. For 10 points each:  [10] These Hebrew manuscripts were found on the shore of a body of water near the present-day West Bank, and are named for that location. ",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Dead",
			"Sea",
			"Scrolls",
			"10",
			"This",
			"manuscript",
			"was",
			"first",
			"comprehensive",
			"translation",
			"Bible",
			"into",
			"Latin",
			"from",
			"Hebrew",
			"and",
			"made",
			"by",
			"St",
			"Jerome",
			"It",
			"replaced",
			"Vetus",
			"Latina"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gurus[10] Gurus are from this religion which originated in Punjab in the 15th Century. Most male followers wear turbans and are prohibited from cutting their hair.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 10 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The last and eternal one of these figures is a book written entirely in song, the Adi Granth. For 10 points each: [10] Name this group of ten religious figures which began with Nanak Dev.",
		"answers": [
			"gurus",
			"10",
			"Gurus",
			"are",
			"from",
			"this",
			"religion",
			"which",
			"originated",
			"in",
			"Punjab",
			"15th",
			"Century",
			"Most",
			"male",
			"followers",
			"wear",
			"turbans",
			"and",
			"prohibited",
			"cutting",
			"their",
			"hair"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lent[10] In the Catholic church and many other denominations, Lent ends on this day. This day commemorates the Last Supper, and priests traditionally wash the feet of their parishioners on this day.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: It commemorates the 40 days that Jesus fasted in the desert and was tempted by the Devil. For 10 points each: [10] ] Name this period of the Christian calendar that starts on Ash Wednesday and lasts for forty days. Christians often \"give up\" something during this time.",
		"answers": [
			"Lent",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Catholic",
			"church",
			"and",
			"many",
			"other",
			"denominations",
			"ends",
			"this",
			"day",
			"This",
			"commemorates",
			"Last",
			"Supper",
			"priests",
			"traditionally",
			"wash",
			"feet",
			"their",
			"parishioners"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nation of Islam (accept NOI; do not accept or prompt on \"Islam\")[10] The Nation of Islam differs from conventional Islam in believing that there was an additional messenger of Allah after this man, who is ordinarily considered the final prophet. The angel Gabriel dictated the Qur'an to this man.",
		"prompts": [
			"Islam",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"differs",
			"from",
			"conventional",
			"Islam",
			"in",
			"believing",
			"that",
			"there",
			"was",
			"an",
			"additional",
			"messenger",
			"Allah",
			"after",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"ordinarily",
			"considered",
			"final",
			"prophet",
			"The",
			"angel",
			"Gabriel",
			"dictated",
			"Qur'an",
			"to",
			"this",
			"man"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 7 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this predominantly African-American faith founded by Wallace D. Fard. It is presently led by Louis Farrakhan, and Malcolm X was once an adherent of it.",
		"answers": [
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"NOI"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "People of the Book [or Ahl-al-Kitab; or dhimmi; or zimm][10] Zakat, the pillar of Islam mandating this activity, is replaced for People of the Book by the jizya tax. The standard amount for the zakat type of it is 2.5 percent of one's income.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 7 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: All definitions of this concept exclude Baha'i, since that faith emerged after Muhammad, and Persian dynasties varied on whether Zoroastrians count as this type of person. For 10 points each: [10] Name this class in Islamic society, the set of non-Muslims who, in contrast to infidels, retained some freedoms because they also believe in the Abrahamic god.",
		"answers": [
			"People",
			"Book",
			"Ahl-al-Kitab",
			"dhimmi",
			"zimm",
			"10",
			"Zakat",
			"pillar",
			"Islam",
			"mandating",
			"this",
			"activity",
			"replaced",
			"for",
			"by",
			"jizya",
			"tax",
			"The",
			"standard",
			"amount",
			"zakat",
			"type",
			"2",
			"5",
			"percent",
			"one's",
			"income"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Jainism[10]  This cycle of life, death, and reincarnation is a central concept in Indian religions such as Jainism, Buddhism, and Hinduism. It is ended by moksha.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 14 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Indian religion emphasizing a strict view of ahimsa, or non-violence. Monks of this religion observe five vows or the Mahavrata, including ahimsa, satya, and aparigraha.",
		"answers": [
			"Jainism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"cycle",
			"life",
			"death",
			"and",
			"reincarnation",
			"central",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"Indian",
			"religions",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Buddhism",
			"Hinduism",
			"It",
			"ended",
			"by",
			"moksha"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "turban [accept pagri, bulle, or dastar][10]  Worn by Muslim women, it is a full-body covering meant to fulfill the requirements of hijab. Some say that the veil portion of this garment is unnecessary in the presence of blind or gay men.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 20 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This head covering is worn by Sikh men, in part to cover their uncut hair. In Kenya, the Akurinu wear these, and pink ones are worn in India for marriage ceremonies.",
		"answers": [
			"turban",
			"pagri",
			"bulle",
			"dastar",
			"10",
			"Worn",
			"by",
			"Muslim",
			"women",
			"full-body",
			"covering",
			"meant",
			"to",
			"fulfill",
			"requirements",
			"hijab",
			"Some",
			"say",
			"that",
			"veil",
			"portion",
			"this",
			"garment",
			"unnecessary",
			"in",
			"presence",
			"blind",
			"gay",
			"men"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gabriel[10]  This archangel and Gabriel are the only ones mentioned in the Qur'an. He is the patron saint of the military, police force, paramedics, and the city of Brussels. He leads God's army into battle against Satan in the Book of Revelation.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 17 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This angel revealed the Qur'an to Muhammad over twenty-three years. In Mormonism, he and Noah are the same being. He is known for foretelling the birth of John the Baptist and Jesus Christ.",
		"answers": [
			"Gabriel",
			"10",
			"This",
			"archangel",
			"and",
			"are",
			"only",
			"ones",
			"in",
			"Qur'an",
			"He",
			"patron",
			"saint",
			"military",
			"police",
			"force",
			"paramedics",
			"city",
			"Brussels",
			"leads",
			"God's",
			"army",
			"into",
			"battle",
			"against",
			"Satan",
			"Book",
			"Revelation"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gnosticism[10]  One prominent symbol of Gnosticism is the \"sun\" type of this symbol. A \"Greek\" type of this symbol has four equal-length arms and symbolizes the Eastern Orthodox church.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 18 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this movement which believes in Sophia, an embodiment of wisdom who births an imperfect demiurge which then creates the universe. This religion derives its name from the Greek word for \"knowledge\".",
		"answers": [
			"Gnosticism",
			"10",
			"One",
			"prominent",
			"symbol",
			"sun",
			"type",
			"this",
			"A",
			"Greek",
			"has",
			"four",
			"equal-length",
			"arms",
			"and",
			"symbolizes",
			"Eastern",
			"Orthodox",
			"church"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Baha'i[10]  This is the primary text of the Baha'i faith. It includes a passage known as the \"Tablet of the True Seeker,\" and is also known as the Book of Iqan.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 6 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this religion that teaches of divine messengers including Moses, the Buddha, and Mohammed, the most recent ones being the Bab and Baha'u'llah.",
		"answers": [
			"Baha'i",
			"10",
			"This",
			"primary",
			"text",
			"faith",
			"It",
			"includes",
			"passage",
			"known",
			"as",
			"Tablet",
			"True",
			"Seeker",
			"and",
			"also",
			"Book",
			"Iqan"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Palm Sunday [accept Passion Sunday][10]  This was final meal Jesus had with his apostles. Jesus foresaw a betrayal from one of his disciples, washed their feet, and predicted that St. Peter would deny knowing him at this event.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 6 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Commemorating Jesus' entry into Jerusalem, riding a donkey while others shouted \"Hosanna!,\" it is celebrated by the distribution of its namesake branches to celebrators, although yew or willow are also used.",
		"answers": [
			"Palm",
			"Sunday",
			"Passion",
			"10",
			"This",
			"was",
			"final",
			"meal",
			"Jesus",
			"had",
			"with",
			"his",
			"apostles",
			"foresaw",
			"betrayal",
			"from",
			"one",
			"disciples",
			"washed",
			"their",
			"feet",
			"and",
			"predicted",
			"that",
			"St",
			"Peter",
			"would",
			"deny",
			"knowing",
			"him",
			"at",
			"this",
			"event"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lent [accept Quadragesima][10]  This month of fasting precedes Shawaal. Laylat al-Qadr occurred during this month, during which meals called suhoor and iftar are eaten before dawn and at sunset, respectively.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 20 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Abstinence from animal products was formerly daily during these forty days, but in modern times is generally observed on Fridays. Ash Wednesday, a day of fasting, marks the beginning of this holiday that ends before Easter.",
		"answers": [
			"Lent",
			"Quadragesima",
			"10",
			"This",
			"month",
			"fasting",
			"precedes",
			"Shawaal",
			"Laylat",
			"al-Qadr",
			"occurred",
			"during",
			"this",
			"which",
			"meals",
			"called",
			"suhoor",
			"and",
			"iftar",
			"are",
			"eaten",
			"dawn",
			"at",
			"sunset",
			"respectively"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zoroastrianism [prompt on \"Mazdaism\" or \"Magianism\"][10]  This is the primary sacred text of Zoroastrianism, containing the Yasnas and the Gathas.",
		"prompts": [
			"Mazdaism",
			"Magianism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"primary",
			"sacred",
			"text",
			"Zoroastrianism",
			"containing",
			"Yasnas",
			"and",
			"Gathas"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 8 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this religion teaching that Ahura Mazda will eventually prevail over the evil Angra Mainyu, whose practitioners may expose corpses on a Tower of Silence before cremating them.",
		"answers": [
			"Zoroastrianism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "voodoo [accept vodoun or vodon][10]  In voodoo, these beings are emissaries of Bondye, as he is too great to directly intervene in human lives. Nanchons of these include Ghede, Petro, Kongo, and Rada.  People \"mounted\" or possessed by these are called \"horses.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 11 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This syncretic chief religion of Haiti believes in a supreme god called Bondye. A temple in this religion is called a Hounfour, and female priests are called Mambos.",
		"answers": [
			"voodoo",
			"vodoun",
			"vodon",
			"10",
			"In",
			"these",
			"beings",
			"are",
			"emissaries",
			"Bondye",
			"as",
			"he",
			"too",
			"great",
			"to",
			"directly",
			"intervene",
			"in",
			"human",
			"lives",
			"Nanchons",
			"include",
			"Ghede",
			"Petro",
			"Kongo",
			"and",
			"Rada",
			"People",
			"mounted",
			"possessed",
			"by",
			"called",
			"horses"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shia Islam [or Shi'ites][10]  This sect of Shia Islam is represented by a five-point star, and is centered in Lebanon and Syria. They are divided into the uqqal and the jahhal. Unlike other sects, adherents are not required to observe most religious rituals.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 5 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This second largest branch of Islam believes that Muhammad's successor was his son-in-law, the first imam. The Alavis, Ismaili, and Zaidi are part of this branch.",
		"answers": [
			"Shia",
			"Islam",
			"Shi'ites",
			"10",
			"This",
			"sect",
			"represented",
			"by",
			"five-point",
			"star",
			"and",
			"centered",
			"in",
			"Lebanon",
			"Syria",
			"They",
			"are",
			"divided",
			"into",
			"uqqal",
			"jahhal",
			"Unlike",
			"other",
			"sects",
			"adherents"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "circumcision[10]  This is the Jewish term for ritual circumcision, in which the kvatter carries the baby from the parents to the mohel. After this ceremony, participants are compelled to attend a seudat mitzvah.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 17 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this surgical action which Jesus underwent when he was 8 days old, which resulted in the Holy Prepuce. Some Indigenous Australians have this procedure as well as subincision as part of rites of passage.",
		"answers": [
			"circumcision",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Jewish",
			"term",
			"for",
			"ritual",
			"in",
			"which",
			"kvatter",
			"carries",
			"baby",
			"from",
			"parents",
			"to",
			"mohel",
			"After",
			"this",
			"ceremony",
			"participants",
			"are",
			"compelled",
			"attend",
			"seudat",
			"mitzvah"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nation of Islam (accept NOI; do not accept or prompt on \"Islam\")[10]  The Nation of Islam differs from conventional Islam in believing that there was an additional messenger of Allah after this man, who is ordinarily considered the final prophet. The angel Gabriel dictated the Qur'an to this man.",
		"prompts": [
			"Islam",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"differs",
			"from",
			"conventional",
			"Islam",
			"in",
			"believing",
			"that",
			"there",
			"was",
			"an",
			"additional",
			"messenger",
			"Allah",
			"after",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"ordinarily",
			"considered",
			"final",
			"prophet",
			"The",
			"angel",
			"Gabriel",
			"dictated",
			"Qur'an",
			"to",
			"this",
			"man"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 7 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this predominantly African-American faith founded by Wallace D. Fard. It is presently led by Louis Farrakhan, and Malcolm X was once an adherent of it.",
		"answers": [
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"NOI"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sermon on the Mount (or Sermo in Monte)[10]  The Sermon on the Mount is found in this first of the four Gospels. Its presumed author was a tax collector from Capernaum.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 2 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this collection of teachings given by Jesus from a large hill, which also contains the Beatitudes.",
		"answers": [
			"Sermon",
			"Mount",
			"Sermo",
			"in",
			"Monte",
			"10",
			"The",
			"found",
			"this",
			"first",
			"four",
			"Gospels",
			"Its",
			"presumed",
			"author",
			"was",
			"tax",
			"collector",
			"from",
			"Capernaum"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Years (accept obvious equivalents)[10]  Like at Yom Kippur, services at Rosh Hashanah often include the blowing of this ram's horn.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 5 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Rosh Hashanah is a holiday celebrating one of these annual occurrences, which occurs on January 1 in the Gregorian calendar. The Chinese celebrate a \"Lunar\" one of these in February.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Years",
			"obvious",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"Like",
			"at",
			"Yom",
			"Kippur",
			"services",
			"Rosh",
			"Hashanah",
			"often",
			"include",
			"blowing",
			"this",
			"ram's",
			"horn"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "kirpan[10]  The kirpan is one of the Five Ks of this religion, whose male members are required to wear turbans. This religion follows the teachings of eleven gurus, including its founder, Guru Nanak.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 4 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this religiously symbolic dagger which is used to stir a sugar and water mixture during the baptism ceremony of a certain religion.",
		"answers": [
			"kirpan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"one",
			"Five",
			"Ks",
			"this",
			"religion",
			"whose",
			"male",
			"members",
			"are",
			"required",
			"to",
			"wear",
			"turbans",
			"This",
			"follows",
			"teachings",
			"eleven",
			"gurus",
			"including",
			"its",
			"founder",
			"Guru",
			"Nanak"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "seder[10]  The seder is a meal during this holiday, which celebrates the exodus of Jews from slavery in Egypt.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 11 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this festive event occurring on the 14th of Nisan, which marks the beginning of a certain weeklong holiday. During it, the youngest child asks the Four Questions, and it includes the hiding of the matzah afikomen.",
		"answers": [
			"seder",
			"10",
			"The",
			"meal",
			"during",
			"this",
			"holiday",
			"which",
			"celebrates",
			"exodus",
			"Jews",
			"from",
			"slavery",
			"in",
			"Egypt"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "names of God (accept answers specifying a Jewish God or Islamic God; prompt on \"names of Allah\")[10]  This mystical sect of Islam highly encourages dhikr and other forms of devotion to Allah. This group's dervishes also engage in a notable \"whirling\" dance.",
		"prompts": [
			"names",
			"Allah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"mystical",
			"sect",
			"Islam",
			"highly",
			"encourages",
			"dhikr",
			"and",
			"other",
			"forms",
			"devotion",
			"to",
			"Allah",
			"This",
			"group's",
			"dervishes",
			"also",
			"engage",
			"in",
			"notable",
			"whirling",
			"dance"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 13 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify these types of words, other examples of which include the Tetragrammaton YHWH (\"yah-weh\") and Adonai.",
		"answers": [
			"names",
			"God",
			"specifying",
			"Jewish",
			"Islamic"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mahayana Buddhism[10]  This highest-ranking lama leads the Yellow-hat Buddhists. The current holder of this position is Tenzin Gyatso, who used to lead the Tibetan government-in-exile.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 15 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Tibetan Buddhism is an offshoot of this \"Great Vehicle\" branch of Buddhism, which is often contrasted with the Theravada school.",
		"answers": [
			"Mahayana",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"highest-ranking",
			"lama",
			"leads",
			"Yellow-hat",
			"Buddhists",
			"The",
			"current",
			"holder",
			"this",
			"position",
			"Tenzin",
			"Gyatso",
			"who",
			"used",
			"to",
			"lead",
			"Tibetan",
			"government-in-exile"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Purim[10]  This wintertime Jewish \"festival of lights\" begins on the 25th of Kislev and commemorates the Maccabees' defeat of Antiochus and the re-dedication of the Temple. It sees the lighting of a nine-branched menorah.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 10 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This holiday celebrates the foiling of the evil Haman's plot by Esther and Mordechai.",
		"answers": [
			"Purim",
			"10",
			"This",
			"wintertime",
			"Jewish",
			"festival",
			"lights",
			"begins",
			"25th",
			"Kislev",
			"and",
			"commemorates",
			"Maccabees'",
			"defeat",
			"Antiochus",
			"re-dedication",
			"Temple",
			"It",
			"sees",
			"lighting",
			"nine-branched",
			"menorah"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Lord's Prayer  (accept Our Father or Pater Noster)[10]  The Lord's prayer is often said before this sacrament, whose participants take bread and wine that, according to the Catholic and Orthodox churches, have been transubstantiated into the body and blood of Christ.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 19 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Christian prayer which asks the title figure to \"forgive us our trespasses\" and to \"lead us not to temptation, but deliver us from evil\".",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Lord's",
			"Prayer",
			"Our",
			"Father",
			"Pater",
			"Noster",
			"10",
			"prayer",
			"often",
			"said",
			"this",
			"sacrament",
			"whose",
			"participants",
			"take",
			"bread",
			"and",
			"wine",
			"that",
			"according",
			"to",
			"Catholic",
			"Orthodox",
			"churches",
			"have",
			"been",
			"transubstantiated",
			"into",
			"body",
			"blood",
			"Christ"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ramadan[10]  The practice of fasting is referred to by this Arabic word, one of the Five Pillars of Islam. It refers to total abstinence from things such as food, drinking, marital relations, and swearing during the day.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 7 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this month of the Islamic calendar, during which able-bodied Muslims fast from dawn to dusk.",
		"answers": [
			"Ramadan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"practice",
			"fasting",
			"referred",
			"to",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Arabic",
			"word",
			"one",
			"Five",
			"Pillars",
			"Islam",
			"It",
			"refers",
			"total",
			"abstinence",
			"from",
			"things",
			"such",
			"as",
			"food",
			"drinking",
			"marital",
			"relations",
			"and",
			"swearing",
			"during",
			"day"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "battle tanks[10]  The tanks central to the Nazi technique of Blitzkrieg during World War II were typically referred to by this name, the German word for \"armor.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 18 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify these armored battle vehicles which typically have a turreted main gun and move around on treads. They were first used in World War I at the Battle of the Somme.",
		"answers": [
			"battle",
			"tanks",
			"10",
			"The",
			"central",
			"to",
			"Nazi",
			"technique",
			"Blitzkrieg",
			"during",
			"World",
			"War",
			"II",
			"were",
			"typically",
			"referred",
			"by",
			"this",
			"name",
			"German",
			"word",
			"for",
			"armor"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Laozi or Lao-Tsu[10]  Laozi was the founder of this Asian religion, the symbol of which is the black and white circle of yin and yang, and whose text is the Tao Te Ching.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 16 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this sixth century BC figure, whom Tang emperors claimed descent from. This founder of a certain religion is believed to be one of the Three Pure Ones, and he supposedly lived in his mother's womb for 70 years.",
		"answers": [
			"Laozi",
			"Lao-Tsu",
			"10",
			"was",
			"founder",
			"this",
			"Asian",
			"religion",
			"symbol",
			"which",
			"black",
			"and",
			"white",
			"circle",
			"yin",
			"yang",
			"whose",
			"text",
			"Tao",
			"Te",
			"Ching"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Druze[10]  The Druze have flag and star have this many points and colors. This is the number of Pillars of Islam and books in the Torah.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 8 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this primarily Middle Eastern faith, whose seven pillars include telling the truth and protecting one's fellow adherents. It evolved from Ismailism, and is predominantly practiced in Syria and Lebanon.",
		"answers": [
			"Druze",
			"10",
			"The",
			"have",
			"flag",
			"and",
			"star",
			"this",
			"many",
			"points",
			"colors",
			"This",
			"number",
			"Pillars",
			"Islam",
			"books",
			"in",
			"Torah"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Exodus[10]  This last of the ten plagues was the most deadly and persuaded the Pharaoh to let Moses and his people out of Egypt. The Israelites marked their doorposts with lamb's blood to avoid this plague.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 8 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]   Name this book that follows Genesis and describes the flight of the Israelites from Egypt. In this book, Moses destroys the golden calf that the Israelites worshipped and acquires the Ten Commandments on Mt. Sinai.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Exodus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"last",
			"ten",
			"plagues",
			"was",
			"most",
			"deadly",
			"and",
			"persuaded",
			"Pharaoh",
			"to",
			"let",
			"Moses",
			"his",
			"people",
			"out",
			"Egypt",
			"The",
			"Israelites",
			"marked",
			"their",
			"doorposts",
			"with",
			"lamb's",
			"blood",
			"avoid",
			"this",
			"plague"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rastafarianism (or Rastas)[10]  In a Reasoning ceremony, a circle of Rastafari sit and smoke this drug in order to communicate with their god.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 1 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this religion originating in Jamaica, whose adherents follow the ital (\"eye-tal\") diet and typically have dreadlocks. Bob Marley was a notable proponent of this religion.",
		"answers": [
			"Rastafarianism",
			"Rastas",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Reasoning",
			"ceremony",
			"circle",
			"Rastafari",
			"sit",
			"and",
			"smoke",
			"this",
			"drug",
			"in",
			"order",
			"to",
			"communicate",
			"with",
			"their",
			"god"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Revelation (or Revelation of St. John; or Apocalypse of John; do not accept \"Revelations\" in place of \"Revelation\")[10]  Revelation begins by addressing this number of churches in Asia and then details the opening of this many seals, the sounding of this many trumpets, and the rising of a beast with this many heads.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 18 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this text written by John of Patmos, which details the Second Coming of Christ and is generally agreed to be the last book of the Bible.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Revelation",
			"St",
			"John",
			"Apocalypse"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pagodas [or tǎ; or buttō; or tōba][10] This Hindu destroyer god with a third eye can be worshipped by pouring perfume or honey onto a stone stump  called a linga.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 1 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 1. Answer these questions about vertical objects used to venerate divine beings in Eastern religions, for 10 points  each. [10] These multi-story, multi-roofed towers are commonly built to serve as Buddhist temples in China and Japan.",
		"answers": [
			"pagodas",
			"tǎ",
			"buttō",
			"tōba",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Hindu",
			"destroyer",
			"god",
			"with",
			"third",
			"eye",
			"can",
			"be",
			"worshipped",
			"by",
			"pouring",
			"perfume",
			"honey",
			"onto",
			"stone",
			"stump",
			"called",
			"linga"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pagodas [or tǎ; or buttō; or tōba][10] This Hindu destroyer god with a third eye can be worshipped by pouring perfume or honey onto a stone stump  called a linga.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 1 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 1. Answer these questions about vertical objects used to venerate divine beings in Eastern religions, for 10 points  each. [10] These multi-story, multi-roofed towers are commonly built to serve as Buddhist temples in China and Japan.",
		"answers": [
			"pagodas",
			"tǎ",
			"buttō",
			"tōba",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Hindu",
			"destroyer",
			"god",
			"with",
			"third",
			"eye",
			"can",
			"be",
			"worshipped",
			"by",
			"pouring",
			"perfume",
			"honey",
			"onto",
			"stone",
			"stump",
			"called",
			"linga"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sufism [accept tasawwuf][10] The Mevlevi order of Sufism practices this as a form of Sama, or observance of dhikr. Sufis in the Western  world are often known for performing this action, which resembles the motion of a dreidel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about Islamic mysticism, for 10 points each: [10] Practitioners of this form of Islam often perform dhikr, the repeating of the name of God. Its many schools span  the entire Muslim world, and its followers are sometimes called dervishes.",
		"answers": [
			"Sufism",
			"tasawwuf",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Mevlevi",
			"order",
			"practices",
			"this",
			"as",
			"form",
			"Sama",
			"observance",
			"dhikr",
			"Sufis",
			"in",
			"Western",
			"world",
			"are",
			"often",
			"known",
			"for",
			"performing",
			"action",
			"which",
			"resembles",
			"motion",
			"dreidel"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gospel According to Luke [accept Gospel of Luke][10] The Gospel of Luke contains this statement, that one should do unto others what he would have others do unto  him.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 2 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This book contains the text of the Magnificat hymn. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Synoptic Gospel that shares much of its content with that of Mark, and which is the third of the  canonical gospels. It also contains the story of the Good Samaritan.",
		"answers": [
			"Gospel",
			"According",
			"to",
			"Luke",
			"10",
			"The",
			"contains",
			"this",
			"statement",
			"that",
			"one",
			"should",
			"unto",
			"others",
			"what",
			"he",
			"would",
			"have",
			"him"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Deuteronomy [accept Devarim or Eleh ha-devarim][10] ] The speeches in Deuteronomy were given by this figure, who battled with the Amalekites along with Joshua and his brother Aaron. He led the Jews on the Exodus and received the Ten Commandments on Mount Sinai.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 17 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This book contains the Shema, a phrase recited in Jewish prayer services. For 10 points each: [10] Name this fifth book of the Torah, which contains speeches given before the entry of the Jews into the Promised Land. Its Hebrew name means \"these are the words\" and  it puts forth many of the Torah's laws.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Deuteronomy",
			"Devarim",
			"Eleh",
			"ha-devarim",
			"10",
			"The",
			"speeches",
			"in",
			"were",
			"given",
			"by",
			"this",
			"figure",
			"who",
			"battled",
			"with",
			"Amalekites",
			"along",
			"Joshua",
			"and",
			"his",
			"brother",
			"Aaron",
			"He",
			"led",
			"Jews",
			"Exodus",
			"received",
			"Ten",
			"Commandments",
			"Mount",
			"Sinai"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shinto [or kami-no-michi][10] Along with Shinto, this branch of Buddhism plays a major role in Japanese culture. Unlike its \"smaller vehicle\" counterpart, adherents of this branch venerate bodhisattvas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 10 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many Japanese identify themselves as members of multiple religions. Answer some questions about those religions, for 10 points each. [10] This religion, native to Japan, is polytheistic, and incorporates the veneration of spirits known as kami. Holy places in this religion include shrines like Kizomizu, and feature tori gates. Deities venerated in this religion include Susanoo and Ame-no-Uzume.",
		"answers": [
			"Shinto",
			"kami-no-michi",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"this",
			"branch",
			"Buddhism",
			"plays",
			"major",
			"role",
			"in",
			"Japanese",
			"culture",
			"Unlike",
			"its",
			"smaller",
			"vehicle",
			"counterpart",
			"adherents",
			"venerate",
			"bodhisattvas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shinto [or kami-no-michi][10] Along with Shinto, this branch of Buddhism plays a major role in Japanese culture. Unlike its \"smaller vehicle\" counterpart, adherents of this branch venerate bodhisattvas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 10 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many Japanese identify themselves as members of multiple religions. Answer some questions about those religions, for 10 points each. [10] This religion, native to Japan, is polytheistic, and incorporates the veneration of spirits known as kami. Holy places in this religion include shrines like Kizomizu, and feature tori gates. Deities venerated in this religion include Susanoo and Ame-no-Uzume.",
		"answers": [
			"Shinto",
			"kami-no-michi",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"this",
			"branch",
			"Buddhism",
			"plays",
			"major",
			"role",
			"in",
			"Japanese",
			"culture",
			"Unlike",
			"its",
			"smaller",
			"vehicle",
			"counterpart",
			"adherents",
			"venerate",
			"bodhisattvas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Deborah[10] This Nazirite Judge told Delilah, a Philistine spy, that his hair was the source of his prodigious strength; she then subsequently betrayed him by shaving his head.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 7 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some Biblical Judges, for 10 points each. [10] This Judge joined forces with the Israelite general Barak to take down the Canaanite general Sisera in battle. The writer of a namesake \"song,\" she gave judgments under a palm tree and was female.",
		"answers": [
			"Deborah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Nazirite",
			"Judge",
			"told",
			"Delilah",
			"Philistine",
			"spy",
			"that",
			"his",
			"hair",
			"was",
			"source",
			"prodigious",
			"strength",
			"she",
			"then",
			"subsequently",
			"betrayed",
			"him",
			"by",
			"shaving",
			"head"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Pyrenees Mountains [or Pirineos; or Pyrénées; or Perinés; or Pirineus; or Pirenèus; or Pirinioak; or Auñamendiak][10] This mountain range runs the length of the Italian peninsula and is home to the rapidly-shrinking Calderone glacier. The small nation of San Marino is located around Monte Titano in this range.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 10 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some European mountain ranges. [10] This mountain range divides France from Spain. The tiny nation of Andorra lies in these mountains, which run from the Bay of Biscay to the Cap de Creus.",
		"answers": [
			"Pyrenees",
			"Mountains",
			"Pirineos",
			"Pyrénées",
			"Perinés",
			"Pirineus",
			"Pirenèus",
			"Pirinioak",
			"Auñamendiak",
			"10",
			"This",
			"mountain",
			"range",
			"runs",
			"length",
			"Italian",
			"peninsula",
			"and",
			"home",
			"to",
			"rapidly-shrinking",
			"Calderone",
			"glacier",
			"The",
			"small",
			"nation",
			"San",
			"Marino",
			"located",
			"around",
			"Monte",
			"Titano",
			"in",
			"this"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mississippi River[10] This lake in Minnesota is often cited as the source of the main length of the Mississippi River.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 7 | 1 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this longest river in the United States. Its major tributaries include the Ohio and Missouri.",
		"answers": [
			"Mississippi",
			"River",
			"10",
			"This",
			"lake",
			"in",
			"Minnesota",
			"often",
			"cited",
			"as",
			"source",
			"main",
			"length"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hawaii Island[10] This most populous of the Hawaiian islands is the home of Honolulu.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 7 | 2 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this largest of James Cook's \"Sandwich Islands.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Hawaii",
			"Island",
			"10",
			"This",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"Hawaiian",
			"islands",
			"home",
			"Honolulu"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lesser Antilles [prompt on Antilles] [10] The Lesser Antilles can be found in this sea. Europeans called islands in this sea the West Indies",
		"prompts": [
			"Antilles",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Lesser",
			"Antilles",
			"can",
			"be",
			"found",
			"in",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"Europeans",
			"called",
			"islands",
			"in",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"West",
			"Indies"
		],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 19 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One member of this chain of islands is a lifeless rock named Redonda whose second-to-last king \"Robert the Bald\" was succeeded by \"Michael the Grey\" in 2009. For 10 points each:  [10] Redonda, which belongs to Antigua and Barbuda, is a member of the Leeward Islands, which makes up this island chain along with the Windward Islands. ",
		"answers": [
			"Lesser",
			"Antilles"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "French Indochina[10] Led by the Chakri dynasty, this country was the only Southeast Asian country to escape colonization. It lost Laos and the Malay peninsula to the French and British, respectively, and retains its monarchy today.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 13 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name the following about Southeast Asia during the colonial period. [10] This French colony included the present-day countries of Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia. These countries became independent in 1954, following the Geneva accords, despite French military intervention.",
		"answers": [
			"French",
			"Indochina",
			"10",
			"Led",
			"by",
			"Chakri",
			"dynasty",
			"this",
			"country",
			"was",
			"only",
			"Southeast",
			"Asian",
			"to",
			"escape",
			"colonization",
			"It",
			"lost",
			"Laos",
			"and",
			"Malay",
			"peninsula",
			"British",
			"respectively",
			"retains",
			"its",
			"monarchy",
			"today"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nova Scotia[10] Nova Scotia is bordered to the west by this body of water, which has access to the Irving oil refinery and is located on a rift valley. St John's lies on it, and it separates most of New Brunswick from Nova Scotia.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 17 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer these questions about the maritime provinces, for 10 points each: [10] This province includes the traditionally-Scottish-inhabited Cape Breton Island, although its capital, Halifax, is on the mainland. French settlers from Acadia were deported from this place and it was renamed by the Brits in 1755.",
		"answers": [
			"Nova",
			"Scotia",
			"10",
			"bordered",
			"to",
			"west",
			"by",
			"this",
			"body",
			"water",
			"which",
			"has",
			"access",
			"Irving",
			"oil",
			"refinery",
			"and",
			"located",
			"rift",
			"valley",
			"St",
			"John's",
			"lies",
			"separates",
			"most",
			"New",
			"Brunswick",
			"from"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Berlin[10] To the southeast of Berlin is this capital of the state of Brandenburg that once served as the official seat of the Kaiser. A namesake declaration from this city called for Japan's unconditional surrender.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 20 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Its borough of Steglitz-Zehlendorf contains two bodies of water known as the greater and lesser Wannsees. For 10 points each: [10] Name this German capital city that contains the locality of Spandau and the Brandenburg Gate.",
		"answers": [
			"Berlin",
			"10",
			"To",
			"southeast",
			"this",
			"capital",
			"state",
			"Brandenburg",
			"that",
			"once",
			"served",
			"as",
			"official",
			"seat",
			"Kaiser",
			"A",
			"namesake",
			"declaration",
			"from",
			"city",
			"called",
			"for",
			"Japan's",
			"unconditional",
			"surrender"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Connecticut River[10] The Connecticut River passes just west of this capital city of Connecticut.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BISB |2013 | 2 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The so-called \"Great Attack\" occurred on this river during the War of 1812. For 10 points each: [10] Name this river which forms the border between New Hampshire and Vermont and reaches its terminus near Saybrook. It's the longest river in New England.",
		"answers": [
			"Connecticut",
			"River",
			"10",
			"The",
			"passes",
			"just",
			"west",
			"this",
			"capital",
			"city"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Great Bear Lake[10] The Great Bear Lake is located southwest of Nunavut in this Canadian territory. Settlements here include Inuvik and Hay River.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 6 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Uranium mining near this body of water has caused controversy and the town of Deline lies on its western shore. For 10 points each: [10] Name this lake, the largest located entirely within Canada.",
		"answers": [
			"Great",
			"Bear",
			"Lake",
			"10",
			"The",
			"located",
			"southwest",
			"Nunavut",
			"in",
			"this",
			"Canadian",
			"territory",
			"Settlements",
			"here",
			"include",
			"Inuvik",
			"and",
			"Hay",
			"River"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rio de la Plata[10] Sites in this capital city on one shore of the Rio de la Plata include the Prado and Rodo Parks and the Palacio Salvo.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 6 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some things related to a river in South America, for 10 points each: [10] This estuary is formed by the confluence of the Paraná and Uruguay Rivers.",
		"answers": [
			"Rio",
			"de",
			"la",
			"Plata",
			"10",
			"Sites",
			"in",
			"this",
			"capital",
			"city",
			"one",
			"shore",
			"include",
			"Prado",
			"and",
			"Rodo",
			"Parks",
			"Palacio",
			"Salvo"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bermuda[10] This other British Overseas territory located north of its namesake strait, is famous for its rock and monkeys, but is also a source of conflict between the UK and Spain.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Located 650 miles off Cape Hatteras, islands in this archipelago include Somerset Island and St. George's Island. For 10 points each: [10] Name this British Overseas Territory whose capital is Hamilton.",
		"answers": [
			"Bermuda",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"British",
			"Overseas",
			"territory",
			"located",
			"north",
			"its",
			"namesake",
			"strait",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"rock",
			"and",
			"monkeys",
			"but",
			"also",
			"source",
			"conflict",
			"between",
			"UK",
			"Spain"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yellowstone National Park[10] This geyser in Yellowstone, named in 1870 for its predicability, erupts approximately every 91 minutes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 1 | 10 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Roosevelt Arch lies at this park's northern entrance. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this national park, the first in the United States.",
		"answers": [
			"Yellowstone",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"10",
			"This",
			"geyser",
			"in",
			"named",
			"1870",
			"for",
			"its",
			"predicability",
			"erupts",
			"approximately",
			"every",
			"91",
			"minutes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New York City[10] This river is connected to the Hudson via the Spuyten Duyvil [Spooi-ten Dooi-vil] Creek. It forms the northern boundary of Manhattan, and is crossed by Interstate 278 over the Triborough Bridge.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 10 | 17 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Although not the capital, this is the largest city in the state of the same name. For 10 points each: [10] Name this largest city of the United States, consisting of five boroughs.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"connected",
			"to",
			"Hudson",
			"via",
			"Spuyten",
			"Duyvil",
			"Spooi-ten",
			"Dooi-vil",
			"Creek",
			"It",
			"forms",
			"northern",
			"boundary",
			"Manhattan",
			"and",
			"crossed",
			"by",
			"Interstate",
			"278",
			"over",
			"Triborough",
			"Bridge"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Dubai[10] In addition to The World Islands and The Universe Islands, Nakheel Properties developed these three artificial archipelagoes named Jebel Ali, Jumeirah, and Deira, which remain under construction. They are located off the coast of Dubai.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 9 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This city is home to the the tallest building in the world, the Burj Khalifa, which was formerly named after the city. For 10 points each: [10] Name this city on the Persian Gulf, one of the seven United Arab Emirates.",
		"answers": [
			"Dubai",
			"10",
			"In",
			"addition",
			"to",
			"The",
			"World",
			"Islands",
			"and",
			"Universe",
			"Nakheel",
			"Properties",
			"developed",
			"these",
			"three",
			"artificial",
			"archipelagoes",
			"named",
			"Jebel",
			"Ali",
			"Jumeirah",
			"Deira",
			"which",
			"remain",
			"under",
			"construction",
			"They",
			"are",
			"located",
			"off",
			"coast"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vietnam War[10] The Vietnam Veterans Memorial was designed by this architect who received criticism for her Asian ethnicity. This architect also designed a Civil Rights Memorial in Montgomery, Alabama.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 19 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: A Moving Wall version of a structure honoring veterans of this war travels across the country. For 10 points each: [10] Give this war whose veterans are honored by two reflective black gabbro walls inscribed with the names of the killed-in-action and missing-in-action of this war.",
		"answers": [
			"Vietnam",
			"War",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Veterans",
			"Memorial",
			"was",
			"designed",
			"by",
			"this",
			"architect",
			"who",
			"received",
			"criticism",
			"for",
			"her",
			"Asian",
			"ethnicity",
			"This",
			"also",
			"Civil",
			"Rights",
			"in",
			"Montgomery",
			"Alabama"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Massachusetts [10] This only national park in Maine contains the Somes Sound and much of Mount Desert Island.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 12 | 6 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: New England is composed of six states. For 10 points each: [10] Name this state, with capital Boston, that is home to Harvard University.",
		"answers": [
			"Massachusetts",
			"10",
			"This",
			"only",
			"national",
			"park",
			"in",
			"Maine",
			"contains",
			"Somes",
			"Sound",
			"and",
			"much",
			"Mount",
			"Desert",
			"Island"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vatican City or the Holy See [10] This nation, whose most populous quartier is Monte Carlo, is located in the French Riviera.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Europe is the smallest continent and is thus home to some really tiny countries. For 10 points each: [10] Name this nation, the smallest in the world. It is home to the headquarters of the Roman Catholic Church, leading to the amusing statistic of having six popes per square mile.  ",
		"answers": [
			"Vatican",
			"City",
			"Holy",
			"See",
			"10",
			"This",
			"nation",
			"whose",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"quartier",
			"Monte",
			"Carlo",
			"located",
			"in",
			"French",
			"Riviera"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cape Horn[10] Cape Horn lies on this archipelago shared between Argentina and Chile. It's name in Spanish literally means \"land of fire.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 3 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Going around this point means traversing the Drake Passage; two shortcuts are the Beagle Channel and the better known Strait of Magellan. For 10 points each: [10] Name this cape, the southern most point of South America.",
		"answers": [
			"Cape",
			"Horn",
			"10",
			"lies",
			"this",
			"archipelago",
			"shared",
			"between",
			"Argentina",
			"and",
			"Chile",
			"It's",
			"name",
			"in",
			"Spanish",
			"literally",
			"means",
			"land",
			"fire"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "France (or French Republic)[10] This peak, the highest in Europe outside of Russia, is located on the border of Rhone-Alpes and the Italian region of Aosta Valley.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 14 | 22 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This western European nation has 27 regions including Alsace, Lorraine, and Corsica. For 10 points each: [10] The Eiffel Tower is located in this country whose capital is located in a landlocked region named \"island of this nation\" when literally translated.",
		"answers": [
			"France",
			"French",
			"Republic",
			"10",
			"This",
			"peak",
			"highest",
			"in",
			"Europe",
			"outside",
			"Russia",
			"located",
			"border",
			"Rhone-Alpes",
			"and",
			"Italian",
			"region",
			"Aosta",
			"Valley"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nile River[10] Third in length to the Nile and Congo, this West African river is the namesake of two of the countries it flows through. It was the principal river of the Mali, Ghana, and Songhay Empires.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 14 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Aswan High Dam lies on this river. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this longest African river whose Blue and White varieties meet at Khartoum. The distinctive shape of this river's mouth on the Mediterranean is the origin of the term 'delta.'",
		"answers": [
			"Nile",
			"River",
			"10",
			"Third",
			"in",
			"length",
			"to",
			"and",
			"Congo",
			"this",
			"West",
			"African",
			"river",
			"namesake",
			"two",
			"countries",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"It",
			"was",
			"principal",
			"Mali",
			"Ghana",
			"Songhay",
			"Empires"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Berlin[10] This city is located in Germany's southeast. It is the capital of the state of Bavaria and is the home of BMW.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 3 | 2 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Germany is the most populous nation in the European Union, and many of those people happen to live in cities. Name some German cities, for 10 points each: [10] This city is the capital of Germany and was divided by a wall for much of the later half of the 20th century. ",
		"answers": [
			"Berlin",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Germany's",
			"southeast",
			"It",
			"capital",
			"state",
			"Bavaria",
			"and",
			"home",
			"BMW"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ontario[10] This province borders Ontario to the west and includes the city of Winnipeg.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 4 | 7 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Though many uninformed people believe that Canada is one of the 51 United States of America, it is in fact its own nation with its own subdivisions, provinces and territories. For 10 points each: [10] Name this province which is the largest by population and includes the cities of Toronto and Ottawa.",
		"answers": [
			"Ontario",
			"10",
			"This",
			"province",
			"borders",
			"to",
			"west",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"city",
			"Winnipeg"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the South [accept equivalents][10] This Texas metropolitan region, an American Airlines hub, is the largest in the South.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 15 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The United States Census Bureau defines this region as all of the former Confederacy plus Kentucky, West Virginia, Delaware, and Maryland. For 10 points each: [10] Name this region of the United States sometimes referred to as Dixie.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"South",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Texas",
			"metropolitan",
			"region",
			"an",
			"American",
			"Airlines",
			"hub",
			"largest",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Crimean peninsula[10] This city on the Crimean peninsula was once home to the Soviet Black Sea fleet and is currently leased by the Russian navy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 3 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This European peninsula is the homeland of its namesake Tatars who were expelled by the Stalin government. For 10 points each: [10] Name this southern Ukranian peninsula bounded by the Black Sea to the south and the Sea of Azov to the east.",
		"answers": [
			"Crimean",
			"peninsula",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"was",
			"once",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Soviet",
			"Black",
			"Sea",
			"fleet",
			"and",
			"currently",
			"leased",
			"by",
			"Russian",
			"navy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ieoh Ming Pei[10] Pei also designed glass pyramids for the entrance to this landmark art museum located in Paris. The Mona Lisa's eyes supposedly follow the viewer around while viewing her in this museum.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 10 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In 2012, a long time goal of playing Tetris with the windows of this man's Green Building at MIT was achieved. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Chinese-American architect who used part of a glass pyramid in designing the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.",
		"answers": [
			"Ieoh",
			"Ming",
			"Pei",
			"10",
			"also",
			"designed",
			"glass",
			"pyramids",
			"for",
			"entrance",
			"to",
			"this",
			"landmark",
			"art",
			"museum",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Paris",
			"The",
			"Mona",
			"Lisa's",
			"eyes",
			"supposedly",
			"follow",
			"viewer",
			"around",
			"while",
			"viewing",
			"her"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Saint Petersburg[10] This city, the eastern terminus of the Trans-Siberian railway, is the largest Russian city on the Pacific Ocean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 9 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Russia, the largest nation in the world, also has some pretty big cities. For 10 points each: [10] This city, the second largest in Russia, was formerly known as Leningrad and Petrograd and was the capital before Moscow.",
		"answers": [
			"Saint",
			"Petersburg",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"eastern",
			"terminus",
			"Trans-Siberian",
			"railway",
			"largest",
			"Russian",
			"Pacific",
			"Ocean"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Olympus Mons[10] Olympus Mons is a volcano on this red planet that is also the site of the Valles Marineris.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 8 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This feature formed during the Amazonian period. For 10 points each: [10] Name this shield volcano that was until 2011 known as the tallest mountain base-to-height in the Solar System.",
		"answers": [
			"Olympus",
			"Mons",
			"10",
			"volcano",
			"this",
			"red",
			"planet",
			"that",
			"also",
			"site",
			"Valles",
			"Marineris"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tokyo [10] This island of Japan is home to Tokyo, Kobe, Hiroshima, and Sendai. It is the second most populous island in the world.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This city was originally known as Edo. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this capital city of Japan. ",
		"answers": [
			"Tokyo",
			"10",
			"This",
			"island",
			"Japan",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Kobe",
			"Hiroshima",
			"and",
			"Sendai",
			"It",
			"second",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"in",
			"world"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tokyo [10] This island of Japan is home to Tokyo, Kobe, Hiroshima, and Sendai. It is the second most populous island in the world.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 11 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This city was originally known as Edo. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this capital city of Japan. ",
		"answers": [
			"Tokyo",
			"10",
			"This",
			"island",
			"Japan",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Kobe",
			"Hiroshima",
			"and",
			"Sendai",
			"It",
			"second",
			"most",
			"populous",
			"in",
			"world"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Alaska[10] This river, the longest in Alaska, originates in British Columbia and flows into the Bering Sea. A Canadian territory was named after this river.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 1 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 1. This is the largest of the 50 United States. For 10 points each: [10] Name this home of the Brooks Range and the only state that has a shore on the Arctic Ocean. It is bordered by Canada on the east",
		"answers": [
			"Alaska",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"longest",
			"in",
			"originates",
			"British",
			"Columbia",
			"and",
			"flows",
			"into",
			"Bering",
			"Sea",
			"A",
			"Canadian",
			"territory",
			"was",
			"named",
			"after",
			"this"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Alberta[10] This river flows from Jasper National Park to a lake of the same name on Alberta's border with Saskatchewan, where it joins with the Peace River to form the Slave River. Its namesake oil sands are also located in Alberta.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 8 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this westernmost of Canada's Prairie provinces which contains cities such as Edmonton and Calgary.",
		"answers": [
			"Alberta",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"flows",
			"from",
			"Jasper",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"to",
			"lake",
			"same",
			"name",
			"Alberta's",
			"border",
			"with",
			"Saskatchewan",
			"where",
			"joins",
			"Peace",
			"River",
			"form",
			"Slave",
			"Its",
			"namesake",
			"oil",
			"sands",
			"are",
			"also",
			"located",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "lochs [accept Loch Eriboll or Loch Ness][10] Loch Eriboll is connected to the Pentland one of these inlets. The Solway one was the original western terminus of Hadrian's Wall.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 3 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Give these Scottish geographic terms, for 10 points each: [10] Eriboll is a sea-inlet example of these features; the better-known freshwater ones include Ness, the supposed home of a legendary monster. ",
		"answers": [
			"lochs",
			"Loch",
			"Eriboll",
			"Ness",
			"10",
			"connected",
			"to",
			"Pentland",
			"one",
			"these",
			"inlets",
			"The",
			"Solway",
			"was",
			"original",
			"western",
			"terminus",
			"Hadrian's",
			"Wall"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mount Rainier[10]  This other stratovolcano in the Cascade Range is famous for its 1980 eruption, the most destructive volcanic event in U.S. history which also formed this mountain's Crater Glacier.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 19 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This stratovolcano in Washington State is the most topographically prominent mountain in the contiguous United States. Its highest summit is known as Columbia Crest.",
		"answers": [
			"Mount",
			"Rainier",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"stratovolcano",
			"in",
			"Cascade",
			"Range",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"its",
			"1980",
			"eruption",
			"most",
			"destructive",
			"volcanic",
			"event",
			"U",
			"S",
			"history",
			"which",
			"also",
			"formed",
			"this",
			"mountain's",
			"Crater",
			"Glacier"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sydney[10]  Sydney is the capital of this state of Australia, bordered to the south by Victoria and to the west by South Australia. Other cities in this state include Wollongong and Newcastle, and it contains Mount Kosciuszko.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 13 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this largest city of Australia that contains Warragamba Dam as well as an architecturally significant Opera House on Bennelong Point.",
		"answers": [
			"Sydney",
			"10",
			"capital",
			"this",
			"state",
			"Australia",
			"bordered",
			"to",
			"south",
			"by",
			"Victoria",
			"and",
			"west",
			"South",
			"Other",
			"cities",
			"in",
			"include",
			"Wollongong",
			"Newcastle",
			"contains",
			"Mount",
			"Kosciuszko"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Poland[10]  This capital of Poland sits on the Vistula and contains a statue of its coat of arms, a mermaid brandishing a sword, in its Old Town Market Place.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 15 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this European nation which houses the White Stork Synagogue in Wroclaw, the capital of Lower Silesian Voivodeship. Other cities on the Oder in this country include a town named Police.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Poland",
			"10",
			"This",
			"capital",
			"sits",
			"Vistula",
			"and",
			"contains",
			"statue",
			"its",
			"coat",
			"arms",
			"mermaid",
			"brandishing",
			"sword",
			"in",
			"Old",
			"Town",
			"Market",
			"Place"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rio Grande [or Rio Bravo del Norte][10]  Mexico also features this long, narrow peninsula in its northwest. In this peninsula's north are the cities of Mexicali and Tijuana, while the Sierra de la Laguna range can be found in its south.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 16 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this river whose mouth is in Matamoros, a city in the state of Tamaulipas. It also serves as the southern border for Terrell and Maverick Counties.",
		"answers": [
			"Rio",
			"Grande",
			"Bravo",
			"del",
			"Norte",
			"10",
			"Mexico",
			"also",
			"features",
			"this",
			"long",
			"narrow",
			"peninsula",
			"in",
			"its",
			"northwest",
			"In",
			"peninsula's",
			"north",
			"are",
			"cities",
			"Mexicali",
			"and",
			"Tijuana",
			"while",
			"Sierra",
			"de",
			"la",
			"Laguna",
			"range",
			"can",
			"be",
			"found",
			"south"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sea of Japan [or East Sea][10]  La Perouse Strait separates Sakhalin from this northernmost Japanese island famous for its Ainu population. Its city of Hakodate is the capital of Oshima Subprefecture.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round05.docx | 5 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this body of water bordered to the north by Russian coastal cities like Vladivostok and to the west by the Korean peninsula. This body contains Moneron Island owned by Sakhalin, known for its sea lions.",
		"answers": [
			"Sea",
			"Japan",
			"East",
			"10",
			"La",
			"Perouse",
			"Strait",
			"separates",
			"Sakhalin",
			"from",
			"this",
			"northernmost",
			"Japanese",
			"island",
			"famous",
			"for",
			"its",
			"Ainu",
			"population",
			"Its",
			"city",
			"Hakodate",
			"capital",
			"Oshima",
			"Subprefecture"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Antarctica[10]  This sea, one of two major Antarctic bays, is notoriously perilous, being the site of the freezing of Ernest Shackleton's ship Endurance. Its namesake seal can be found on the Antarctic Peninsula.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 6 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this continent, the windiest and driest continent on average, which has its highest point at Vinson Massif in the Ellsworth Mountains.",
		"answers": [
			"Antarctica",
			"10",
			"This",
			"sea",
			"one",
			"two",
			"major",
			"Antarctic",
			"bays"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Seattle[10]  Seattle, as well as Tacoma and Kitsap Peninsula, is located on this body of water. Admiralty Inlet connects this body of water to the Strait of Juan de Fuca, which opens into the Pacific Ocean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 14 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this large coastal city in Washington State whose Century 21 Exposition in 1962 saw the construction of the Space Needle, which is a short walk from the Experience Music Project.",
		"answers": [
			"Seattle",
			"10",
			"as",
			"well",
			"Tacoma",
			"and",
			"Kitsap",
			"Peninsula",
			"located",
			"this",
			"body",
			"water",
			"Admiralty",
			"Inlet",
			"connects",
			"to",
			"Strait",
			"Juan",
			"de",
			"Fuca",
			"which",
			"opens",
			"into",
			"Pacific",
			"Ocean"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Niagara Falls[10]  This highest uninterrupted waterfall is located in Canaima National Park in Venezuela. It is named for the American aviator who discovered it upon crashing his monoplane onto Auyantepui.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  These falls actually consist of three waterfalls, two in New York State and Horseshoe Falls in Ontario, Canada. Its namesake river connects Lake Ontario and Lake Erie.",
		"answers": [
			"Niagara",
			"Falls",
			"10",
			"This",
			"highest",
			"uninterrupted",
			"waterfall",
			"located",
			"in",
			"Canaima",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"Venezuela",
			"It",
			"named",
			"for",
			"American",
			"aviator",
			"who",
			"discovered",
			"upon",
			"crashing",
			"his",
			"monoplane",
			"onto",
			"Auyantepui"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of South Africa[10]  In South Africa's north is this desert, which primarily covers Botswana and Namibia. The Okavango River flows through this desert, home to the Dragon's Breath Cave, which contains a huge underground lake.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round09.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country whose highest point, Mafadi, is located in the Drakensberg range. This polity recognizes distinct executive, judicial, and legislative capital cities.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"South",
			"Africa",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Africa's",
			"north",
			"this",
			"desert",
			"which",
			"primarily",
			"covers",
			"Botswana",
			"and",
			"Namibia",
			"The",
			"Okavango",
			"River",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Dragon's",
			"Breath",
			"Cave",
			"contains",
			"huge",
			"underground",
			"lake"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Madagascar[10]  This archipelago owned by Chile and Argentina is separated from the rest of South America by the Strait of Magellan. Its southernmost island is Cape Horn, and it also includes a Staten Island.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 16 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This Indian Ocean island nation is located off the southeastern coast of Africa. Its capital of Antananarivo is located in the Analamanga region.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Madagascar",
			"10",
			"This",
			"archipelago",
			"owned",
			"by",
			"Chile",
			"and",
			"Argentina",
			"separated",
			"from",
			"rest",
			"South",
			"America",
			"Strait",
			"Magellan",
			"Its",
			"southernmost",
			"island",
			"Cape",
			"Horn",
			"also",
			"includes",
			"Staten",
			"Island"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Yangtze River [or Chang Jiang][10]  This structure built on the Yangtze River is the largest hydroelectric power station in the world. Completed in 2012, this controversial dam is located in Yichang, in the Hubei province.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 19 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This river begins at a glacier on Geladandong Peak before flowing east. One of its headwaters, the Golden Sands River, features the very deep Tiger Leaping Gorge.",
		"answers": [
			"Yangtze",
			"River",
			"Chang",
			"Jiang",
			"10",
			"This",
			"structure",
			"built",
			"largest",
			"hydroelectric",
			"power",
			"station",
			"in",
			"world",
			"Completed",
			"2012",
			"this",
			"controversial",
			"dam",
			"located",
			"Yichang",
			"Hubei",
			"province"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Andes Mountains[10]  The Andes pass through this country with both a constitutional capital and a departmental capital, which is the highest capital city in the world. This landlocked nation contains Santa Cruz and much of the Altiplano.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this South American mountain range, which reaches as far north as Merida in Venezuela to Mount Aconcagua in Argentina.",
		"answers": [
			"Andes",
			"Mountains",
			"10",
			"The",
			"pass",
			"through",
			"this",
			"country",
			"with",
			"both",
			"constitutional",
			"capital",
			"and",
			"departmental",
			"which",
			"highest",
			"city",
			"in",
			"world",
			"This",
			"landlocked",
			"nation",
			"contains",
			"Santa",
			"Cruz",
			"much",
			"Altiplano"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zambezi River[10]  The Zambezi flows through the eastern portion of this nation whose capital is Luanda. This former Portuguese colony now has a province named Zaire, which borders the Democratic Republic of the Congo.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 20 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  The Kabompo and Lungwebungu Rivers are major tributaries of this river. It also flows along the eastern border of Namibia and the northern border of Botswana after originating in Zambia.",
		"answers": [
			"Zambezi",
			"River",
			"10",
			"The",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"eastern",
			"portion",
			"this",
			"nation",
			"whose",
			"capital",
			"Luanda",
			"This",
			"former",
			"Portuguese",
			"colony",
			"now",
			"has",
			"province",
			"named",
			"Zaire",
			"which",
			"borders",
			"Democratic",
			"Republic",
			"Congo"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Naples [or Napoli][10]  We got on a cruise ship and began sailing due west, ending up in this sea on the Mediterranean. This sea is connected to the Ligurian Sea by the Corsica Channel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 8 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  We begin in this \"new city\" sandwiched between the Phlegraean Fields and Mount Vesuvius, the capital of the region of Campania. It's essential to visit the Palace of Caserta and the huge square, Piazza del Plebiscito.",
		"answers": [
			"Naples",
			"Napoli",
			"10",
			"We",
			"got",
			"cruise",
			"ship",
			"and",
			"began",
			"sailing",
			"due",
			"west",
			"ending",
			"up",
			"in",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"Mediterranean",
			"This",
			"connected",
			"to",
			"Ligurian",
			"Sea",
			"by",
			"Corsica",
			"Channel"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Guatemala[10]  This mountain range dividing Europe and Asia lies west of Yekaterinburg. It begins at the Kara Sea and ends at the Kazakh Steppes. Its highest point is Mount Narodnaya.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 14 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Along with Belize, this country is the border between North America and South America. Hurricanes Mitch and Stan occurred here, and its cities include Petapa, Mixco, and Villa Nueva.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Guatemala",
			"10",
			"This",
			"mountain",
			"range",
			"dividing",
			"Europe",
			"and",
			"Asia",
			"lies",
			"west",
			"Yekaterinburg",
			"It",
			"begins",
			"at",
			"Kara",
			"Sea",
			"ends",
			"Kazakh",
			"Steppes",
			"Its",
			"highest",
			"point",
			"Mount",
			"Narodnaya"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Alberta[10]  This river flows from Jasper National Park to a lake of the same name on Alberta's border with Saskatchewan, where it joins with the Peace River to form the Slave River. Its namesake oil sands are also located in Alberta.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 8 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this westernmost of Canada's Prairie provinces which contains cities such as Edmonton and Calgary.",
		"answers": [
			"Alberta",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"flows",
			"from",
			"Jasper",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"to",
			"lake",
			"same",
			"name",
			"Alberta's",
			"border",
			"with",
			"Saskatchewan",
			"where",
			"joins",
			"Peace",
			"River",
			"form",
			"Slave",
			"Its",
			"namesake",
			"oil",
			"sands",
			"are",
			"also",
			"located",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Idaho[10]  This river rises in Yellowstone National Park and receives the Salmon and Clearwater Rivers in Idaho before passing into Washington and eventually flowing into the Columbia River.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this state which contains cities such as Pocatello, Coeur d'Alene (\"KORR duh-LAYN\"), and Boise.",
		"answers": [
			"Idaho",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"rises",
			"in",
			"Yellowstone",
			"National",
			"Park",
			"and",
			"receives",
			"Salmon",
			"Clearwater",
			"Rivers",
			"passing",
			"into",
			"Washington",
			"eventually",
			"flowing",
			"Columbia",
			"River"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kingdom of Spain (or Reino de Espana)[10]  This longest river on the Iberian Peninsula rises in the Meseta Central and flows past Toledo before emptying into the Atlantic at Lisbon.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 17 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country with cities such as Cadiz, Asturias, and Valladolid which lies across the Strait of Gibraltar from Morocco.",
		"answers": [
			"Kingdom",
			"Spain",
			"Reino",
			"de",
			"Espana",
			"10",
			"This",
			"longest",
			"river",
			"Iberian",
			"Peninsula",
			"rises",
			"in",
			"Meseta",
			"Central",
			"and",
			"flows",
			"past",
			"Toledo",
			"emptying",
			"into",
			"Atlantic",
			"at",
			"Lisbon"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Borneo[10]  Indonesia also contains this island that contains the cities of Banda Aceh, Palembang, and Medan. It lies across the Sunda Strait from Java and across the Strait of Malacca from the Malay Peninsula.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 17 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this third largest island in the world, which is shared between Brunei, Malaysia, and Indonesia.",
		"answers": [
			"Borneo",
			"10",
			"Indonesia",
			"also",
			"contains",
			"this",
			"island",
			"that",
			"cities",
			"Banda",
			"Aceh",
			"Palembang",
			"and",
			"Medan",
			"It",
			"lies",
			"across",
			"Sunda",
			"Strait",
			"from",
			"Java",
			"Malacca",
			"Malay",
			"Peninsula"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Namibia[10]  This desert, home to the Bushmen and the Makgadikgadi salt pan, is shared among Namibia, South Africa, and Botswana.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 3 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country which contains Walvis Bay and the Skeleton Coast with capital at Windhoek. Its southern border is formed by the Orange River.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Namibia",
			"10",
			"This",
			"desert",
			"home",
			"to",
			"Bushmen",
			"and",
			"Makgadikgadi",
			"salt",
			"pan",
			"shared",
			"among",
			"South",
			"Africa",
			"Botswana"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Mexico[10]  This national park lies in southeastern New Mexico and features the Big Room, the third largest cave chamber in North America.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 20 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this state bisected by the Rio Grande which contains White Sands National Monument and cities like Alamogordo, Las Cruces, Albuquerque, and Santa Fe.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Mexico",
			"10",
			"This",
			"national",
			"park",
			"lies",
			"in",
			"southeastern",
			"and",
			"features",
			"Big",
			"Room",
			"third",
			"largest",
			"cave",
			"chamber",
			"North",
			"America"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Munich (or Munchen)[10]  Before joining the Danube at Belgrade, the Sava flows through the capital of this country that contains the Istrian Peninsula and the cities of Rijeka and Dubrovnik.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 7 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Before joining the Danube, the Isar flows through this Oktoberfest-celebrating capital city of Bavaria.",
		"answers": [
			"Munich",
			"Munchen",
			"10",
			"Before",
			"joining",
			"Danube",
			"at",
			"Belgrade",
			"Sava",
			"flows",
			"through",
			"capital",
			"this",
			"country",
			"that",
			"contains",
			"Istrian",
			"Peninsula",
			"and",
			"cities",
			"Rijeka",
			"Dubrovnik"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Nicaragua[10]  This country contains the Great Blue Hole as well as a namesake barrier reef that is the second longest in the world. It is the only officially English-speaking country in Central America and the only one not to border the Pacific Ocean.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This country that lies at the southern end of the Gulf of Fonseca and contains the largest lake in Central America as well as a lake named after its capital, Managua.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Nicaragua",
			"10",
			"This",
			"country",
			"contains",
			"Great",
			"Blue",
			"Hole",
			"as",
			"well",
			"namesake",
			"barrier",
			"reef",
			"that",
			"second",
			"longest",
			"in",
			"world",
			"It",
			"only",
			"officially",
			"English-speaking",
			"Central",
			"America",
			"and",
			"one"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Toronto[10]  Queen Charlotte Island is a part of this Canadian province, which also features the Fraser River and the Hecate Strait. Its capital is Victoria and its largest city lies across the border from the state of Washington.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 7 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This provincial capital of Ontario lies on Lake Ontario. The most recognizable feature of this largest city in Canada is its 1800-foot tall CN Tower.",
		"answers": [
			"Toronto",
			"10",
			"Queen",
			"Charlotte",
			"Island",
			"part",
			"this",
			"Canadian",
			"province",
			"which",
			"also",
			"features",
			"Fraser",
			"River",
			"and",
			"Hecate",
			"Strait",
			"Its",
			"capital",
			"Victoria",
			"its",
			"largest",
			"city",
			"lies",
			"across",
			"border",
			"from",
			"state",
			"Washington"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Minnesota[10]  This river forms the border between Minnesota and North Dakota. Another river of the same name forms the border between Oklahoma and Texas and flows into the Mississippi River in Louisiana.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 1 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this state which contains Lake Itasca as well as the cities of Duluth, St. Paul, and Minneapolis.",
		"answers": [
			"Minnesota",
			"10",
			"This",
			"river",
			"forms",
			"border",
			"between",
			"and",
			"North",
			"Dakota"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Santiago (accept but do not reveal Santiago de Chile)[10]  Santiago is the capital of this long, narrow country which contains the western half of Tierra del Fuego in its south and the Atacama Desert in its north.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 8 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this South American capital city which lies 60 miles southwest of Aconcagua and 70 miles southeast of the port of Valparaiso.",
		"answers": [
			"Santiago",
			"but"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Scotland (or Alba)[10]  Scotland controls the Shetland Islands, the Orkney Islands, and this archipelago lying off the western coast of Scotland which contains the Isle of Lewis and the Isle of Skye.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 21 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this country which contains the Firth of Forth and the Firth of Clyde as well as cities such as Aberdeen, Glasgow, and its capital Edinburgh, which lies north of England.",
		"answers": [
			"Scotland",
			"Alba",
			"10",
			"controls",
			"Shetland",
			"Islands",
			"Orkney",
			"and",
			"this",
			"archipelago",
			"lying",
			"off",
			"western",
			"coast",
			"which",
			"contains",
			"Isle",
			"Lewis",
			"Skye"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Guinea (or Papua Island; do not accept \"Papua New Guinea\")[10]  This strait, which connects the Arafura Sea to the Coral Sea, separates New Guinea from the Cape York Peninsula.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this large island, the western portion of which contains Puncak Jaya and is controlled by Indonesia, and the eastern portion of which contains a namesake country with capital at Port Moresby.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Guinea",
			"Papua",
			"Island"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nevada[10]  New Orleans lies in between the Mississippi River and this second largest saltwater lake in the United States.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 18 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Lake Tahoe lies on the border between California and this state, which also contains Pyramid Lake and cities such as Reno and Carson City.",
		"answers": [
			"Nevada",
			"10",
			"New",
			"Orleans",
			"lies",
			"in",
			"between",
			"Mississippi",
			"River",
			"and",
			"this",
			"second",
			"largest",
			"saltwater",
			"lake",
			"United",
			"States"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Islamic Republic of Afghanistan[10]  Tirich Mir is the highest point in this mountain range which dominates central and northeastern Afghanistan.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 11 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this landlocked country in which the Helmand River drains into the Sistan Basin. Its cities include Herat, Kandahar, and its capital, Kabul.",
		"answers": [
			"Islamic",
			"Republic",
			"Afghanistan",
			"10",
			"Tirich",
			"Mir",
			"highest",
			"point",
			"in",
			"this",
			"mountain",
			"range",
			"which",
			"dominates",
			"central",
			"and",
			"northeastern"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Djibouti[10]  The Bab-el-Mandeb connects the Gulf of Aden to this sea, which is in turn connected to the Mediterranean Sea by the Suez Canal.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 19 | Geography |  | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this small country that lies across the Bab-el-Mandeb from Yemen.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Djibouti",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Bab-el-Mandeb",
			"connects",
			"Gulf",
			"Aden",
			"to",
			"this",
			"sea",
			"which",
			"in",
			"turn",
			"connected",
			"Mediterranean",
			"Sea",
			"by",
			"Suez",
			"Canal"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Johannesburg [or Egoli][10] This city near Johannesburg is the administrative capital of South Africa, as opposed to the other two judicial  and legislative capitals. It is named after a leader of the Voortrekkers.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 2 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: It is the world's largest city not located on a river or body of water. For 10 points each: [10] Name this city containing the impoverished Soweto area; it is the largest city in South Africa.",
		"answers": [
			"Johannesburg",
			"Egoli",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"near",
			"administrative",
			"capital",
			"South",
			"Africa",
			"as",
			"opposed",
			"to",
			"other",
			"two",
			"judicial",
			"and",
			"legislative",
			"capitals",
			"It",
			"named",
			"after",
			"leader",
			"Voortrekkers"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Anchorage[10] This western Alaskan city was a gold mining boom town, and is the end point of the Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 16 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: America's largest state is also one of its least populated. For 10 points each: [10] This is Alaska's largest city, home to over half its population.",
		"answers": [
			"Anchorage",
			"10",
			"This",
			"western",
			"Alaskan",
			"city",
			"was",
			"gold",
			"mining",
			"boom",
			"town",
			"and",
			"end",
			"point",
			"Iditarod",
			"Trail",
			"Sled",
			"Dog",
			"Race"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Philippines[10] This city adjacent to the capital Manila is the largest city in the Philippines.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 5 | Geography | None | HS",
		"subject": "Geography",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Consisting of over 7,000 islands, this country featured a large settlement on a mountainous landfill in Payatas.. For 10 points each: [10] Name this country, separated from Taiwan by the Luzon Strait and from Indonesia by the Sulu Sea. Its capital city is Manila.",
		"answers": [
			"Philippines",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"adjacent",
			"to",
			"capital",
			"Manila",
			"largest",
			"in"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Serial[10] This Muslim-American activist and lawyer brought Koenig's attention to Adnan's case. As a friend of the Syed family, she leads the campaign to free Adnan",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "MUT |2015 | 5 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: An oft-parodied advertisement preceding episodes of this podcast involves a girl who is inexplicably unable to pronounce \"Mailchimp.\"  [10] Name this podcast narrated by Sarah Koenig, whose first season covered the controversy surrounding the arrest and trial of Adnan Syed for the murder of his girlfriend Hae Min Lee.",
		"answers": [
			"Serial",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Muslim-American",
			"activist",
			"and",
			"lawyer",
			"brought",
			"Koenig's",
			"attention",
			"to",
			"Adnan's",
			"case",
			"As",
			"friend",
			"Syed",
			"family",
			"she",
			"leads",
			"campaign",
			"free",
			"Adnan"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Muath al-Kasasbeh[10] The screening of his murder took place in this city, an ISIS stronghold in the north of Iraq. The Jordanian Air Force responded to the murder by bombing this city, killing 55 militants.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "STIMPY |2015 | Illinois A - VCU A | 6 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This man's murder was broadcast in the streets on large television screens. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Jordanian pilot who was burned alive on January 3, 2015, after a mechanical failure caused him to crash over ISIS occupied territory in Syria.",
		"answers": [
			"Muath",
			"al-Kasasbeh",
			"10",
			"The",
			"screening",
			"his",
			"murder",
			"took",
			"place",
			"in",
			"this",
			"city",
			"an",
			"ISIS",
			"stronghold",
			"north",
			"Iraq",
			"Jordanian",
			"Air",
			"Force",
			"responded",
			"to",
			"by",
			"bombing",
			"killing",
			"55",
			"militants"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mike Huckabee[10] Huckabee recently authored this bestseller, which defends the \"catfish and cornbread crowd\" against \"the crepes and caviar set\" and argues \"Status is a Ford 150 truck; luxury is crawfish étouffée and slaw on your pulled-pork sandwich; and privilege is front-row seats at a Lynyrd Skynyrd concert.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "STIMPY |2015 | Virginia A - Kentucky A | 14 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about a potential Republican candidate for President. For 10 points each: [10] This former Governor of Arkansas who ran for the nomination in 2012, has tried to position himself as a populist alternative in the upcoming election. He also hosts a show on Fox News.",
		"answers": [
			"Mike",
			"Huckabee",
			"10",
			"recently",
			"authored",
			"this",
			"bestseller",
			"which",
			"defends",
			"catfish",
			"and",
			"cornbread",
			"crowd",
			"against",
			"crepes",
			"caviar",
			"set",
			"argues",
			"Status",
			"Ford",
			"150",
			"truck",
			"luxury",
			"crawfish",
			"étouffée",
			"slaw",
			"your",
			"pulled-pork",
			"sandwich",
			"privilege",
			"front-row",
			"seats",
			"at",
			"Lynyrd",
			"Skynyrd",
			"concert"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mayor of New York City[10] Bill de Blasio has pledged to reform this New York City police policy which usually goes by a three-word name. It conforms to Terry v. Ohio but has been riddled with allegations of racial profiling.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals |2014 | Brown A, Caltech B, and Colonel By | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this position currently held by Bill de Blasio and which has been held by Rudy Giuliani and Michael Bloomberg in the past..",
		"answers": [
			"Mayor",
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"10",
			"Bill",
			"de",
			"Blasio",
			"has",
			"pledged",
			"to",
			"reform",
			"this",
			"police",
			"policy",
			"which",
			"usually",
			"goes",
			"by",
			"three-word",
			"name",
			"It",
			"conforms",
			"Terry",
			"v",
			"Ohio",
			"but",
			"been",
			"riddled",
			"with",
			"allegations",
			"racial",
			"profiling"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kansas[10] This man was the Kansan Secretary of State who unsuccessfully tried to replace Chad Taylor on the ballot. He cowrote the infamous Arizona Immigration law in 2008.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Chicago A | 18 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The Republican Secretary of State in this State took the unusual step of suing his State's Democratic Party to force them to add a candidate to the ballot in the Senate Race.  [10] Name this state where Pat Roberts won a fourth consecutive term in the US Senate over independent candidate Greg Orman.",
		"answers": [
			"Kansas",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"was",
			"Kansan",
			"Secretary",
			"State",
			"who",
			"unsuccessfully",
			"tried",
			"to",
			"replace",
			"Chad",
			"Taylor",
			"ballot",
			"He",
			"cowrote",
			"infamous",
			"Arizona",
			"Immigration",
			"law",
			"in",
			"2008"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tsakhia(giin) Elbegdorj[10] Elbegdorj often referenced Mongolia's occupation by Baron Ungern, a commander from this foreign political faction. The Polar Bear expedition backed this political faction.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Chicago A | 19 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Wikileaks revealed that a popular story about this man adopting 20 orphans over the course of his life was false; in fact, he had actually adopted 21.  [10] Name this President of Mongolia, who has been called the \"Golden Swallow of Democracy\" for driving pretty much every positive development in the country since 1990.",
		"answers": [
			"Tsakhia",
			"giin",
			"Elbegdorj",
			"10",
			"often",
			"referenced",
			"Mongolia's",
			"occupation",
			"by",
			"Baron",
			"Ungern",
			"commander",
			"from",
			"this",
			"foreign",
			"political",
			"faction",
			"The",
			"Polar",
			"Bear",
			"expedition",
			"backed"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Leung Chun-ying [or C. Y. Leung][10] Leung is the Chief Executive of this Special Administrative Region. This polity's Central business district is the namesake of the nonviolent \"Occupy\" group led by Benny Tai that kicked off the 2014 protests here.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Columbia B | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Protesters have derisively nicknamed him \"689\" because he ascended to his highest post with only 689 votes to represent a city of 7 million.  [10] Name this man, who has faced pro-democracy protesters asking for his resignation. This man responded by stressing the importance of operating within the legal framework of Basic Law.",
		"answers": [
			"Leung",
			"Chun-ying",
			"C",
			"Y",
			"10",
			"Chief",
			"Executive",
			"this",
			"Special",
			"Administrative",
			"Region",
			"This",
			"polity's",
			"Central",
			"business",
			"district",
			"namesake",
			"nonviolent",
			"Occupy",
			"group",
			"led",
			"by",
			"Benny",
			"Tai",
			"that",
			"kicked",
			"off",
			"2014",
			"protests",
			"here"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Catalan independence [or independence of Catalonia, etc.][10] The cause of Catalan independence was violently advocated by this terrorist group throughout the 1980s; they especially targeted public figures promoting the use of Castilian Spanish.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Editors 1 | 9 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In November 2014, Spanish prosecutors announced charges against Artur Mas for illegally conducting a referendum on this question.  [10] Identify this cause which seeks to make Barcelona the capital of a new country.",
		"answers": [
			"Catalan",
			"independence",
			"Catalonia",
			"etc",
			"10",
			"The",
			"cause",
			"was",
			"violently",
			"advocated",
			"by",
			"this",
			"terrorist",
			"group",
			"throughout",
			"1980s",
			"they",
			"especially",
			"targeted",
			"public",
			"figures",
			"promoting",
			"use",
			"Castilian",
			"Spanish"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vladimir Putin[10] Like in real life, Putin's sidekick is this man nicknamed \"Dima\" who can turn into a bear at will.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Editors 1 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In a webcomic, this man has to drive a bus through a crowd of zombies demanding basic human rights.   [10] Name this man, who in real life has been seen tranquilizing polar bears and swimming in Siberian rivers, typically bare-chested.",
		"answers": [
			"Vladimir",
			"Putin",
			"10",
			"Like",
			"in",
			"real",
			"life",
			"Putin's",
			"sidekick",
			"this",
			"man",
			"nicknamed",
			"Dima",
			"who",
			"can",
			"turn",
			"into",
			"bear",
			"at",
			"will"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "school districts[10] State and local government entities obtain MRAPs and other military equipment such as airplanes, bayonets, and old computers from the US Department of Defense through this program, which has come under recent fire for lack of oversight.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Editors 3 + UCSD | 19 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: One of these associations in San Diego obtained a mine-resistant, ambush-protected vehicle which it calls a \"love-buggy\" and \"fun bus,\"  [10] Name these local government agencies. One of these entities was sued by Edward Schempp and Madalyn Murray O'Hair, the founder of American Atheists.",
		"answers": [
			"school",
			"districts",
			"10",
			"State",
			"and",
			"local",
			"government",
			"entities",
			"obtain",
			"MRAPs",
			"other",
			"military",
			"equipment",
			"such",
			"as",
			"airplanes",
			"bayonets",
			"old",
			"computers",
			"from",
			"US",
			"Department",
			"Defense",
			"through",
			"this",
			"program",
			"which",
			"has",
			"come",
			"under",
			"recent",
			"fire",
			"for",
			"lack",
			"oversight"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "People's Republic of Bangladesh[10] The Nationalist and Jatiya Parties are particularly pissed at this party, which currently leads Bangladesh and helped secure its independence. It merged with another party to form the BAKSAL Party in the 1970s.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Maryland A | 3 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This country has recently been ripped apart by strikes by parties attempting to amend its constitution.  [10] Name this country whose Nationalist Party and Jatiya Party boycotted 2014 elections that were won by a party led by Sheikh Hasina. Her father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman was a leader in this country's war of independence against Pakistan.",
		"answers": [
			"People's",
			"Republic",
			"Bangladesh",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Nationalist",
			"and",
			"Jatiya",
			"Parties",
			"are",
			"particularly",
			"pissed",
			"at",
			"this",
			"party",
			"which",
			"currently",
			"leads",
			"helped",
			"secure",
			"its",
			"independence",
			"It",
			"merged",
			"with"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Malaysia Airlines [accept MH370 or MAS370][10] Another Malaysia Airlines flight was shot out of the air while flying over this oblast in eastern Ukraine. It is the site of a namesake \"Peoples' Republic\", a separatist state that has been at war with the Ukrainian army.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Michigan A | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The year thus far has not been good for a certain airline.  [10] Earlier this year a flight registered with this airline disappeared while en route to Beijing, and it remains lost, despite the largest and most expensive multinational search effort in history.",
		"answers": [
			"Malaysia",
			"Airlines",
			"MH370",
			"MAS370",
			"10"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Ford Brothers [or Rob and Doug Ford][10] This Conservative Senator became a national embarrassment earlier in 2014 when the RCMP charged him with thirty-one counts of fraud, bribery and breach of trust.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Toronto-Waterloo-McMaster A | 2 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about people disproving the notion that all Canadians are nice,  [10] This farcical duo made their way into the spotlight in the fall of 2010, when they won Toronto municipal elections. One of them refused to apologize for the other's anti-Semitic remarks and defended himself by saying that he has a \"Jewish doctor, [...] Jewish dentist [and] Jewish lawyer.\"",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Ford",
			"Brothers",
			"Rob",
			"and",
			"Doug",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Conservative",
			"Senator",
			"became",
			"national",
			"embarrassment",
			"earlier",
			"in",
			"2014",
			"when",
			"RCMP",
			"charged",
			"him",
			"with",
			"thirty-one",
			"counts",
			"fraud",
			"bribery",
			"breach",
			"trust"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ferguson, Missouri[10] This governor of Missouri declared a state of emergency in Ferguson, calling in the Missouri State Highway Patrol to take over policing in the city.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | Virginia B | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Unrest in this Missouri city has been ongoing since the death of a young black man.  [10] Name this St. Louis suburb, the location of protests against the city's disproportionately white police force.",
		"answers": [
			"Ferguson",
			"Missouri",
			"10",
			"This",
			"governor",
			"declared",
			"state",
			"emergency",
			"in",
			"calling",
			"State",
			"Highway",
			"Patrol",
			"to",
			"take",
			"over",
			"policing",
			"city"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hobby Lobby[10] The Becket Fund for Religious Liberty, which represented Hobby Lobby, is also representing Gregory Holt, whose lawsuit against this state's Department of Corrections over the right to wear a beard in prison was heard by the Supreme Court in October 2014.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DEES |2014 | WUSTL  | 6 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The Conestoga Wood Specialties company joined this company in its 2014 lawsuit against the Affordable Care Act's contraceptive mandate.  [10] Name this company which, in June 2014, won a namesake case allowing it to deny employees birth control coverage.",
		"answers": [
			"Hobby",
			"Lobby",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Becket",
			"Fund",
			"for",
			"Religious",
			"Liberty",
			"which",
			"represented",
			"also",
			"representing",
			"Gregory",
			"Holt",
			"whose",
			"lawsuit",
			"against",
			"this",
			"state's",
			"Department",
			"Corrections",
			"over",
			"right",
			"to",
			"wear",
			"beard",
			"in",
			"prison",
			"was",
			"heard",
			"by",
			"Supreme",
			"Court",
			"October",
			"2014"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "France [or French Republic; or République Française][10] Name this Socialist politician who defeated Sarkozy in 2012 and is currently the president of France.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ICCS |2014 | 10 | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Prime Minister Manuel Valls recently had to replace his entire cabinet in this country.  [10] Name this European country whose former presidents include Valéry Giscard d'Estaing and Nicolas Sarkozy.",
		"answers": [
			"France",
			"French",
			"Republic",
			"République",
			"Française",
			"10",
			"Name",
			"this",
			"Socialist",
			"politician",
			"who",
			"defeated",
			"Sarkozy",
			"in",
			"2012",
			"and",
			"currently",
			"president"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of India [or Bharat][10] The 2014 Indian elections led to the election of this man as Prime Minister. This Hindu nationalist was the Chief Minister of Gujarat from 2001-2014.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ICCS |2014 | 2 | 6 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In December 2013, this country's Supreme Court overturned a lower court ruling that had decriminalized homosexuality.  [10] Name this country with capital New Delhi; it is the second largest in the world by population.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"India",
			"Bharat",
			"10",
			"The",
			"2014",
			"Indian",
			"elections",
			"led",
			"to",
			"election",
			"this",
			"man",
			"as",
			"Prime",
			"Minister",
			"This",
			"Hindu",
			"nationalist",
			"was",
			"Chief",
			"Gujarat",
			"from",
			"2001-2014"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Montana[10] Bullock appointed this former lieutenant governor to fill Max Baucus's Senate seat in 2014. He recently dropped a re-election bid when he was found to have plagiarized his master's thesis.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ICCS |2014 | 4 | 21 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This state is the largest to have only one seat in the House of Representatives; that position is currently held by Republican Steve Daines.  [10] Name this western state that usually votes Republican in Presidential elections, but is currently led by Democratic Governor Steve Bullock from Helena.",
		"answers": [
			"Montana",
			"10",
			"Bullock",
			"appointed",
			"this",
			"former",
			"lieutenant",
			"governor",
			"to",
			"fill",
			"Max",
			"Baucus's",
			"Senate",
			"seat",
			"in",
			"2014",
			"He",
			"recently",
			"dropped",
			"re-election",
			"bid",
			"when",
			"he",
			"was",
			"found",
			"have",
			"plagiarized",
			"his",
			"master's",
			"thesis"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "2014 FIFA World Cup[10] Brazil's current President is this woman, a member of the Workers' Party.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ICCS |2014 | 6 | 5 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Romario described this event as \"the biggest theft in history.\"  [10] Name this large soccer tournament held in Brazil in 2014, which was marked by protests throughout the country.",
		"answers": [
			"2014",
			"FIFA",
			"World",
			"Cup",
			"10",
			"Brazil's",
			"current",
			"President",
			"this",
			"woman",
			"member",
			"Workers'",
			"Party"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hobby Lobby[10] Hobby Lobby and several organizations affiliated with the Catholic Church argued that requiring them to purchase health insurance covering birth control violated this type of freedom.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ICCS |2014 | 8 | 4 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This \"closely held\" corporation is owned and operated by David Green and his family.  [10] Name this craft store chain that won a 2014 Supreme Court case against the federal government over their opposition to birth control requirements in the Affordable Care Act.",
		"answers": [
			"Hobby",
			"Lobby",
			"10",
			"and",
			"several",
			"organizations",
			"affiliated",
			"with",
			"Catholic",
			"Church",
			"argued",
			"that",
			"requiring",
			"them",
			"to",
			"purchase",
			"health",
			"insurance",
			"covering",
			"birth",
			"control",
			"violated",
			"this",
			"type",
			"freedom"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "United States presidential line of succession [accept any equivalents that indicate the order in which persons may succeed to the U.S. presidency][10] Until 1971, the holder of this office was in the line of succession. This person oversees the largest civilian vehicle fleet in the world, many of which have a right-hand driver's seat.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ICCS |2014 | 8 | 8 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The Secretary of Homeland Security is currently the last person on this list.  [10] Name this list, the current order of which was established by law in 1947, of individuals who are eligible to hold a particular political office under certain circumstances.",
		"answers": [
			"United",
			"States",
			"presidential",
			"line",
			"succession",
			"equivalents",
			"that",
			"indicate",
			"order",
			"in",
			"which",
			"persons",
			"may",
			"succeed",
			"to",
			"U",
			"S",
			"presidency",
			"10",
			"Until",
			"1971",
			"holder",
			"this",
			"office",
			"was",
			"This",
			"person",
			"oversees",
			"largest",
			"civilian",
			"vehicle",
			"fleet",
			"world",
			"many",
			"have",
			"right-hand",
			"driver's",
			"seat"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "NPR [or National Public Radio][10] This popular news game show on NPR features a panel of three people playing various humorous games related to news stories. Listeners can win an answering machine message from scorekeeper Carl Kasell.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "MUT |2014 | 1 | 18 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This organization's president, Vivian Schiller, resigned after referring to the Tea Party as \"gun-toting\" racists. For 10 points each: [10] Name this media organization, a non-profit broadcasting corporation which airs such programs as All Things Considered and repeats of Car Talk.",
		"answers": [
			"NPR",
			"National",
			"Public",
			"Radio",
			"10",
			"This",
			"popular",
			"news",
			"game",
			"show",
			"features",
			"panel",
			"three",
			"people",
			"playing",
			"various",
			"humorous",
			"games",
			"related",
			"to",
			"stories",
			"Listeners",
			"can",
			"win",
			"an",
			"answering",
			"machine",
			"message",
			"from",
			"scorekeeper",
			"Carl",
			"Kasell"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Addison Mitchell \"Mitch\" McConnell, Jr. [10] This Louisiana Democrat and current chair of the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources is expected to face Bill Cassidy in a close race for re-election.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 10 | 6 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about the 2014 midterm elections, for 10 points each.  [10] This Senator, the current Senate Minority Leader, is running for re-election and was opposed by Matt Bevin in a primary race. ",
		"answers": [
			"Addison",
			"Mitchell",
			"Mitch",
			"McConnell",
			"Jr",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Louisiana",
			"Democrat",
			"and",
			"current",
			"chair",
			"Senate",
			"Committee",
			"Energy",
			"Natural",
			"Resources",
			"expected",
			"to",
			"face",
			"Bill",
			"Cassidy",
			"in",
			"close",
			"race",
			"for",
			"re-election"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Islamic Republic of Iran[10] This president of Iran tweeted that the government \"shouldn\"t be too hard on behaviors caused by joy.\" This member of the MDP party was elected in 2013.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 14 | 13 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This country has supposedly recently developed a stealth fighter called the Qaher-313, though many analysts think that it's fake. For 10 points each;  [10] Name this country in which a group of students were arrested for creating a video of them dancing to Pharrell Williams's \"Happy.\" ",
		"answers": [
			"Islamic",
			"Republic",
			"Iran",
			"10",
			"This",
			"president",
			"tweeted",
			"that",
			"government",
			"shouldn",
			"t",
			"be",
			"too",
			"hard",
			"behaviors",
			"caused",
			"by",
			"joy",
			"member",
			"MDP",
			"party",
			"was",
			"elected",
			"in",
			"2013"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "People's Republic of China and Vietnam [either order] [10] China is currently undergoing a dispute over these uninhabited islands with Japan. In 2013, China set up an air defense zone around these islands.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 16 | 14 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: These two countries recently entered a territorial dispute when one of then moved the Ocean Oil 981 platform towards the other's territory. For 10 points each: [10] Name these two countries that previously fought a battle over the Paracel Islands. ",
		"answers": [
			"People's",
			"Republic",
			"China",
			"and",
			"Vietnam",
			"order",
			"10",
			"currently",
			"undergoing",
			"dispute",
			"over",
			"these",
			"uninhabited",
			"islands",
			"with",
			"Japan",
			"In",
			"2013",
			"set",
			"up",
			"an",
			"air",
			"defense",
			"zone",
			"around"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Los Angeles International Airport [or LAX][10] Hernandez worked for this government agency, a part of the Homeland Security Department that conducts passenger screenings at airports.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2014 | 2 | 12 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This location was where Paul Ciancia killed Gerardo Hernandez with a point-blank shot to the chest. [10] Name this facility, where a government employee was killed on November 1, 2013, by Ciancia, who apparently wanted to shoot \"pigs.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Los",
			"Angeles",
			"International",
			"Airport",
			"LAX",
			"10",
			"Hernandez",
			"worked",
			"for",
			"this",
			"government",
			"agency",
			"part",
			"Homeland",
			"Security",
			"Department",
			"that",
			"conducts",
			"passenger",
			"screenings",
			"at",
			"airports"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "West Virginia[10] This type of mining has drastically altered West Virginia's landscape in the past halfcentury. This method uses dynamite to expose coal, blowing off large amounts of land which are then filled into valleys.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 4 | 14 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In 2014, a chemical leak in this state contaminated the Elk River, a tributary of the Kanawha, and forced residents of Charleston to import bottled water. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this Appalachian mountain state.",
		"answers": [
			"West",
			"Virginia",
			"10",
			"This",
			"type",
			"mining",
			"has",
			"drastically",
			"altered",
			"Virginia's",
			"landscape",
			"in",
			"past",
			"halfcentury",
			"method",
			"uses",
			"dynamite",
			"to",
			"expose",
			"coal",
			"blowing",
			"off",
			"large",
			"amounts",
			"land",
			"which",
			"are",
			"then",
			"filled",
			"into",
			"valleys"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "William \"Bill\" Nye[10] The Ham/Nye debate spurred fundraising for Ham's latest project, which plans to construct this object in Grant County, Kentucky.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 4 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This man posted the video \"Creationism is Not Appropriate for Children.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this man, who was then invited to debate Creation Museum founder and Answers in Genesis leader Ken Ham about creationism and evolution in a February 4, 2014 debate. This former television personality has also urged for more work fighting climate change. ",
		"answers": [
			"William",
			"Bill",
			"Nye",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Ham/Nye",
			"debate",
			"spurred",
			"fundraising",
			"for",
			"Ham's",
			"latest",
			"project",
			"which",
			"plans",
			"to",
			"construct",
			"this",
			"object",
			"in",
			"Grant",
			"County",
			"Kentucky"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kathleen Sebelius [10] In June 2013, Sebelius declared that this number of enrollees would constitute a success for the ACA, a number which was in fact slightly exceeded.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 6 | 9 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about the rollout of the Affordable Care Act, for 10 points each. [10] This former Secretary of Health and Human Services directed the implementation of the Affordable Care Act and presided over the ACA website's disastrous rollout.",
		"answers": [
			"Kathleen",
			"Sebelius",
			"10",
			"In",
			"June",
			"2013",
			"declared",
			"that",
			"this",
			"number",
			"enrollees",
			"would",
			"constitute",
			"success",
			"for",
			"ACA",
			"which",
			"was",
			"in",
			"fact",
			"slightly",
			"exceeded"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "toilet paper [or TP][10] Nicolás Maduro succeeded this strongly Bolivarian and anti-American President of Venezuela, who died of lung complications in March 2013",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PADAWAN |2014 | 11 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In September 2013, the Maduro government seized the production facilities of Manpa, the company that provides a plurality of this product to Venezuelans. [10] Name this common non-culinary household product, which Venezuela has been hilariously short of in recent years, requiring the government to shell out $79 million for additional supplies of it.",
		"answers": [
			"toilet",
			"paper",
			"TP",
			"10",
			"Nicolás",
			"Maduro",
			"succeeded",
			"this",
			"strongly",
			"Bolivarian",
			"and",
			"anti-American",
			"President",
			"Venezuela",
			"who",
			"died",
			"lung",
			"complications",
			"in",
			"March",
			"2013"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "marijuana [or cannabis; or obvious equivalents, such as pot, sativa, MJ, weed, bud, Mary Jane, marijuwana, grass, herb, ganja, chronic, reefer, Acapulco gold, Texas tea, Thai sticks, or Panama red][10] Though he opposed the rescheduling, this current governor of Colorado accepted the results of the marijuana referendum as a shift in public attitudes. He makes a cameo in Kurt Vonnegut's novel Timequake.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PADAWAN |2014 | 12 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Washington and Colorado legalized recreational use of this product for people over 21. [10] Name this product whose medicinal usage is legal in several more states, like California",
		"answers": [
			"marijuana",
			"cannabis",
			"obvious",
			"equivalents",
			"such",
			"as",
			"pot",
			"sativa",
			"MJ",
			"weed",
			"bud",
			"Mary",
			"Jane",
			"marijuwana",
			"grass",
			"herb",
			"ganja",
			"chronic",
			"reefer",
			"Acapulco",
			"gold",
			"Texas",
			"tea",
			"Thai",
			"sticks",
			"Panama",
			"red",
			"10",
			"Though",
			"he",
			"opposed",
			"rescheduling",
			"this",
			"current",
			"governor",
			"Colorado",
			"accepted",
			"results",
			"referendum",
			"shift",
			"in",
			"public",
			"attitudes",
			"He",
			"makes",
			"cameo",
			"Kurt",
			"Vonnegut's",
			"novel",
			"Timequake"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "vocational education[10] This country's vocational education system is cited as a reason for it having one of the lowest youth unemployment rates in Europe. This country's Free Democrats failed to win enough seats to secure national representation in its most recent parliamentary election.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PADAWAN |2014 | 14 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: New York City has expanded its offerings of this kind of education through the CTE program, which opened The Harbor School in 2003. [10] Give this term for technical education designed to prepare students for specific trades, such as plumbing or electrical work. In the United States, this form of education is often provided through community colleges.",
		"answers": [
			"vocational",
			"education",
			"10",
			"This",
			"country's",
			"system",
			"cited",
			"as",
			"reason",
			"for",
			"having",
			"one",
			"lowest",
			"youth",
			"unemployment",
			"rates",
			"in",
			"Europe",
			"Free",
			"Democrats",
			"failed",
			"to",
			"win",
			"enough",
			"seats",
			"secure",
			"national",
			"representation",
			"its",
			"most",
			"recent",
			"parliamentary",
			"election"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "princelings [or the Crown Prince Party][10] This other prominent princeling, who developed a partnership with British businessman Neil Heywood, served as secretary of the CCP's Chongqing branch.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PADAWAN |2014 | 2 | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Give this term for descendants of prominent Chinese Communist Party officials, such as current President Xi Jingping, who have used nepotism and cronyism to gain high political and economic positions.",
		"answers": [
			"princelings",
			"Crown",
			"Prince",
			"Party",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"prominent",
			"princeling",
			"who",
			"developed",
			"partnership",
			"with",
			"British",
			"businessman",
			"Neil",
			"Heywood",
			"served",
			"as",
			"secretary",
			"CCP's",
			"Chongqing",
			"branch"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "United States military bases [or obvious equivalents, such as U.S. army bases, U.S. naval bases, or U.S. air bases; prompt on \"(military) bases\" or other answers that lack a country][10] Drones based at Camp Lemonnier often conduct strikes in this pirate-ravaged country, where government initiatives and foreign support have succeeded in pushing back al-Shabaab.",
		"prompts": [
			"military",
			"bases",
			"other",
			"that",
			"lack",
			"country",
			"10",
			"Drones",
			"based",
			"at",
			"Camp",
			"Lemonnier",
			"often",
			"conduct",
			"strikes",
			"in",
			"this",
			"pirate-ravaged",
			"country",
			"where",
			"government",
			"initiatives",
			"and",
			"foreign",
			"support",
			"have",
			"succeeded",
			"in",
			"pushing",
			"back",
			"al-Shabaab"
		],
		"heading": "Padawan |2014 | 3 | 13 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: A large one of these facilities is located at Andrews in Prince George's County, Maryland. For 10 points each: [10] Name this type of facility, of which Camp Lemonnier is the only example in Africa. KAIA is a major one of these facilities located in Kabul.",
		"answers": [
			"United",
			"States",
			"military",
			"bases",
			"obvious",
			"equivalents",
			"such",
			"as",
			"U",
			"S",
			"army",
			"naval",
			"air"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "North Dakota[10] This city at the center of the oil boom is the namesake for the basin containing the oil shale deposits and in February 2014 was found to have the highest apartment rental prices in the United States.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2014 | 10 | 10 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: As of September 2014, this state has the lowest unemployment rate in the United States at 2.8%. For 10 points each:  [10] Identify this state whose Bakken and Three Forks formations contain extensive deposits of shale oil that has led to an economic boom despite controversy over flaring and fracking practices. ",
		"answers": [
			"North",
			"Dakota",
			"10",
			"This",
			"city",
			"at",
			"center",
			"oil",
			"boom",
			"namesake",
			"for",
			"basin",
			"containing",
			"shale",
			"deposits",
			"and",
			"in",
			"February",
			"2014",
			"was",
			"found",
			"to",
			"have",
			"highest",
			"apartment",
			"rental",
			"prices",
			"United",
			"States"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "license plates [or vehicle registration plate and other equivalents; prompt on \"cars\"] [10] The 1979 energy crisis occurred during the term of this American president and former Georgian governor who spoke of his lust for women in a Playboy interview during his successful 1976 campaign.",
		"prompts": [
			"cars",
			"10",
			"The",
			"1979",
			"energy",
			"crisis",
			"occurred",
			"during",
			"term",
			"this",
			"American",
			"president",
			"and",
			"former",
			"Georgian",
			"governor",
			"who",
			"spoke",
			"his",
			"lust",
			"for",
			"women",
			"in",
			"Playboy",
			"interview",
			"during",
			"his",
			"successful",
			"1976",
			"campaign"
		],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2014 | 11 | 2 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: A strategy using these objects was used during the 2008 Olympics to control smog in Beijing. For 10 points each: [10] Identify these objects that determined who was allowed to fill up with gasoline during the 1979 energy crisis in the United States depending on the day of the week and whether the last digit on this object was even or odd. ",
		"answers": [
			"license",
			"plates",
			"vehicle",
			"registration",
			"plate",
			"and",
			"other",
			"equivalents"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Benjamin Netanyahu[10] This is the political party to which Netanyahu belongs and which received a plurality of votes in the 2013 legislative election. It was founded by Menachem Begin and holds a center right position.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2014 | 13 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This man got into a spat with the White House in October 2014 by claiming that opposing settlements goes against American values. For 10 points each: [10] Name this current Israeli prime minister who oversaw Operation Protective Edge in early 2014.",
		"answers": [
			"Benjamin",
			"Netanyahu",
			"10",
			"This",
			"political",
			"party",
			"to",
			"which",
			"belongs",
			"and",
			"received",
			"plurality",
			"votes",
			"in",
			"2013",
			"legislative",
			"election",
			"It",
			"was",
			"founded",
			"by",
			"Menachem",
			"Begin",
			"holds",
			"center",
			"right",
			"position"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Yemen [or Jumhuriya Al-Yamania][10] Many Yemeni nationals have joined this Somalia-based Islamist group after crossing the Red Sea. It briefly occupied Mogadishu in 2006 and raided a Nairobi shopping mall in 2013.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2014 | 6 | 4 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: American citizen Anwar al-Awlaki was hiding in this country with his 16-year-old son Abdurrahman when a United States drone killed both of them during Barack Obama's first term. For 10 points each: [10] Name this country on the Arabian Peninsula. Its recent turmoil has included the 2012 stepdown of Ali Abdullah Saleh, who had reunified its warring north and south in 1990.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Yemen",
			"Jumhuriya",
			"Al-Yamania",
			"10",
			"Many",
			"Yemeni",
			"nationals",
			"have",
			"joined",
			"this",
			"Somalia-based",
			"Islamist",
			"group",
			"after",
			"crossing",
			"Red",
			"Sea",
			"It",
			"briefly",
			"occupied",
			"Mogadishu",
			"in",
			"2006",
			"and",
			"raided",
			"Nairobi",
			"shopping",
			"mall",
			"2013"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "[Thomas] Woodrow Wilson[10] The eugenicist Margaret Sanger founded this organization to promote access to birth control. A branch of this organization sued restrictions on abortions imposed by the state of Pennsylvania in 1992.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2014 | 8 | 3 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about the eugenics movement in the United States. For 10 points each: [10] This governor of New Jersey signed a law in 1911 authorizing the sterilization of the \"feeble-minded...and other defectives.\" He also notably praised The Birth of a Nation.",
		"answers": [
			"Thomas",
			"Woodrow",
			"Wilson",
			"10",
			"The",
			"eugenicist",
			"Margaret",
			"Sanger",
			"founded",
			"this",
			"organization",
			"to",
			"promote",
			"access",
			"birth",
			"control",
			"A",
			"branch",
			"sued",
			"restrictions",
			"abortions",
			"imposed",
			"by",
			"state",
			"Pennsylvania",
			"in",
			"1992"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "eminent domain[10] Law enforcement officials can use this procedure during a roadside stop to seize suspicious cash in a vehicle without an indictment. A series of 2014 articles by the Washington Post criticized its overuse on state highways.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2014 | 8 | 12 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about ways government can take property from private citizens in the United States without trial, for 10 points each. [10] This process of buying back private land is constitutionally limited to \"public use\" for which the owner is given \"just compensation\" by the Takings Clause in the Fifth Amendment.",
		"answers": [
			"eminent",
			"domain",
			"10",
			"Law",
			"enforcement",
			"officials",
			"can",
			"use",
			"this",
			"procedure",
			"during",
			"roadside",
			"stop",
			"to",
			"seize",
			"suspicious",
			"cash",
			"in",
			"vehicle",
			"without",
			"an",
			"indictment",
			"A",
			"series",
			"2014",
			"articles",
			"by",
			"Washington",
			"Post",
			"criticized",
			"its",
			"overuse",
			"state",
			"highways"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mark Sanford[10] Robin Kelly won the special election to replace this man who resigned in 2012. This man had previously worked with his father in Operation PUSH and was recently sentenced to prison for taking campaign money for personal use.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Editors 1 | 9 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] This South Carolinian defeated Elizabeth Colbert Busch in a special election to win a seat in the House of Representatives. While governor, he is perhaps better known for taking a vacation to the \"Appalachian Trail\" when he was really boning his mistress.",
		"answers": [
			"Mark",
			"Sanford",
			"10",
			"Robin",
			"Kelly",
			"won",
			"special",
			"election",
			"to",
			"replace",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"resigned",
			"in",
			"2012",
			"This",
			"had",
			"previously",
			"worked",
			"with",
			"his",
			"father",
			"Operation",
			"PUSH",
			"and",
			"was",
			"recently",
			"sentenced",
			"prison",
			"for",
			"taking",
			"campaign",
			"money",
			"personal",
			"use"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Běijīng[10] Běijīng's China Central Television Tower, which features two slanted towers connected by a cantilever, was designed by OMA, a firm headed by this Dutch architect. His theories are outlined in Delirious New York.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Editors 2 | 10 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Prolific Swiss firm Herzog & De Meuron collaborated with artist Ài Wèiwèi on the design of an athletic stadium also known as the Bird's Nest, which is located in this city.",
		"answers": [
			"Běijīng",
			"10",
			"Běijīng's",
			"China",
			"Central",
			"Television",
			"Tower",
			"which",
			"features",
			"two",
			"slanted",
			"towers",
			"connected",
			"by",
			"cantilever",
			"was",
			"designed",
			"OMA",
			"firm",
			"headed",
			"this",
			"Dutch",
			"architect",
			"His",
			"theories",
			"are",
			"outlined",
			"in",
			"Delirious",
			"New",
			"York"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "OAO Gazprom (accept OAO Gazprom)[10] Russia slashed gas prices to this country after it nixed a treaty with the EU. Led by Viktor Yanukovych, massive protests have rocked the country since December.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Editors 3 | 13 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Natural gas in Eastern Europe is doled out by this massive Russian company. The world's leading gas producer, it is currently headed by Alexei Miller.",
		"answers": [
			"OAO",
			"Gazprom",
			"10",
			"Russia",
			"slashed",
			"gas",
			"prices",
			"to",
			"this",
			"country",
			"after",
			"nixed",
			"treaty",
			"with",
			"EU",
			"Led",
			"by",
			"Viktor",
			"Yanukovych",
			"massive",
			"protests",
			"have",
			"rocked",
			"since",
			"December"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Francois Bozize Yangouvonda[10] You've probably heard about how unstable things are in this post-revolutionary country, currently led by Ali Zeidan. The instability is understandable, considering it had been led by Mu'ammar Gaddafi for more than 40 years before the revolution.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Harvard A, UVA B | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] This former president of the Central African Republic had to flee in 2013 after rebels nearly reached Bangui. He's currently hanging out in Cameroon.",
		"answers": [
			"Francois",
			"Bozize",
			"Yangouvonda",
			"10",
			"You've",
			"probably",
			"heard",
			"about",
			"how",
			"unstable",
			"things",
			"are",
			"in",
			"this",
			"post-revolutionary",
			"country",
			"currently",
			"led",
			"by",
			"Ali",
			"Zeidan",
			"The",
			"instability",
			"understandable",
			"considering",
			"had",
			"been",
			"Mu'ammar",
			"Gaddafi",
			"for",
			"more",
			"than",
			"40",
			"years",
			"revolution"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "neutrinos[10] Jenny McCarthy's completely wackadoo interpretation of autism led her to feed her son a diet free of both gluten and this other protein family found in milk and delicious, delicious cheese.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Illinois A, Alabama, Yale B | 5 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] In 2012, scientists at the OPERA experiment announced that they had observed these particles moving faster than the speed of light. They hadn't.",
		"answers": [
			"neutrinos",
			"10",
			"Jenny",
			"McCarthy's",
			"completely",
			"wackadoo",
			"interpretation",
			"autism",
			"led",
			"her",
			"to",
			"feed",
			"son",
			"diet",
			"free",
			"both",
			"gluten",
			"and",
			"this",
			"other",
			"protein",
			"family",
			"found",
			"in",
			"milk",
			"delicious",
			"cheese"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "North Korea[10] North Korea shocked the world in December 2013 with the public removal and execution of this figure, the uncle of Kim Jong-Un who was the vice-chairman of North Korea's top military group.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Penn A, Louisville | 3 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this secretive Asian nation led by Kim Jong-Un, whose president is \"friends for life\" with former Chicago Bulls star Dennis Rodman.",
		"answers": [
			"North",
			"Korea",
			"10",
			"shocked",
			"world",
			"in",
			"December",
			"2013",
			"with",
			"public",
			"removal",
			"and",
			"execution",
			"this",
			"figure",
			"uncle",
			"Kim",
			"Jong-Un",
			"who",
			"was",
			"vice-chairman",
			"Korea's",
			"top",
			"military",
			"group"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "feminism[10] One member of the Third Wave feminism movement is this Berkeley-based queer theorist and philosopher, who argued that gender is a construction of repeated performance in her seminal work Gender Trouble.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | Penn A, Louisville | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this movement, the \"second wave\" of which was boosted by Betty Friedan, that seeks political and social equality for women.",
		"answers": [
			"feminism",
			"10",
			"One",
			"member",
			"Third",
			"Wave",
			"movement",
			"this",
			"Berkeley-based",
			"queer",
			"theorist",
			"and",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"argued",
			"that",
			"gender",
			"construction",
			"repeated",
			"performance",
			"in",
			"her",
			"seminal",
			"work",
			"Gender",
			"Trouble"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Geert Wilders[10] Wilders found common cause with this president of the Front National. She compared Islamic prayers on the streets of France to the Nazi occupation.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "SUBMIT |2014 | UVA A, Minnesota, Northeastern A | 14 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this right-wing Dutch politician who founded the Party for Freedom.",
		"answers": [
			"Geert",
			"Wilders",
			"10",
			"found",
			"common",
			"cause",
			"with",
			"this",
			"president",
			"Front",
			"National",
			"She",
			"compared",
			"Islamic",
			"prayers",
			"streets",
			"France",
			"to",
			"Nazi",
			"occupation"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "DOMA [or Defense of Marriage Act][10] This woman elected to a Wisconsin senate seat in November 2012 is the first openly gay politician elected to the Senate.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals |2013 | Illinois A + Dorman A + Wellesley | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Identify the following about recent developments in gay rights, for 10 points each: [10] Slated to be heard in 2013, U.S. v. Windsor is a pending Supreme Court case over the constitutionality of section 3 of this 1996 law, which defines marriage as the union of one man and woman at the federal level.",
		"answers": [
			"DOMA",
			"Defense",
			"Marriage",
			"Act",
			"10",
			"This",
			"woman",
			"elected",
			"to",
			"Wisconsin",
			"senate",
			"seat",
			"in",
			"November",
			"2012",
			"first",
			"openly",
			"gay",
			"politician",
			"Senate"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mali[10] This German car company took a heavy PR hit because one of their large SUVs carries the name of the Touraeg tribes and are planning to rename the car for the 2014 year.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals |2013 | Penn A + Chicago B | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This country is currently seeing a conflict for the Azawad regions, which groups like the MNLA hoped to establish as a homeland for the Touareg people. [10] Name this African nation where rebels currently control cities like Doutenza and Gao.",
		"answers": [
			"Mali",
			"10",
			"This",
			"German",
			"car",
			"company",
			"took",
			"heavy",
			"PR",
			"hit",
			"because",
			"one",
			"their",
			"large",
			"SUVs",
			"carries",
			"name",
			"Touraeg",
			"tribes",
			"and",
			"are",
			"planning",
			"to",
			"rename",
			"for",
			"2014",
			"year"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Anonymous[10] The not-a-cannon LOIC was used to retaliated against the justice department after the shutdown of Megaupload arrest of this man, its founder, who currently constitutes 50% of Wikipedia's \"People Deported from Thailand\" page.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals |2013 | Schindler + Yale C + Minnesota B | 8 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Denial-of-service attacks by this group have utilized something called the \"Low Orbit Ion Cannon,\" which sounds really cool but actually ended up just being some boring computer thing. For 10 points each: [10] Name this loosely-organized hacktivist group that gained prominence by attacking the Church of Scientology, known for their affinity for Guy Fawkes masks.",
		"answers": [
			"Anonymous",
			"10",
			"The"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hewlett-Packard[10] HP has woefully underperformed during the tenure of this current President and CEO, who transferred to HP after heading eBay. She ran against Jerry Brown in California's 2010 gubernatorial election.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DRAGOON |2013 | 10 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In 2013, this company was kicked off the Dow Jones Industrial Average and replaced by Visa. For 10 points each: [10] Name this tech company which sells the Pavilion and ENVY computer lines and the Deskjet printer lines. Oh yeah, and it's also named for two guys.",
		"answers": [
			"Hewlett-Packard",
			"10",
			"HP",
			"has",
			"woefully",
			"underperformed",
			"during",
			"tenure",
			"this",
			"current",
			"President",
			"and",
			"CEO",
			"who",
			"transferred",
			"to",
			"after",
			"heading",
			"eBay",
			"She",
			"ran",
			"against",
			"Jerry",
			"Brown",
			"in",
			"California's",
			"2010",
			"gubernatorial",
			"election"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bashar al-Assad[10] U.S. Intelligence claims that the Syrian regime used this nerve gas agent in the August 21 attacks. Aum Shinrikyo also used this gas in its 1995 attack on the Tokyo subway system.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DRAGOON |2013 | 13 | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: During a recent interview with Charlie Rose, he warned \"Expect everything\" if his country is attacked. For 10 points each: [10] Name this President of Syria, who is accused of using chemical weapons against his own people.",
		"answers": [
			"Bashar",
			"al-Assad",
			"10",
			"U",
			"S",
			"Intelligence",
			"claims",
			"that",
			"Syrian",
			"regime",
			"used",
			"this",
			"nerve",
			"gas",
			"agent",
			"in",
			"August",
			"21",
			"attacks",
			"Aum",
			"Shinrikyo",
			"also",
			"its",
			"1995",
			"attack",
			"Tokyo",
			"subway",
			"system"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Bo Xilai[10] Most of the news on the Bo trial has been provided by this official press outlet of the Communist party, which provides much material for the People's Daily Newspaper.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Dragoon |2013 | 2 | 10 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This politician's wife was convicted of the murder of Neil Heywood. [10] Name this Chinese politician who was considered a candidate for the Central Politburo but was recently sentenced to life imprisonment for bribery and abuse of power.",
		"answers": [
			"Bo",
			"Xilai",
			"10",
			"Most",
			"news",
			"trial",
			"has",
			"been",
			"provided",
			"by",
			"this",
			"official",
			"press",
			"outlet",
			"Communist",
			"party",
			"which",
			"provides",
			"much",
			"material",
			"for",
			"People's",
			"Daily",
			"Newspaper"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Cesar Pelli[10] The record for the world's tallest building is currently held by the Burj Khalifa in this city in the United Arab Emirates, which is also home to a so-called seven-star hotel at the sail-shaped Burj al-Arab.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DRAGOON |2013 | 5 | 10 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer these things about really tall buildings. [10] This Argentine-born American architect designed Philadelphia's Cira Centre, but is probably more famous for designing the giant Petronas Towers in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.",
		"answers": [
			"Cesar",
			"Pelli",
			"10",
			"The",
			"record",
			"for",
			"world's",
			"tallest",
			"building",
			"currently",
			"held",
			"by",
			"Burj",
			"Khalifa",
			"in",
			"this",
			"city",
			"United",
			"Arab",
			"Emirates",
			"which",
			"also",
			"home",
			"to",
			"so-called",
			"seven-star",
			"hotel",
			"at",
			"sail-shaped",
			"al-Arab"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Chris Christie[10] New Jersey also elected Cory Booker to fill the vacant Senate seat left by Frank Lautenberg. In the primary, Booker defeated this fellow Democrat, one of only two physicists in congress. His webpage says he's a Jeopardy! champion.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DRAGOON |2013 | 8 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Two gubernatorial elections have taken place in November 2013. [10] In New Jersey, this man defeated Barbara Buono. In 2012, he drew criticism for his cooperation with and praise of President Obama in the aftermath of Hurricane Sandy, but his response to the disaster was generally well-received.",
		"answers": [
			"Chris",
			"Christie",
			"10",
			"New",
			"Jersey",
			"also",
			"elected",
			"Cory",
			"Booker",
			"to",
			"fill",
			"vacant",
			"Senate",
			"seat",
			"left",
			"by",
			"Frank",
			"Lautenberg",
			"In",
			"primary",
			"defeated",
			"this",
			"fellow",
			"Democrat",
			"one",
			"only",
			"two",
			"physicists",
			"in",
			"congress",
			"His",
			"webpage",
			"says",
			"he's",
			"Jeopardy!",
			"champion"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Charles, Prince of Wales [accept either][10] This current Dutch king ascended to the throne in April following the abdication of his mother Beatrix, though his year has been marred by the death of his brother Prince Friso following a skiing accident.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "DRAGOON |2013 | Finals 1 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about changes in royal power across the world in 2013. [10] This heir apparent to the British throne welcomed his first grandchild, George Alexander Louis, into the world in July. This father of Princes William and Harry has now been waiting over 60 years to succeed his mother the Queen.",
		"answers": [
			"Charles",
			"Prince",
			"Wales",
			"10",
			"This",
			"current",
			"Dutch",
			"king",
			"ascended",
			"to",
			"throne",
			"in",
			"April",
			"following",
			"abdication",
			"his",
			"mother",
			"Beatrix",
			"though",
			"year",
			"has",
			"been",
			"marred",
			"by",
			"death",
			"brother",
			"Friso",
			"skiing",
			"accident"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Francis I[10] A Volvo limousine is the state car of this European monarch, who was crowned following the abdication of his mother, Queen Beatrix.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Michigan Fall Tournament |2013 | Editors Round 6 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name the following about cars and some heads of state who ride them. [10] A Mercedes M-class serves as the Popemobile, the official ride of this current head of the Vatican.",
		"answers": [
			"Francis",
			"I",
			"10",
			"A",
			"Volvo",
			"limousine",
			"state",
			"car",
			"this",
			"European",
			"monarch",
			"who",
			"was",
			"crowned",
			"following",
			"abdication",
			"his",
			"mother",
			"Queen",
			"Beatrix"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Edward Joseph Snowden[10] One of the NSA programs that Snowden revealed was this one, which, according to a leaked PowerPoint slide, collects information \"directly from the servers ofMicrosoft, Yahoo, Google, Facebook,\" and several others.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Michigan Fall Tournament |2013 | Editors Round 9 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: His request for asylum in Russia was a handwritten note saying \"I hereby request your considering the possibility of granting to me temporary asylum in the Russian Federation.\" It worked. For 10 points each: [10] Name this whistleblower of several NSA programs to collect Americans' phone records and look at Americans' emails, among other things. Getting asylum in Russia for a year meant he could move out of the Moscow airport.",
		"answers": [
			"Edward",
			"Joseph",
			"Snowden",
			"10",
			"One",
			"NSA",
			"programs",
			"that",
			"revealed",
			"was",
			"this",
			"one",
			"which",
			"according",
			"to",
			"leaked",
			"PowerPoint",
			"slide",
			"collects",
			"information",
			"directly",
			"from",
			"servers",
			"ofMicrosoft",
			"Yahoo",
			"Google",
			"Facebook",
			"and",
			"several",
			"others"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Felix Baumgartner[10] Baumgartner's jump took place through this energy drink company's Stratos project. This company also hosts \"Flugtag\" and Crashed Ice competitions.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 12 | 18 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: On October 14, 2012, this Austrian became the first human to break the sound barrier without a vehicle. For 10 points each: [10] Name this skydiver whose drop from a helium balloon down to earth 24 miles below set the record for the highest successful parachute jump.",
		"answers": [
			"Felix",
			"Baumgartner",
			"10",
			"Baumgartner's",
			"jump",
			"took",
			"place",
			"through",
			"this",
			"energy",
			"drink",
			"company's",
			"Stratos",
			"project",
			"This",
			"company",
			"also",
			"hosts",
			"Flugtag",
			"and",
			"Crashed",
			"Ice",
			"competitions"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Petraeus scandal [or Petraeusgate; accept any number of humorous answers that include the name of Petraeus, but not Betray Us since that's a different thing][10] Much amusement has been had by retrospectively considering the name of this book, the biography of Petraeus that his lover Paula Broadwell authored.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 14 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: One baffling part of this scandal, involving a shirtless picture of an FBI agent, was later revealed to have just been a joke. For 10 points each: [10] Name this scandal, in which a retired four star general resigned as CIA director after he was found having an extramarital affair with his biographer.",
		"answers": [
			"Petraeus",
			"scandal",
			"Petraeusgate",
			"number",
			"humorous",
			"that",
			"include",
			"name",
			"but"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hurricane Sandy[10] This Congressman from New York threatened to leave the Republican Party over opposition to Sandy relief funding. He has been chided for his stance on Islamic terrorism following his vocal support for the IRA in the 1980s.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 16 | 10 | Current Events | American | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: One person who was discussing legislation addressing this event labeled Darell Issa \"one thousand percent wrong\" and promised to \"hold all my votes in abeyance.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this event which displaced thousands of New York and New Jersey residents in October 2012 after causing flooding across the Northeast.",
		"answers": [
			"Hurricane",
			"Sandy",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Congressman",
			"from",
			"New",
			"York",
			"threatened",
			"to",
			"leave",
			"Republican",
			"Party",
			"over",
			"opposition",
			"relief",
			"funding",
			"He",
			"has",
			"been",
			"chided",
			"for",
			"his",
			"stance",
			"Islamic",
			"terrorism",
			"following",
			"vocal",
			"support",
			"IRA",
			"in",
			"1980s"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "France[10] The \"City of God\" is a famous example of these overpopulated, heavily policed urban shantytowns in Brazil.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 19 | 19 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about social apartheid in countries that are not South Africa, for 10 points each. [10] In 2005, much rioting occurred in this European country due to the squalor of its banlieu suburban housing projects, primarily inhabited by North African immigrants.",
		"answers": [
			"France",
			"10",
			"The",
			"City",
			"God",
			"famous",
			"example",
			"these",
			"overpopulated",
			"heavily",
			"policed",
			"urban",
			"shantytowns",
			"in",
			"Brazil"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tunisia[10]  Amina Tyler is a member of this feminist organization based in Ukraine, partially known for its topless protests. A recent topless protest by this group against Vladimir Putin apparently resulted in Putin enjoying the experience.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 2 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this country which has been home to significant controversy after Tyler posted topless pictures of herself.",
		"answers": [
			"Tunisia",
			"10",
			"Amina",
			"Tyler",
			"member",
			"this",
			"feminist",
			"organization",
			"based",
			"in",
			"Ukraine",
			"partially",
			"known",
			"for",
			"its",
			"topless",
			"protests",
			"A",
			"recent",
			"protest",
			"by",
			"group",
			"against",
			"Vladimir",
			"Putin",
			"apparently",
			"resulted",
			"enjoying",
			"experience"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Republic of Colombia [or Republica de Colombia][10] In March 2013, peace talks between FARC and the government were restarted by this current Colombian president, who replaced Alvaro Uribe in 2010.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 20 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In May 2013, three women dressed as nuns tried to travel from this country's capital to its island San Andres with two kilos of cocaine. For 10 points each: [10] Name this South American country that also had its internal transportation stymied by blockades set up during a two-week strike by its coffee farmers.",
		"answers": [
			"Republic",
			"Colombia",
			"Republica",
			"de",
			"10",
			"In",
			"March",
			"2013",
			"peace",
			"talks",
			"between",
			"FARC",
			"and",
			"government",
			"were",
			"restarted",
			"by",
			"this",
			"current",
			"Colombian",
			"president",
			"who",
			"replaced",
			"Alvaro",
			"Uribe",
			"in",
			"2010"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Randal Howard \"Rand\" Paul[10] Paul was blocking voting regarding the nomination of this man as the Director of the CIA. This man took office in March.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 3 | 3 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This man gave a 12 hour filibuster in March 2013 to protest the administration's use of drones. For 10 points each: [10] Name this senator from Kentucky and Tea Party favorite. He is the son of a Texas congressman and frequent Presidential candidate who retired in 2013.",
		"answers": [
			"Randal",
			"Howard",
			"Rand",
			"Paul",
			"10",
			"was",
			"blocking",
			"voting",
			"regarding",
			"nomination",
			"this",
			"man",
			"as",
			"Director",
			"CIA",
			"This",
			"took",
			"office",
			"in",
			"March"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "deductible[10] Medicaid, which often provides health insurance financing for the indigent, automatically finances families with children who receive benefits from this program, which was created under Clinton's Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Act.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 4 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about paying for health insurance, for 10 points each. [10] Along with a copayment, this is a type of payment that falls under the cateogory of \"cost sharing\" in insurance. It is the amount an insured person must pay before any benefits are actually payable by the plan.",
		"answers": [
			"deductible",
			"10",
			"Medicaid",
			"which",
			"often",
			"provides",
			"health",
			"insurance",
			"financing",
			"for",
			"indigent",
			"automatically",
			"finances",
			"families",
			"with",
			"children",
			"who",
			"receive",
			"benefits",
			"from",
			"this",
			"program",
			"was",
			"created",
			"under",
			"Clinton's",
			"Personal",
			"Responsibility",
			"and",
			"Work",
			"Opportunity",
			"Act"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Silvio Berlusconi[10] Berlusconi is the current leader of this party, which he formed by merging his earlier Forza Italia party with the National Alliance.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 4 | 21 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This man referred to Barack Obama as \"young, handsome, and even tanned.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this media tycoon and three-time prime minister of Italy. In 2011, he was accused of soliciting underage prostitution.",
		"answers": [
			"Silvio",
			"Berlusconi",
			"10",
			"current",
			"leader",
			"this",
			"party",
			"which",
			"he",
			"formed",
			"by",
			"merging",
			"his",
			"earlier",
			"Forza",
			"Italia",
			"with",
			"National",
			"Alliance"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hugo Rafael Chavez Frias[10] After Chavez referred to George W. Bush as the devil, Rafael Correa, the current president of this country, noted it was an insult to the devil because at least the devil is intelligent.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2013 | 9 | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This man claimed \"Democracy is impossible in a capitalist system.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this Socialist leader who was the president of Venezuela from 1999 to 2013.",
		"answers": [
			"Hugo",
			"Rafael",
			"Chavez",
			"Frias",
			"10",
			"After",
			"referred",
			"to",
			"George",
			"W",
			"Bush",
			"as",
			"devil",
			"Correa",
			"current",
			"president",
			"this",
			"country"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "European Union [or the EU][10] In July 2013, this country became the latest to join the EU. Zoran Milanovic's Kukuriku coalition won its 2011 parliamentary elections.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2013 | 12 | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: A dispute with Greece over Macedonia's name is slowing the latter country's attempt to join this organization. [10] Name this international organization and winner of the 2012 Nobel Peace Prize that is negotiating with potential member-state Turkey. Most of its members are in Schengen Area and use a shared currency.",
		"answers": [
			"European",
			"Union",
			"EU",
			"10",
			"In",
			"July",
			"2013",
			"this",
			"country",
			"became",
			"latest",
			"to",
			"join",
			"Zoran",
			"Milanovic's",
			"Kukuriku",
			"coalition",
			"won",
			"its",
			"2011",
			"parliamentary",
			"elections"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "G8 [or Group of Eight][10] Shortly before the conference, Cameron and Hollande made a joint announcement that they would lead their countries into this transparency agreement, meant to level the playing field in resource-rich developing countries.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2013 | 6 | 18 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: At the most recent conference of this organization, David Cameron wished that tax evasion and transparency should dominate the agenda. [10] At that latest conference of this organization of industrialized nations, Stephen Harper warned that due to Vladimir Putin's support of Assad, it could become the \"G7+1\".",
		"answers": [
			"G8",
			"Group",
			"Eight",
			"10",
			"Shortly",
			"conference",
			"Cameron",
			"and",
			"Hollande",
			"made",
			"joint",
			"announcement",
			"that",
			"they",
			"would",
			"lead",
			"their",
			"countries",
			"into",
			"this",
			"transparency",
			"agreement",
			"meant",
			"to",
			"level",
			"playing",
			"field",
			"in",
			"resource-rich",
			"developing"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Li Keqiang[10] Li Keqiang was governor of Henan during an outbreak of this disease caused by tainted equipment used by commercialized blood banks that collected from peasants as well as poor sexual education.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2013 | 9 | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This former governor of Henan is the second most important figure in his country's Fifth Generation of leadership. [10] Name this member of the Tuanpai and successor to Wen Jiabao as Premier of China.",
		"answers": [
			"Li",
			"Keqiang",
			"10",
			"was",
			"governor",
			"Henan",
			"during",
			"an",
			"outbreak",
			"this",
			"disease",
			"caused",
			"by",
			"tainted",
			"equipment",
			"used",
			"commercialized",
			"blood",
			"banks",
			"that",
			"collected",
			"from",
			"peasants",
			"as",
			"well",
			"poor",
			"sexual",
			"education"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sabah[10]  Sabah, lying on the northern tip of Borneo, has long been the subject of disputes between Malaysia and this other nearby country, whose capital is Manila.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Terrapin |2013 | Chris Ray - FINAL | 1 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In Februrary 2013, several hundred angry gunmen took a boat trip to this state's town of Lahad Datu to enforce Jamlul Kiram III's claim to the Sulu Sultanate. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this state, the second largest in Malaysia after Sarawak, where negotiations to end the recent crisis now centrally take place between the remaining rebels and a few F/A-18 Hornets from the Malaysian Air Force.",
		"answers": [
			"Sabah",
			"10",
			"lying",
			"northern",
			"tip",
			"Borneo",
			"has",
			"long",
			"been",
			"subject",
			"disputes",
			"between",
			"Malaysia",
			"and",
			"this",
			"other",
			"nearby",
			"country",
			"whose",
			"capital",
			"Manila"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mario Monti[10] This Italian media mogul and former Prime Minister, known for his love of the ladies, ended up with a miraculous 29.1% of the vote, only 0.4% behind the winning Pier Luigi Bersani and the Democratic Party. He ran under his own People of Freedom party.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Terrapin |2013 | Editors 2 - FINAL | 19 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about the recent elections in Italy. For 10 points each: [10] The elections were a huge mess, but one clear loser was this technocrat Prime Minister who resigned in late 2012 after passing a budget with many unpopular austerity measures. This man only received 10% of the vote.",
		"answers": [
			"Mario",
			"Monti",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Italian",
			"media",
			"mogul",
			"and",
			"former",
			"Prime",
			"Minister",
			"known",
			"for",
			"his",
			"love",
			"ladies",
			"ended",
			"up",
			"with",
			"miraculous",
			"29",
			"1%",
			"vote",
			"only",
			"0",
			"4%",
			"behind",
			"winning",
			"Pier",
			"Luigi",
			"Bersani",
			"Democratic",
			"Party",
			"He",
			"ran",
			"under",
			"own",
			"People",
			"Freedom",
			"party"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "giving a Nazi salute after scoring[10] Although he claims he has no idea what it means, Katidis was probably influenced by this right-wing extremist party in Greece. It currently holds 18 seats in parliament after an increase in popularity following the collapse of the Greek economy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Terrapin |2013 | Editors 3 - FINAL | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The perpetrator of this action claims he was pointing at a teammate in the stands, but one has to wonder why his teammate wasn't on the field. For 10 points each: [10] Name this action, which led to the lifetime ban of football player Giorgos Katidis from representing his country in international matches.",
		"answers": [
			"giving",
			"Nazi",
			"salute",
			"after",
			"scoring",
			"10",
			"Although",
			"he",
			"claims",
			"has",
			"no",
			"idea",
			"what",
			"means",
			"Katidis",
			"was",
			"probably",
			"influenced",
			"by",
			"this",
			"right-wing",
			"extremist",
			"party",
			"in",
			"Greece",
			"It",
			"currently",
			"holds",
			"18",
			"seats",
			"parliament",
			"an",
			"increase",
			"popularity",
			"following",
			"collapse",
			"Greek",
			"economy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nouri Al-Maliki[10] This other political leader of Iraq has lead the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan since 1975. The Iraqi president for the past eight years, this man suffered a stroke and was briefly in a coma in December 2012.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed  |2013 | Chicago A + Illinois B  | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Janaury 2013 rallies in Ramadi and Fallujah called for the release of prisoners held by this man's government. For 10 points each: [10] Name this leader of the Islamic Dawa Party, who has been prime minister of Iraq since 2007.",
		"answers": [
			"Nouri",
			"Al-Maliki",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"political",
			"leader",
			"Iraq",
			"has",
			"lead",
			"Patriotic",
			"Union",
			"Kurdistan",
			"since",
			"1975",
			"The",
			"Iraqi",
			"president",
			"for",
			"past",
			"eight",
			"years",
			"this",
			"man",
			"suffered",
			"stroke",
			"and",
			"was",
			"briefly",
			"in",
			"coma",
			"December",
			"2012"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Felipe Calderon[10] This cartel is also known as the Arellano Felix Organization and is named for a border town. Its influence has waned with the guilty plea of Benjamin Arellano-Felix to racketeering, and the Sinaloa Cartel has increased influence in this cartel's namesake city.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed  |2013 | Chicago C & South Carolina A | 15 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: A member of the Partido Accion Nacional, this man stepped down in November of 2012 from his highest office. For 10 points each: [10] Name this man who served as Secretary of Energy under Vicente Fox and ramped up Mexico's drug war as that country's president.",
		"answers": [
			"Felipe",
			"Calderon",
			"10",
			"This",
			"cartel",
			"also",
			"known",
			"as",
			"Arellano",
			"Felix",
			"Organization",
			"and",
			"named",
			"for",
			"border",
			"town",
			"Its",
			"influence",
			"has",
			"waned",
			"with",
			"guilty",
			"plea",
			"Benjamin",
			"Arellano-Felix",
			"to",
			"racketeering",
			"Sinaloa",
			"Cartel",
			"increased",
			"in",
			"this",
			"cartel's",
			"namesake",
			"city"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Saudi Arabia[10] Saudi Arabia, ironically, ratified this UN international convention which came into effect in September of 1981 and aims to end gender-based discrimination. The United States signed but didn't ratify and Sudan, Somalia, and Iran remain non-signatories.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed  |2013 | Columbia A + Ottawa  | 16 | Current Events | American | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about recent developments in women's rights, for 10 points each. [10] On September 26, 2011 King Abdullah announced that women would both have the right to vote and be able to run in the 2015 municipal elections in this nation.",
		"answers": [
			"Saudi",
			"Arabia",
			"10",
			"ironically",
			"ratified",
			"this",
			"UN",
			"international",
			"convention",
			"which",
			"came",
			"into",
			"effect",
			"in",
			"September",
			"1981",
			"and",
			"aims",
			"to",
			"end",
			"gender-based",
			"discrimination",
			"The",
			"United",
			"States",
			"signed",
			"but",
			"didn't",
			"ratify",
			"Sudan",
			"Somalia",
			"Iran",
			"remain",
			"non-signatories"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "NYPD [or New York City Police Department, or obvious equivalents][10] The NYPD's electronic surveillance activities likely violated this law, originally passed in 1978, that governs wiretapping by the government and sets up a namesake court to oversee requests for wiretaps.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed  |2013 | Delaware + Michigan A  | 21 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In 2011, the AP reported that this organization sent spies on a whitewater rafting trip taken by Yale's Muslim student association. For 10 points each [10] Name this organization, led by Raymond Kelly, which partnered with the CIA to monitor Muslims, and has been criticized for its \"stop and frisk\" policy targeted at minorities.",
		"answers": [
			"NYPD",
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"Police",
			"Department",
			"obvious",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"The",
			"NYPD's",
			"electronic",
			"surveillance",
			"activities",
			"likely",
			"violated",
			"this",
			"law",
			"originally",
			"passed",
			"in",
			"1978",
			"that",
			"governs",
			"wiretapping",
			"by",
			"government",
			"and",
			"sets",
			"up",
			"namesake",
			"court",
			"to",
			"oversee",
			"requests",
			"for",
			"wiretaps"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Verma panel[10] The Verma panel was formed in response to the much‐publicized December 2012 gang rape incident on a bus in this Indian territory.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed |2013 | Editors 2 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This group was led by a former chief justice who retired in 1998. For 10 points each: [10] Name this body which produced a 630‐page report on reform of Indian rape laws in January 2013.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Verma",
			"panel",
			"10",
			"The",
			"was",
			"formed",
			"in",
			"response",
			"to",
			"much‐publicized",
			"December",
			"2012",
			"gang",
			"rape",
			"incident",
			"bus",
			"this",
			"Indian",
			"territory"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Knesset[10] This leader of the right‐wing Ha‐Bayit Ha‐Yehudi or Jewish Home party was expected to win more seats in the election, but instead has seen a diminishing of his hardline proposals, which included separating Palestinian‐dominated areas into three tiers and denying any Palestinian state.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed |2013 | Editors 3 | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: A new party in this election for this body was led by a longtime host of news roundtable shows who entered politics in 2012. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this legislative body which was up for election in January 2013. The new Yesh Atid party came in second with the slogan \"Where Is The Money?\" and platform against corruption and exemptions from the draft.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Knesset",
			"10",
			"This",
			"leader",
			"right‐wing",
			"Ha‐Bayit",
			"Ha‐Yehudi",
			"Jewish",
			"Home",
			"party",
			"was",
			"expected",
			"to",
			"win",
			"more",
			"seats",
			"in",
			"election",
			"but",
			"instead",
			"has",
			"seen",
			"diminishing",
			"his",
			"hardline",
			"proposals",
			"which",
			"included",
			"separating",
			"Palestinian‐dominated",
			"areas",
			"into",
			"three",
			"tiers",
			"and",
			"denying",
			"Palestinian",
			"state"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "United Kingdom [or Britain or Great Britain][10] This politician is expected to become the Chinese head of government in March 2013, replacing Wen Jiabao as Premier of the State Council, alongside Xi Jinping's rise to the presidency. He will become a leading figure in the fifth generation of Communist Party Leadership.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed |2013 | Georgia Tech and Williams | 19 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about political changes in the year 2012, for 10 points each. [10] This is the only one of the five UN Security Council countries to not undergo an election or change of leadership in the year 2012.",
		"answers": [
			"United",
			"Kingdom",
			"Britain",
			"Great",
			"10",
			"This",
			"politician",
			"expected",
			"to",
			"become",
			"Chinese",
			"head",
			"government",
			"in",
			"March",
			"2013",
			"replacing",
			"Wen",
			"Jiabao",
			"as",
			"Premier",
			"State",
			"Council",
			"alongside",
			"Xi",
			"Jinping's",
			"rise",
			"presidency",
			"He",
			"will",
			"leading",
			"figure",
			"fifth",
			"generation",
			"Communist",
			"Party",
			"Leadership"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ron Paul[10] This Maine Republican, one of the \"Gang of 14,\" announced in February 2012 that she would retire at the end of her term because she was sick of partisanship. Her Senate seat was won by independent Angus King.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed |2013 | Harvard A and Virginia B | 14 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Identify these people whose seats were contested in the 2012 elections, for 10 points each. [10] This former Representative from Texas, nicknamed \"Dr. No,\" retired from the House to run for president in 2012, but failed to win the Republican nomination.",
		"answers": [
			"Ron",
			"Paul",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Maine",
			"Republican",
			"one",
			"Gang",
			"14",
			"announced",
			"in",
			"February",
			"2012",
			"that",
			"she",
			"would",
			"retire",
			"at",
			"end",
			"her",
			"term",
			"because",
			"was",
			"sick",
			"partisanship",
			"Her",
			"Senate",
			"seat",
			"won",
			"by",
			"independent",
			"Angus",
			"King"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Syrian civil war [or Syrian uprising, etc.][10] In November 2012, this former leader of the Syrian National Coalition became head of the new National Coalition for Syrian Revolutionary and Opposition Forces . This Damascus imam is a former executive with Royal Dutch Shell.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "VCU Closed |2013 | Maryland B and Michigan A | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This conflict has included the Hama massacre, and it escalated after incidents such as the torture of the adolescent Hamza al-Khatib. For 10 points each: [10] Name this ongoing, extremely bloody Arab Spring event in which a coalition is attempting to overthrow the government of Bashar Assad.",
		"answers": [
			"Syrian",
			"civil",
			"war",
			"uprising",
			"etc",
			"10",
			"In",
			"November",
			"2012",
			"this",
			"former",
			"leader",
			"National",
			"Coalition",
			"became",
			"head",
			"new",
			"for",
			"Revolutionary",
			"and",
			"Opposition",
			"Forces",
			"This",
			"Damascus",
			"imam",
			"executive",
			"with",
			"Royal",
			"Dutch",
			"Shell"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Allen West[10] Three votes went to this politician from Virginia. He is the House Majority Leader.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Western Invitational Tournament |2013 | Alabama + Georgia Tech+ WUStL | 12 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Although John Boehner was re-elected as Speaker of the House, support among Republicans was not unanimous. For 10 points each: [10] This Tea Party leader and distinguished veteran got two votes, despite losing office. This first black Republican from Florida since Reconstruction claimed that 80% of House Democrats were \"card-carrying socialists\".",
		"answers": [
			"Allen",
			"West",
			"10",
			"Three",
			"votes",
			"went",
			"to",
			"this",
			"politician",
			"from",
			"Virginia",
			"He",
			"House",
			"Majority",
			"Leader"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Federal Republic of Somalia[10] The HSM Press Office is the official Twitter account of this Islamic group that absorbed Hizbub Islam. The Kenyans' amphibious Operation Sledgehammer to capture its last stronghold of Kismayo in early October 2012.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "2012 Penn-ance |2012 | 2 | 11 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Sharif Sheikh Ahmed, who was elected president of this country in 2009, was defeated by Hassan Sheikh Mohamud in its September 2012 presidential elections. For 10 points each: [10] Name this country that still has a problem with piracy off the Horn of Africa. American intervention in this country ended pretty quickly after a Black Hawk was shot down near its capital of Mogadishu.",
		"answers": [
			"Federal",
			"Republic",
			"Somalia",
			"10",
			"The",
			"HSM",
			"Press",
			"Office",
			"official",
			"Twitter",
			"account",
			"this",
			"Islamic",
			"group",
			"that",
			"absorbed",
			"Hizbub",
			"Islam",
			"Kenyans'",
			"amphibious",
			"Operation",
			"Sledgehammer",
			"to",
			"capture",
			"its",
			"last",
			"stronghold",
			"Kismayo",
			"in",
			"early",
			"October",
			"2012"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Eric Cantor[10] As majority leader, Cantor succeeded this Maryland Democrat, who made news for shouting on the House floor while trying to bring the payroll tax cut extension to a vote.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals |2012 | Alabama + Yale C + Alberta | 21 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  [10] This House Majority Leader from Virginia is the only Jewish Republican currently serving in Congress.",
		"answers": [
			"Eric",
			"Cantor",
			"10",
			"As",
			"majority",
			"leader",
			"succeeded",
			"this",
			"Maryland",
			"Democrat",
			"who",
			"made",
			"news",
			"for",
			"shouting",
			"House",
			"floor",
			"while",
			"trying",
			"to",
			"bring",
			"payroll",
			"tax",
			"cut",
			"extension",
			"vote"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"Jimmy's World\"[10] This man, a reporter for The New Republic, created an uproar in the late 90s when it was revealed that almost all of this man's feature articles were entirely fictitious, such as a story about a 15-year-old computer hacker. He wrote The Fabulist about his experiences.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals  |2012 | Maryland B + Loyola  | 21 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Name some things related to journalists writing fraudulent articles, for 10 points each: [10] Washington Post journalist Janet Cooke wrote this article about an 8-year-old heroin addict that was later revealed to be entirely fabricated. Cooke won the Pulitzer Prize for the article.",
		"answers": [
			"Jimmy's",
			"World",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"reporter",
			"for",
			"The",
			"New",
			"Republic",
			"created",
			"an",
			"uproar",
			"in",
			"late",
			"90s",
			"when",
			"was",
			"revealed",
			"that",
			"almost",
			"all",
			"this",
			"man's",
			"feature",
			"articles",
			"were",
			"entirely",
			"fictitious",
			"such",
			"as",
			"story",
			"about",
			"15-year-old",
			"computer",
			"hacker",
			"He",
			"wrote",
			"Fabulist",
			"his",
			"experiences"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Plan B [or the Morning-After Pill][10] This Secretary of Health and Human Services overruled the FDA's decision to allow over-the-counter sales of Plan B to teenagers. She was the governor of Kansas from 2003 to 2009.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals  |2012 | Northwestern A | 21 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Eric Mukherjee said that the Obama administration's decision not to sell this drug over-the-counter to teenagers was a \"fatal error.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this form of emergency contraception with scientific name levonorgestrel.",
		"answers": [
			"Plan",
			"B",
			"Morning-After",
			"Pill",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Secretary",
			"Health",
			"and",
			"Human",
			"Services",
			"overruled",
			"FDA's",
			"decision",
			"to",
			"allow",
			"over-the-counter",
			"sales",
			"teenagers",
			"She",
			"was",
			"governor",
			"Kansas",
			"from",
			"2003",
			"2009"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "voting [or election; accept word forms][10] In a 2011 referendum, citizens of the UK chose not to adopt this voting system, in which voters rank their preferences and the lowest-polling candidate is eliminated in succession until one candidate has a majority.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals  |2012 | RPI | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Duverger's law asserts that conducting these using a certain method leads to two-party systems. For 10 points each: [10] Name this practice whose types include Condorcet and first-past-the-post which democracies use to choose candidates.",
		"answers": [
			"voting",
			"election",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"In",
			"2011",
			"referendum",
			"citizens",
			"UK",
			"chose"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "voting [or election; accept word forms][10] In a 2011 referendum, citizens of the UK chose not to adopt this voting system, in which voters rank their preferences and the lowest-polling candidate is eliminated in succession until one candidate has a majority.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "ACF Regionals  |2012 | RPI | 7 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Duverger's law asserts that conducting these using a certain method leads to two-party systems. For 10 points each: [10] Name this practice whose types include Condorcet and first-past-the-post which democracies use to choose candidates.",
		"answers": [
			"voting",
			"election",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"In",
			"2011",
			"referendum",
			"citizens",
			"UK",
			"chose"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "[Willard] Mitt Romney[10] Mitt Romney's business tactics at this private equity firm have come under fire. An insane theory holds that the villain in the recent Dark Knight Rises film was chosen to draw attention to this company.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Collegiate Novice |2012 | 5 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question:  This man lost to Ted Kennedy in the 1994 U.S. Senate election in Massachusetts.  [10] Name this man who served as Governor of Massachusetts from 2003 to 2007, and is the current Republican nominee for this year's Presidential election. ",
		"answers": [
			"Willard",
			"Mitt",
			"Romney",
			"10",
			"Romney's",
			"business",
			"tactics",
			"at",
			"this",
			"private",
			"equity",
			"firm",
			"have",
			"come",
			"under",
			"fire",
			"An",
			"insane",
			"theory",
			"holds",
			"that",
			"villain",
			"in",
			"recent",
			"Dark",
			"Knight",
			"Rises",
			"film",
			"was",
			"chosen",
			"to",
			"draw",
			"attention",
			"company"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John [Glover] Roberts Jr. [10] Roberts cited this power of Congress in his majority opinion in NFIB v. Sebelius, ruling that the Affordable Care Act is constitutional under this power of Congress rather than the Commerce Clause.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Collegiate Novice |2012 | 9 | 18 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: In this man's confirmation hearings, he said that a judge's role is to \"call balls and strikes.\"  [10] Name this current Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States. ",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Glover",
			"Roberts",
			"Jr",
			"10",
			"cited",
			"this",
			"power",
			"Congress",
			"in",
			"his",
			"majority",
			"opinion",
			"NFIB",
			"v",
			"Sebelius",
			"ruling",
			"that",
			"Affordable",
			"Care",
			"Act",
			"constitutional",
			"under",
			"rather",
			"than",
			"Commerce",
			"Clause"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Federative Republic of Brazil [or Republica Federativa do Brasil][10] This man finished second in the first-round election but lost to Collor in the runoff. He lost in the 1994 and 1998 presidential elections before finally winning, on his fourth attempt, in 2002.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2012 | 1 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The documentary Beyond Citizen Kane showcased the influence of Globo TV over this country's politics. For 10 points each: [10] Name this country in which Globo TV's biased edit of a debate helped lead to Fernando Collor's victory in the 1989 presidential election, the first under its 1988 Constitution.",
		"answers": [
			"Federative",
			"Republic",
			"Brazil",
			"Republica",
			"Federativa",
			"Brasil",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"finished",
			"second",
			"in",
			"first-round",
			"election",
			"but",
			"lost",
			"to",
			"Collor",
			"runoff",
			"He",
			"1994",
			"and",
			"1998",
			"presidential",
			"elections",
			"finally",
			"winning",
			"his",
			"fourth",
			"attempt",
			"2002"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Federative Republic of Brazil [or Republica Federativa do Brasil][10] This man finished second in the first-round election but lost to Collor in the runoff. He lost in the 1994 and 1998 presidential elections before finally winning, on his fourth attempt, in 2002.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT |2012 | 1 | 16 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: The documentary Beyond Citizen Kane showcased the influence of Globo TV over this country's politics. For 10 points each: [10] Name this country in which Globo TV's biased edit of a debate helped lead to Fernando Collor's victory in the 1989 presidential election, the first under its 1988 Constitution.",
		"answers": [
			"Federative",
			"Republic",
			"Brazil",
			"Republica",
			"Federativa",
			"Brasil",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"finished",
			"second",
			"in",
			"first-round",
			"election",
			"but",
			"lost",
			"to",
			"Collor",
			"runoff",
			"He",
			"1994",
			"and",
			"1998",
			"presidential",
			"elections",
			"finally",
			"winning",
			"his",
			"fourth",
			"attempt",
			"2002"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Florida[10] This politician was Secretary of State of Florida during the election controversy. She was also accused of purging several eligible black voters from voter lists in the run-up to the election.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2012 | 7 | 2 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Jeb Bush was governor of this state, which was the subject of the Supreme Court case Bush v Gore. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this state which saw a massive recount during the 2000 election due to problems with hanging chads and really confusing ballots.",
		"answers": [
			"Florida",
			"10",
			"This",
			"politician",
			"was",
			"Secretary",
			"State",
			"during",
			"election",
			"controversy",
			"She",
			"also",
			"accused",
			"purging",
			"several",
			"eligible",
			"black",
			"voters",
			"from",
			"voter",
			"lists",
			"in",
			"run-up",
			"to"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Anonymous[10] Anonymous' most famous attack is undoubtedly the one against this organization, during which they posted a really creepy youtube video criticizing this L. Ron Hubbard-founded \"church\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn Bowl |2012 | Editors Packet 4 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This group uses the so-called Low Orbit Ion Cannon for some of its attacks, and \"members\" of this group have appeared in protests wearing Guy Fawkes masks. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this group of hackers, which recently attacked the US Department of Justice website after megaupload was shut down by the government. They also attacked PayPal after it froze WikiLeaks' account in 2010.",
		"answers": [
			"Anonymous",
			"10",
			"Anonymous'",
			"most",
			"famous",
			"attack",
			"undoubtedly",
			"one",
			"against",
			"this",
			"organization",
			"during",
			"which",
			"they",
			"posted",
			"really",
			"creepy",
			"youtube",
			"video",
			"criticizing",
			"L",
			"Ron",
			"Hubbard-founded",
			"church"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Pussy Riot[10] This former European head of state called for the release of Pussy Riot, though he called their actions tasteless. This staunch Catholic and loser of a 1995 election in his country recently endorsed Mitt Romney for the presidency.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Penn-ance |2012 | 5 | 12 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Amnesty International declared August 17 the \"Global Day\" of this group, who were arrested after a so-called \"Punk Prayer\". For 10 points each: [10] Name this Russian feminist band which was recently arrested for performing an anti-Putin concert in front of a cathedral in Moscow.",
		"answers": [
			"Pussy",
			"Riot",
			"10",
			"This",
			"former",
			"European",
			"head",
			"state",
			"called",
			"for",
			"release",
			"though",
			"he",
			"their",
			"actions",
			"tasteless",
			"staunch",
			"Catholic",
			"and",
			"loser",
			"1995",
			"election",
			"in",
			"his",
			"country",
			"recently",
			"endorsed",
			"Mitt",
			"Romney",
			"presidency"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "First Intifada[10] Much of the First Intifada was centered around this contested strip of land, which was occupied by Israel after the Six-Day War.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "QUARK |2012 | 1 | 13 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This uprising began in Jabalia Camp in December 1987 and ended in 1993. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Palestinian uprising against Israeli occupation, which preceded a similar event in the early 21st century.",
		"answers": [
			"First",
			"Intifada",
			"10",
			"Much",
			"was",
			"centered",
			"around",
			"this",
			"contested",
			"strip",
			"land",
			"which",
			"occupied",
			"by",
			"Israel",
			"after",
			"Six-Day",
			"War"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "debit cards [do not accept \"credit cards\"][10] The Durbin Amendment was part of this larger piece of legislation passed in July 2010 in response to the 2008 fiscal crisis. It is named for its two chief sponsors, a former Senator from Connecticut and a gay representative from Massachusetts.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "MAGNI |2011 | 1 | 20 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: Senator Dick Durbin sponsored an amendment that limited the amount banks could charge vendors for transactions using these objects. For 10 points each: [10] Identify these objects used instead of currency to conduct financial transactions. Bank of America announced in October 2011 that it would start charging a $5 monthly fee for consumers to use them.",
		"answers": [
			"debit",
			"cards"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nantaz[10] Stuxnet was a cyberwarfare operation conducted by the United States and this nation. This largest recipient of U.S. military aid, currently led by Benjamin Netanyahu, remains embroiled in controversy over settlements in the West Bank.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Missiles of October |2011 | 1 | 17 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about every Iranian nuclear engineer's nightmare, the Stuxnet worm: [10] The Stuxnet worm primarily affected computers in this Iranian nuclear facility. The worm caused this facility's gas centrifuges to spin too fast, destroying almost a thousand of them.",
		"answers": [
			"Nantaz",
			"10",
			"Stuxnet",
			"was",
			"cyberwarfare",
			"operation",
			"conducted",
			"by",
			"United",
			"States",
			"and",
			"this",
			"nation",
			"This",
			"largest",
			"recipient",
			"U",
			"S",
			"military",
			"aid",
			"currently",
			"led",
			"Benjamin",
			"Netanyahu",
			"remains",
			"embroiled",
			"in",
			"controversy",
			"over",
			"settlements",
			"West",
			"Bank"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Minnesota[10] In Congress, Bachmann introduced a measure to repeal this doubly-eponymous July 2010 piece of legislation that reformed financial regulation, including a provision that requires the registration of smaller investment companies and hedge funds.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Missiles of October |2011 | 12 | 12 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name some things about Republican presidential candidate Michele Bachmann. [10] Bachmann represents this state in the House.  Tim Pawlenty, a one-time Republican candidate, served for eight years as governor of this state.",
		"answers": [
			"Minnesota",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Congress",
			"Bachmann",
			"introduced",
			"measure",
			"to",
			"repeal",
			"this",
			"doubly-eponymous",
			"July",
			"2010",
			"piece",
			"legislation",
			"that",
			"reformed",
			"financial",
			"regulation",
			"including",
			"provision",
			"requires",
			"registration",
			"smaller",
			"investment",
			"companies",
			"and",
			"hedge",
			"funds"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Euskadi Ta Askatasuna[10] [10] The ETA want freedom for this ethnic group who speak a language isolate and are centered in a namesake region in France and Spain including Bilbao.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "2010 ACF Fall |2010 | Bellarmine and UCLA (1) | 5 | Current Events | None | College",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "College",
		"question": "Question: This group declared a ceasefire in September 2010 after an earlier, broken \"permanent ceasefire\" in 2006. For 10 points each: [10] ] Name this group responsible for assassinating Prime Minister Luis Carrero Blanco in 1973 and accused by some of carrying out some 2004 train bombings in a capital city.",
		"answers": [
			"Euskadi",
			"Ta",
			"Askatasuna",
			"10",
			"The",
			"ETA",
			"want",
			"freedom",
			"for",
			"this",
			"ethnic",
			"group",
			"who",
			"speak",
			"language",
			"isolate",
			"and",
			"are",
			"centered",
			"in",
			"namesake",
			"region",
			"France",
			"Spain",
			"including",
			"Bilbao"
		]
	}
]